<法規>
<法規性質>法律</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Organization Act of the General Staff Headquarters of the Ministry of National Defense</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>國防部參謀本部組織條例</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawContent.aspx?PCODE=F0000002</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20140129</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>廢</廢止註記>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Decreed  Date ：July 17 , 1978
2.Amended on Nov.12,2001
3.Abolished on January 29, 2014]]></沿革內容>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Provisions are established according to Provision 6 of Organization  Law of NMD.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[General Staff Office in MND (called“General Staff Office”in abbreviation in the following specification) is the authority, combining both the functions of staffs in military-command-mechanism & conduction in Army/Navy/Air Force joint operations, which supports the Defense Minister to administer:
operational requirement for force  establishment  readiness
suggestions for defense resources distribution.
examining & directing for readiness condition & force training.
Scheme for operational array.
Scheme & executive of operational plan &  other force command & control affairs.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[General Staff Office  is divided into the following units:
(1) Joint Operations, Training's , & Principle Development Office.
(2) Office of Deputy Chief of the General Staff for personnel.
(3) Office of Deputy Chief of the General Staff for Intelligence.
(4) Office of Deputy Chief of the General Staff for Operations & Planning.
(5) Office of Deputy Chief of the General Staff for Logistics.
(6) Office of Deputy Chief of the General Staff for Communications, Electronics, &
    Information.
(7) General Affairs Office.
  General Staff Office could reckon the requirement to increase or decrease
  the previous units within the establishment limit specified in the Establishment 
  provisions.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[General Staff Office executes the conducting affairs to the authorities & operational
force units, which are established under the MND command mechanism.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[To execute the military conduction, General Staff Office may establish the special-affair unit, implementation execution unit, & supporting unit & force.  The units are specified on the Establishment Charts.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[General Staff Office has one Chief of the General Staff, one Vice Chief of General Staff (Executive), & two Vice Chiefs of General Staff.  The establishment rank is first-class-general  for CGS and second-class-general for VCGS.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[General Staff Office has the following officers in establishment:
-5~7 Deputy Chiefs of General Staff & 2 Director Generals(2-star or 1-star general in rank)
-8~16 Assistants to DCGS (Executive), Assistants to DCGS, & Deputy Director Generals (1-star-general in rank)
-23~45 Directors (1-star-general or colonel/captain in rank)
-49~85 Deputy Directors, Chiefs, Deputy Chiefs (colonel/captain in rank)
-9 Secretaries to DCGS & Director Generals (colonel/captain or Lt. Col./commander in rank) 
-430~692 Staffs (lieutenant officer, field officer, & specialist in rank).  It could have 121~211 colonels/captains within the limit of 430-692 Staffs.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[General Staff Office  will be schemed by General Staff Office, approved & proclaimed by MND.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[General Staff Office could employ advisors (15~30 persons in limit) & administrative clients.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 10</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The provisions’execution date is decided by Executive Yuan within 6 months after officialization.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
