<法規>
<法規性質>法律</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>The Organic Act of the Ministry of Finance</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>財政部組織法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawContent.aspx?PCODE=G0300001</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20120203</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated on December 08, 1928
2.Amended on May 09, 1929
3.Amended on February 21, 1931
4.Amended on July 14, 1936
5.Amended on March 26, 1940
6.Amended on Novenber 24, 1941
7.Amended on March 31, 1943
8.Amended on February 02, 1981
9.Amended on May 31, 1991
10.Amendment and Promulgation of Article 8 by the Presidential Order of Hua-Zong-Yi-Yi-Zi No. 10100022711 on February 3, 2012; the enforcement date of this act shall be at the directive of the Executive Yuan.
   Promulgated by the Executive Yuan Order of Yuan-Shou-Yan-Zong-Zi No. 1012261456 on December 18, 2012, with the exception of Article 2, Item 6 with reference to government procurement ; the act shall take effect on January 1, 2013.]]></沿革內容>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[To carry out transactions of national finance, the Executive Yuan established the Ministry of Finance (hereinafter referred to as “the Ministry”).
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Ministry shall be in charge of the following functions:
一、Fund collection and payments of the national treasury
二、National taxation
三、Customs affairs
四、National property
五、Financial information
六、Government procurement
七、Private participation in infrastructure projects
八、Supervision of the Training Institute for the Personnel of the Ministry of Finance and its subsidiary organizations
九、Other issues of finance
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Ministry shall have one (1) politically appointed Minister, two (2) Political Deputy Ministers of a rank equivalent to Grade 14, and one (1) Administrative Deputy Minister of a rank equivalent to Grade 14.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Ministry shall have one (1) chief secretary of a rank equivalent to senior appointment at the grade of twelve (12).
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The subsidiary organizations of the Ministry  and their functions are as follows:
一、National Treasury Administration: Planning and execution of fund collection and payment of the national treasury
二、Taxation  Administration: Planning and execution of national taxation
三、Regional National Taxation Bureaus: Execution of tax collection transactions
四、Customs Administration: Planning and execution of national Customs affairs
五、National Property Administration: Planning and execution of national property transactions
六、Fiscal Information Agency: Planning and execution of promotion and management of information of the Ministry and its subsidiary organizations (institutions)
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[For the needs of business operation, the Ministry may request the Executive Yuan for approval to station personnel overseas, subject to the provisions of the Act Governing the Organization of Overseas Government Agencies.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The scale of the position and the number of the personnel of the official ranks of the Ministry shall be stipulated in a staffing chart.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The enforcement date of the act shall be specified in an order from the Executive Yuan.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
