<法規>
<法規性質>法律</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>The Organic Act Establishing the National Archives Administration, National Development Council is hereby promulgated</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>國家發展委員會檔案管理局組織法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawContent.aspx?PCODE=A0010107</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20130821</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Enacted and promulgated by President Order Hua-ZongHua-Tsung (I)-Yi- No.10200156131 on August 21, 2013]]></沿革內容>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The National Development Council has established the National Archives Administration (NAA) to deal with the management and use of government agency records.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The NAA shall be in charge of the following matters:
1.studying and drafting policies, legislation, and management systems for archives;
2.supervising and assessing the management and use of government agency records, and compiling and publishing government agency records catalogs;
3.reviewing the government agency record retention periods and disposal practices;
4.appraising and classifying archives, setting retention periods, and settling disputed matters;
5.acquiring, transferring, organizing, and preserving national archives , making them available for use, and planning and implementing the establishment of facilities;
6.accepting donations of, accepting custody of, and purchasing documents or artifacts owned by private individuals or groups;
7.planning and coordinating the building of documents and archives information systems;
8.researching the management and use of archives, and conducting related publishing, technology development, academic exchange, and international cooperation, as well as training of archive management personnel;
9.planning and implementing document timeliness control at government agencies under the Executive Yuan; and
10.other matters pertaining to archives.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The NAA shall have one director-general, who shall be a 13th-grade senior-level career civil servant, and two deputy directors-general, who shall be 12th-grade senior-level career civil servants.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The NAA shall have one chief secretary, who shall be an 11th-grade senior-level career civil servant,
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The civil service ranks and occupational grades attaching to each occupational title at the NAA shall be separately set out in a staffing chart.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This Act shall enter into force on the date prescribed by an order of the Executive Yuan.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
