<法規>
<法規性質>法律</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Organizational Act of the Executive Yuan</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>行政院組織法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=A0010032</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20100203</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Enacted and promulgated a total sixteen articles of the Act on March 31, 1947
2.Amended and promulgated a total sixteen articles of the Act on April 22, 1947
3.Amended and promulgated a total seveneen articles of the Act on December 25, 1947
4.Amended and promulgated Article 3, Article 5, and Article 15 of the Act on May 13, 1948
5.Amended and promulgated Article 3 and Article 15 of the Act by the Presidential Order on March 21, 1949
6.Amended and promulgated Article 5 of the Act by the Presidential Order on November 20, 1952
7.Amended and promulgated Article 3 of the Act by the Presidential Order No.3666 on November 20, 1980
8.Amended and promulgated a total fifteen articles of the Act by the Presidential Order No.09900024171 on February 3, 2010, and enacted on January 1, 2012]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Act is established in accordance with Article 61 of the Constitutional Law.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Executive Yuan shall exercise the powers granted by the Constitutional Law.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Executive Yuan establishes the Ministries as follows:
(1)Ministry of the Interior;
(2)Ministry of Foreign Affairs;
(3)Ministry of National Defense;
(4)Ministry of Finance;
(5)Ministry of Education;
(6)Ministry of Justice;
(7)Ministry of Economic and Energy Affairs;
(8)Ministry of Transportation and Construction;
(9)Ministry of Labor;
(10)Ministry of Agriculture;
(11)Ministry of Health and Welfare;
(12)Ministry of Environment and Natural Resources;
(13)Ministry of Culture; and
(14)Ministry of Science and Technology.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Executive Yuan establishes the Councils or Commissions as follows:
(1)National Development Council;
(2)Mainland Affairs Council;
(3)Financial Supervisory Commission;
(4)Ocean Affairs Council;
(5)Overseas Chinese Affairs Council;
(6)Veterans Affairs Council;
(7)Council of Indigenous Peoples; and
(8)Hakka Affairs Council.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Executive Yuan shall have seven to nine Ministers without Portfolio, specially appointed.
The Ministers without Portfolio may hold concurrent positions as the ministers of the Commissions or the Councils mentioned in the preceding article.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Executive Yuan establishes the Directorate-General of Budget, Accounting and Statistics and the Directorate-General of Personnel Administration.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Executive Yuan establishes the Central Bank of the Republic of China (Taiwan).]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Executive Yuan establishes the National Palace Museum.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Executive Yuan establishes the independent administrative institutions equivalent to the second-level agencies of the Central Government:
(1)Central Election Commission;
(2)Fair Trade Commission; and
(3)National Communications Commission.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 10</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Executive Yuan Premier shall generally manage and govern all the affairs, and direct and supervise the affiliate agencies and the personnel thereof. 
In the event that Premier fails to perform his duties for any reason, the duties shall devolve on Vice Premier.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 11</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Executive Yuan Premier may invite or appoint any relevant person to attend the Executive Yuan meetings.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 12</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Executive Yuan shall have one Secretary-General, specially appointed, to manage the general staff affairs, and two Deputy Secretaries-General, one of whom shall be a political appointee of equivalent ranking to Senior fourteenth grade and shall assist Secretary-General with the staff affairs of the Executive Yuan. 
The Executive Yuan shall have one spokesperson, specially appointed, who may be held concurrently by a political appointee in charge of press release and communication.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 13</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The official ranks, grades, and headcounts of personnel at the Executive Yuan shall be regulated by a separate Personnel Establishment Table.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 14</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[For the purpose of managing a specific affair, the Executive Yuan may establish an internal dedicated department.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 15</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Act shall take into effect on January 1, 2012.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
