<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Regulations on Classification of Cyber Security Responsibility Levels</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>資通安全責任等級分級辦法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=A0030304</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20181121</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Schedule 1：Matters to be conducted by the government agency of cyber security responsibility Level-A.pdf]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000005661</下載網址>
  </檔案>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Schedule 1：Matters to be conducted by the government agency of cyber security responsibility Level-A.doc]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000005662</下載網址>
  </檔案>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Schedule 2：Matters to be conducted by the specific non-government agency of cyber security responsibility Level-A.pdf]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000005663</下載網址>
  </檔案>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Schedule 2：Matters to be conducted by the specific non-government agency of cyber security responsibility Level-A.doc]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000005664</下載網址>
  </檔案>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Schedule 3：Matters to be conducted by the government agency of cyber security responsibility Level-B.pdf]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000005665</下載網址>
  </檔案>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Schedule 3：Matters to be conducted by the government agency of cyber security responsibility Level-B.doc]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000005666</下載網址>
  </檔案>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Schedule 4：Matters to be conducted by the specific non-government agency of cyber security responsibility Level-B.pdf]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000005667</下載網址>
  </檔案>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Schedule 4：Matters to be conducted by the specific non-government agency of cyber security responsibility Level-B.doc]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000005668</下載網址>
  </檔案>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Schedule 5：Matters to be conducted by the government agency of cyber security responsibility Level-C.pdf]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000005669</下載網址>
  </檔案>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Schedule 5：Matters to be conducted by the government agency of cyber security responsibility Level-C.doc]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000005670</下載網址>
  </檔案>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Schedule 6：Matters to be conducted by the specific non-government agency of cyber security responsibility Level-C.pdf]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000005671</下載網址>
  </檔案>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Schedule 6：Matters to be conducted by the specific non-government agency of cyber security responsibility Level-C.doc]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000005672</下載網址>
  </檔案>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Schedule 7：Matters to be conducted by each agency of cyber security responsibility Level-D.pdf]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000005673</下載網址>
  </檔案>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Schedule 7：Matters to be conducted by each agency of cyber security responsibility Level-D.doc]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000005674</下載網址>
  </檔案>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Schedule 8：Matters to be conducted by each agency of cyber security responsibility Level-E.pdf]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000005675</下載網址>
  </檔案>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Schedule 8：Matters to be conducted by each agency of cyber security responsibility Level-E.doc]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000005676</下載網址>
  </檔案>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Schedule 9：Principles of classification of levels of defense requirements of information and communication system.pdf]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000005677</下載網址>
  </檔案>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Schedule 9：Principles of classification of levels of defense requirements of information and communication system.doc]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000005678</下載網址>
  </檔案>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Schedule 10：Defense standards of information and communication system.pdf]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000005679</下載網址>
  </檔案>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Schedule 10：Defense standards of information and communication system.doc]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000005680</下載網址>
  </檔案>
</附件>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated on Novenber 21, 2018
]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulationsare stipulatedaccording to Paragraph 1 of Article 7 of the Cyber Security Management Act(hereinafter referred to as “the Act”).]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The cyber security responsibility levels of the government agency or specific non-government agency(hereinafter referred to as “each agency”) are classified from high to low into Level-A, Level-B, Level-C, Level-D and Level-E.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The competent authority shall approve its own cyber security responsibility levels every two years.
The agencies directly subordinate to the Executive Yuan shall, every two years, propose the cyber security responsibility levels of their own, their subordinate or supervisory government agencies, and the specific non-government agencies under their charge, and shall report the same to the competent authority for approval.
Specialmunicipality, county(city) government shall, every two years, propose the cyber security responsibility levels of their own, their subordinate or supervisory government agencies, and their governed villages(townships/cities), mountain indigenous district offices of municipality, and the subordinate or supervisory government agencies of such governed villages(townships/cities) and mountain indigenous district offices of special municipalities, and shall report the same to the competent authority for approval.
Special municipality and county(city) council, village(township/city) council, and mountain indigenous districts of special municipality council shall, every two years, submit their own cyber security responsibility level, which shall be compiled and submitted by the municipality and county(city) government where it is located to the competent authority for approval.
The Presidential Office, the National Security Council, the Legislative Yuan, the Judicial Yuan, the Examination Yuan, and the Control Yuan shall, every two years, approve the cyber security responsibility level of their own, their subordinate or supervisory government agencies, and the specific non-government agencies under their charge, and shall submit the same to the competent authority for recordation.
If each agency is required to change its cyber security responsibility level due to adjustment to the organization or business, it shall immediately conduct the change to level according to the procedures under the preceding five paragraphs; the same shall apply to the case when a new agency is established.
In conducting the submission or approval of cyber security responsibility level under Paragraph 1 to Paragraph 5, if the government agency thinks it is necessary to otherwise give the entity within the government agency or the specific non-government agency the level that is different from those of such agency, it may determine such level in accordance with the requirements of Article 4 to Article 10, by taking into consideration the nature of businessof such entity.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The cyber security responsibility level of each agency under anyof the following circumstances is Level-A:
1. Its business involves national security information.
2. Its business involves matters of foreign issue, national defense, or homeland security.
3. Its business involves the maintenance operation of information and communication system commonly used for nationwide people service or cross agencies.
4. Its business involves the possession of personal information of nationwide people or civil servants.
5. It is a government agency, and its business involves matters of nationwide energy, water resource, telecommunication, transportation, banking & finance, or emergent rescue.
6. It is a critical infrastructure provider, and the central authority in charge of relevant industry, based on the consideration of the number of users, market share, the area and the substitutability of its business or maintenance operation of critical infrastructures and services, considers that the failures of or impact on its cyber security system might cause disasters or extremely serious impact on social public interests, people’s morale, or the security of people’s lives, body or property.
7. It is a government medical center.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The cyber security responsibility levels of each agency under any of the following circumstances are Level-B.
1. Its business involves the security maintenance and management of sensitively scientific technology information that is donated, researched, or developed by the government agency.
2. Its business involves the maintenance operation of information and communication systems that are commonly used for regional or local people services or cross agencies.
3. Its business involves the possession of the archives of personal information of regional or local people.
4. It is a government agency, and its business involves matters of regional or local energy, water resources, telecommunications, transportation, banking & finance, or emergent rescues.
5. It is a critical infrastructure provider, and the central authority in charge of relevant industry, based on consideration of the number of users, market share, the area and the substitutability of its business, or the maintenance operation of critical infrastructure and services, considers that the failure of or impacts on its information and communication system might cause serious impact on social public interest, people’s morale, or the security of people’s lives, body or properties.
6. It is a public regional hospital or local hospital.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The cyber security responsibility level of each agency who maintains and operates by itself or outsources the development of information and communicationsystem is Level-C.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The cyber security responsibility levels of each agency who conducts information and communication business by itself but does not maintain and operate the information and communication system that is developed by itself or outsourced for the development is Level-D.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The cyber security responsibility level of each agency under any of the following circumstances is Level-E:
1. It neither has theinformation and communication system, nor provides the information and communication service.
2. It is a government agency, and all its information and communication business is conducted concurrently or managed by its superior or supervisory agency.
3. It is a specific non-government agency, and all of its information and communication business is conducted concurrently or managed by itscentral authority in charge of relevant industry, the subordinate government agency of the central authority in charge of relevant industry, or the specific non-government agency under their charge by the central authority in charge of relevant industry.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[If the cyber security responsibility level of each agency conforms to two or above requirements under Article 4 to Article 8, the level of each agency are classified as the highest level conforming to such requirements.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 10</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The cyber security responsibility level of each agency shall be determined in accordance with the preceding six articles; however, when the government agency submits or approves the cyber security responsibility level under Paragraphs 1 to 5 of Article 3, the levels of each agency may be adjusted, by taking into consideration the degree of impact of the following matters on national security, social public interests, the security of people’s lives, body, properties, or the reputation of the government agency:
1. Thebusiness involving foreign issue, national defense, homeland security, or its business involves nationwide, regional or local energy, water resource, telecommunication, transportation, banking and finance, emergent rescues, and hospitalare interrupted or impeded.
2. The business involves personal information, official confidentiality, or other information which should be kept confidential by law or contract, the quantity and nature of such information, and the unauthorized access, use, control, breach, damage, tampering, destruction or other infringement.
3. The function of each agency is affected, disabled or interrupted depending on the hierachy of the agency.
4. Other concrete matters relating to the provision, maintenance operation, size, or nature of information and communication system.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 11</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Each agency shall conduct the matters specified in Schedule 1 to Schedule 8, depending on its cyber security responsibility level.
For the information and communicationsystem that is developed by each agency itself or outsourced for the development, each agency shall complete the classification of information and communication system according to the principles of classification of defense requirements of information and communication system specified in Schedule 9, and shall implement control measures according to the defense standards of information and communication systemspecified in Schedule 10; if thecentral authority in charge of relevant industry of a critical infrastructure provider considers it is necessary to otherwise provide for defense standards of specific types of the information and communication systems, it may propose by itself the defense standards and report such standards to the competent authority for approval, and shall follow the requirements of such standards, if approved.
In conducting the matters specified in Schedule 1 to Schedule 8 or implementing control measures specified in Schedule 10, if each agency has apparent difficulties in conducting or implementing specific matters or control measures due to such factors as technical limitation, design, structure or nature of individual information and communication system, it may, with consent of each agency submitting its level under Paragraph 2 to Paragraph 4 of Article 3 or each agency approving its level under Paragraph 5 of the same article, and upon reporting to the competent authority for recordation, be exempted from the implementation of such matters or control measures.
The government agency whose cyber security responsibility level isLevel-A or Level-B shall report the implementation status of matters under Paragraph 1 and Paragraph 2 in the manner designated by the competent authority.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 12</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The implementation date of the Regulations shall be stipulated by the competent authority.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
