<法規>
<法規性質>法律</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Praise and Commendation Act</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>褒揚條例</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=A0030004</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>19861128</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Full text of 16 articles established and announced by the National Government on 11 July 1931
2.Full text of 10 articles amended by Presidential Decree (1986) in Hua-Zong (I) Yi-Zi No. 6006 and announced on 28 November 1986]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This Act is established to praise and commend individuals whose high moral values, meritorious achievements, and great thoughts contribute to the nation, encourage the public, perpetuate history, and serve as models for future generations.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Individuals who accomplish the following deeds may receive praise and commendation under this Act:
1.Dedication to the cause of the national revolution, with outstanding contribution to the nation and her people.
2.Participating in building the nation by suppressing the communist rebellion, showing proper response and discretion under crisis, and outstanding loyalty.
3.Tactfulness in implementing national policy, achieving great success in diplomatic or international affairs.
4.Outstanding contributions in establishing educational and cultural businesses to promote Chinese culture.
5.Self-sacrifice in adventurous deeds, showing unflinching loyalty to the nation.
6.Achieving academic excellence or releasing a publication that receives laudatory remarks in its time.
7.Developing an invention that contributes to the nation and her people.
8.Practicing superb ethical, moral, and virtuous conduct that influences society and corrects social vices, serving as models for all.
9.Outstanding achievements in consolidating overseas Chinese and boosting their patriotism.
10.Outstanding acts of donation of properties and devotion to public welfare.
11.Other outstanding contributions to the nation and society worthy of praise and commendation.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Praise and commendation may be granted in the following manners:
1.By decree.
2.Presenting honorary plaque.
Item 1 in this Article is solely applicable to deceased individuals.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Unless by special Presidential decree, the Executive Yuan may initiate praise and commendation by decree or by presenting an honorary plaque. In cases of praise and commendation by decree, the recipient’s deeds should be listed in the application and submitted to a meeting in the Executive Yuan for approval.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[After the death of recipients of praise and commendation under Subparagraphs 1 or 2 of Article 2 or recipients under Subparagraph 5 of Article 2, the said persons shall be venerated in the National Revolutionary Martyr’s Shrine or the local Martyr’s Shrine.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The written record of the deeds of individuals receiving praise and commendation by decree shall be housed in the Academia Historica. The deeds shall also be kept in provincial (municipal) or county (city) chronicles.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[If it is discovered after the praise and commendation that the deeds were fake, in addition to canceling the previous praise and commendation, the object of praise and commendation shall also be returned.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Foreigners who accomplish the deeds under the Subparagraphs of Article 2 may receive praise and commendation.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Executive Yuan, in consultation with the Examination Yuan, shall establish the enforcement rules of this Act.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 10</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This Act shall be implemented from the day of its announcement.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
