<法規>
<法規性質>法律</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Petitions Act</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>請願法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=A0030019</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>19691218</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated on December 18, 1954
2.Amended on December 18, 1969]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[People's petitions shall be governed by the provisions of this Law.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The people may present petitions to the legislators or administrative authorities in charge of state policy, public interest, or their rights and interests.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[People's petition matters shall not violate the Constitution or interfere with the trial.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The people may not present petitions for matters that should be brought to litigation or administrative appeal according to law.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[A people's petition shall have a petition statement, which includes the following matters, and shall be signed and sealed by the petitioner or petition group and its person in charge:
1. The name, gender, age, place of origin, occupation, and address of the petitioner; if the petitioner is a group, the name, address, and person in charge of the group.
2. The facts, reasons and wishes on which the petition is based.
3. The authority shall accept the petition.
4. The year, month, and date of the Republic of China.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[When the people jointly petition to various authorities, if the petition is submitted in person and a statement is made, representatives shall be nominated; the number of representatives shall not exceed ten.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[When handling a petition case, each authority may notify the petitioner, or a representative nominated by the petitioner to come in preparation for inquiry; the number of representatives shall not exceed ten.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Each authority that handles a petition case shall notify the petitioner of the result; if the petition case is beyond its jurisdiction, the petitioner shall be notified of the appropriate authority to which the petition should be submitted.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The head of the authority that accepts the petition or the authority to which the petitioner belongs shall not coerce the petitioner or discriminate against him/her because of his/her petition.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 10</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[When local councils petition to other relevant councils on behalf of the people, the provisions of this Act shall apply mutatis mutandis.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 11</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[When people petition, they must not gather crowds to coerce, disturb order, interfere with official duties, or do other illegal things; violators will be stopped or punished in accordance with the law, the petition-accepting authority may not accept the petition.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 12</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This Act shall come into force on the date of promulgation.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
