<法規>
<法規性質>法律</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Orders Act</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>勳章條例</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=A0030006</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>19811207</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Table.PDF]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000004687</下載網址>
  </檔案>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Table.doc]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000002580</下載網址>
  </檔案>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Attachment.PDF]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000004688</下載網址>
  </檔案>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Attachment.doc]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000002581</下載網址>
  </檔案>
</附件>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Full text including 17 articles established and announced by the National Government on 12 February 1941
2.Article 10 amended and announced by the National Government on 25 March 1942
3.Article 7 amended and announced by the National Government on 11 September 1945
4.Article 6 amended and announced by the National Government on 7 September 1946
5.Article 12 amended and announced by the National Government on 10 December 1947
6.Full text including 17 articles amended and announced by the President on 11 January 1980
7.“ Verbal description of the Order of Chiang Chung-cheng with Grand Cordon ” and its graphic representation (Figure 3) added to table attached to Article 10, announced by the President on 7 December 1981.
  Table attached to Article 10 reset horizontally pursuant to a letter from the Ministry of the Interior Tai-Nei-Min-Zi No. 0940076028 on 5 January 2005 ]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[An order shall be awarded to any citizen of the Republic of China offering honorable services to the nation or society.
Orders may also be awarded to foreigners to promote diplomatic relationships.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Orders are classified into the following types:
1. Order of Brilliant Jade with Grand Cordon.
2. Order of Dr. Sun Yat-sen with Grand Cordon.
3. Order of Chiang Chung-cheng with Grand Cordon.
4. Order of Propitious Clouds.
5. Order of Brilliant Star.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The President dons the Order of Brilliant Jade with Grand Cordon.
The Order of Brilliant Jade with Grand Cordon may be awarded to heads of foreign states and may be presented by an authorized delegate.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Individuals offering the following honorable services may be awarded the Order of Dr. Sun Yat-sen with Grand Cordon by the President in person:
1. Managing a master plan for the stability of the nation.
2. Acting as the pillar of society in crushing rebellions or averting disasters.
3. Other honorable services to the building of the nation.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Individuals offering the following honorable services may be awarded the Order of Chiang Chung-cheng with Grand Cordon by the President in person:
1.Outstanding achievement in implementing the Three Principles of the People.
2. Outstanding contribution in debunking communism and the building of the nation.
3.Outstanding performance in the rehabilitation of Chinese culture.
4.Outstanding services in implementing the democratic constitution.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Civil servants offering the following honorable services may be awarded the Order of Propitious Clouds or the Order of Brilliant Star:
1.Facilitating and implementing our nation's executive, legislative, judicial, examination, or control systems.
2. Nourishing the economy, education, or culture of our nation.
3.Consolidating diplomatic relationships through tactful negotiation and friendliness to distant neighbors.
4. Promoting virtuous conduct, caring for people nationwide, and securing national frontiers.
5. Skillful handling of affairs about overseas Chinese.
6. Mitigating disasters, comforting people without housing, and bringing benefits to the people.
7. Keeping local order and eliminating hazards of life safety.
8.Civil servants at the national or regional level who have served for more than 10 years.
9. Outstanding achievements in assisting the governance.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Individuals other than civil servants offering the following honorable services may be awarded the Order of Propitious Clouds or the Order of Brilliant Star:
1. Identify distinctive inventions or profound contributions that benefit the nation and its people.
2. Establishing sizable charity organizations that cater to social well-being.
3. Sustained efforts in establishing educational or cultural businesses, at home or abroad, that serve as role models.
4. Frequent success in guarding the local territory and averting disasters that deserve to be remembered.
5. Efficient management of business enterprise to assist the running of the government, benefiting the public.
6. Demonstrating profound knowledge and publishing important written works, benefiting the culture or education.
7. Dedication to citizen diplomacy.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Foreigners offering the following honorable services may be awarded the Order of Propitious Clouds or the Order of Brilliant Star:
1. Suppressing violence or safeguarding justice to benefit our nation.
2. Notable success in promoting and spreading our culture.
3. Assistance with the diplomacy between our government and other countries.
4. Facilitating materials or moral support from foreign governments or people.
5. Outstanding contribution in constructing the infrastructure of our nation.
6. Establishing educational or charity organizations that benefit our society.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The previous three Articles may also be applied to individuals who offer honorable services to our nation and society that are not mentioned in the previous three articles.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 10</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Order of Brilliant Jade with Grand Cordon, Order of Dr. Sun Yat-sen with Grand Cordon, and Order of Chiang Chung-cheng with Grand Cordon are awarded with a Grand Cordon. The Order of Propitious Clouds or the Order of Brilliant Star is awarded with Grand Cordon, Cravat, Rosette with Ribbon, or Rosette according to the different degrees of services the recipient offers.
The attached table shows the verbal description and graphic representation of the orders.
Table.PDF
Table.doc
Attachment.PDF
Attachment.doc]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 11</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Order of Propitious Clouds or the Order of Brilliant Star is awarded according to different degrees of services offered. The President awards the first level in person. The other levels are awarded by the recipients’ superintending Yuan or superintendent.
If the recipient is abroad, the relevant embassy or consulate may award the order.
The orders shall be awarded with certificates.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 12</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[After an order is awarded, the recipient may receive a different type of order due to accumulated services. However, the same recipient shall be awarded only one type of order simultaneously.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 13</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[All applications for the award shall be reviewed by the Honorary Deeds Review Committee, except when the President bestows the order.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 14</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The award of orders for army, navy, and air force members shall be subject to other legislation.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 15</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Recipients subject to disfranchisement shall return the orders and certificates.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 16</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Ministry of the Interior, the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, the Overseas Chinese Affairs Council, and the Ministry of Civil Service shall establish the enforcement rules of this Act.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 17</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This Act shall be implemented from its day of announcement.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
