<法規>
<法規性質>法律</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Presidential and Vice Presidential Oath Act</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>總統副總統宣誓條例</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=A0030001</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>19540513</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.The full text of 7 Articles enacted and promulgated by President Order on 13 May 1954]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The oaths of President and Vice President shall be governed by the provisions of this Act.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The President and Vice President shall take oaths on the day of the President’s assumption of office.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The oath of the President is in accordance with the provision of Article 48 of the Constitution. The oath of the Vice President is as follows:
“I do solemnly and sincerely swear before the people of the whole country that I will observe the Constitution and be loyal to the nation. Should I break my oath, I shall be willing to submit myself to severe punishment by the State. This is my solemn oath.”]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The President and Vice President shall separately take an oath in a public ceremony at the seat of the Central Government, and the Chief Justice shall be the person administering the oaths.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The President and Vice President shall stand at attention and face to the national flag and the picture of Dr. Sun Yat-sen, raise the right hand up with an open palm, fingers together, and palm facing forward, and read the oath while taking the oath.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The oath documents shall be signed and stamped by the President and Vice President separately, and be submitted to the agency of the supervisor for future reference.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This Act shall take effect on the date of promulgation.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
