<法規>
<法規性質>法律</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>THE LAW IN SUPPORTING FOREIGN COURTSON CONSIGNED CASES</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>外國法院委託事件協助法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawContent.aspx?PCODE=B0010014</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>19630425</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1. Promulgated on April 25, 1963]]></沿革內容>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Unless otherwise provided for in laws or pacts,this Law governs courts when they are consigned by a foreign court to help take charge of civil or criminal cases.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[A court,when consigned by a foreign court to help take charge of civil or criminal cases,shall not conflict laws of the Republic of China.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The consigned cases shall be conveyed in writing through foreign affairs authorities.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The country of the consigning foreign court shall declare reciprocal support the Republic of China courts in a similar case.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The documents of civil or criminal cases for which a court is consigned by a foreign court to help take charge shall be duly served according to document service provisions in the Code of Civil or Criminal Procedure.
（2）The service document shall expressly bear the name,nationality,domicile,address or office of the party to be served.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The exhibits or evidence of civil or criminal cases for which a court is consigned by a foreign court to help investigate shall be duly handled according to evidence investigation in the Code of Civil or Criminal Procedure.
（2）For consigned investigation into evidence,the power of attorney shall expressly bear the names of the involved parties,methods and categories of evidence, the name,nationality,domicile,address or office of the parties to be investigated,and the subjects of investigation,and,in case of a criminal case,summary of the case.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Chinese translation versions,along with the affidavit of faithful conformity between Chinese and foreign language shall accompany the Power of attorney or other documents in a foreign language.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The service and investigation costs shall be duly handled according to the relevant regulations of the Republic of China in civil cases,and shall be counted at actual spending and reimbursed by the country of the consigning foreign court in criminal cases.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This Law comes into force upon promulgation.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
