<法規>
<法規性質>法律</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Act of Supervising Temples</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>監督寺廟條例</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawContent.aspx?PCODE=D0020027</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>19291207</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated by the Government of the Republic of China on December 7, 1929]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Buildings occupied by monks/nuns, regardless of their name or title, will be referred to and regarded as temples.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The temple, its property and possessions will be under supervision of this act, besides other specifications in the law.
Possession in caption refers to statues, idols, worship and musical instruments, talismans, scripture, sculptures, paintings and any antiques long possessed/preserved by the temple.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Temples under the clauses listed below, will not be   affected by this act:
1. Administered by the Government.
2. Administered by local pubic organizations.
3. Founded and administered by private persons.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Temples which are neglected will be administered by the local autonomy group.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Temple property and possessions ought to be declared and registered with the local administration.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Ownership of all property and possessions will be retained by the temple and managed by the trustee monk/nun.
Trustee monk/nun refers to any monk or nun who has management authority, whatever their title or ranking may be.
However, they cannot take charge as trustee monk/nun if they are not citizens of the Republic of China.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Trustee monks/nuns are not to use incomes derived from temple property except for the purpose of giving religious instruction, upholding the commandments and other miscellaneous expenses with proper usage.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[A temple’s fixed properties and possessions are not to be disposed of, or altered, unless and until the decision has ratified and approved by its related religious association, and thereafter submitted to the jurisdictional government administration for permission.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The sum of expenses and/or income and benefits organized by the temple should be reported to the jurisdictional government administration semi-annually and made public.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 10</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[It is incumbent that a temple initiates benefits or charities in accordance with its financial status.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 11</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[For violation of the fifth, the sixth or the tenth articles of this act, the jurisdictional government administration will dismiss the trustee monk/nun.  Violation of the seventh and the eighth articles will result in banishment from the temple or prosecution in a court of law.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 12</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This act is not applicable to temples in Tibet, Xi-Kang, Mongolia and Qing-Hai.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 13</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This act become effected on their date of publication.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
