<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Regulations for Report and File Management of Suspected Delay Development Children</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>疑似發展遲緩兒童通報流程及檔案管理辦法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=D0050179</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20220725</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Table 1　suspected delay development children report table.pdf]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000007562</下載網址>
  </檔案>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Table 1　suspected delay development children report table.doc]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000007563</下載網址>
  </檔案>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Table x 2　Form of Response to the Report of Child With Suspected Developmental Delay.doc]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000007564</下載網址>
  </檔案>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Table x 2　Form of Response to the Report of Child With Suspected Developmental Delay.pdf]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000007565</下載網址>
  </檔案>
</附件>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated by Order Tai-Ne-Tong No.1010840183 on May 29rd, 2012
2.Promulgated by the Ministry of Health and Welfare Order Wei-Shou-Jia-Zi No.1110960736 on July 25, 2022.
]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These regulations are established in accordance with paragraph 2 article 32 of Children and Youth Welfare Act.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Social welfare, education and medical care institutions discover suspected delay development children should fill up suspected delay development children report table (Table 1) within one week from the date of discovery, and report to competent authorities of the municipality and provincial county (city) governments of the child's place of residence by telecommunication equipment, electronic communication, Internet, or other similar means.
The preceding paragraph shall apply mutatis mutandis to parents or family childcare service providers with suspected developmental delay and shall also apply to other relevant personnel who discover such a child.
Competent authorities of the municipality and provincial county (city) governments should fill up the treatment situation in suspected delay development children reply table as attached table 2, and reply for the report institution or person.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[When competent authorities of the municipality and provincial county (city) governments receive the reports in previous article ,they should key in the data in the case management information system to manage and evaluate. A child’s individual service plan shall be provided in accordance with the evaluation results.
The plan in previous paragraph should be practiced with case management by social workers, other related professionals and the child’s primary caregivers to ensure the provision of child- and family-related treatment services.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The child’s individual service plan specified in the first paragraph of the preceding article shall include the following content:
1. Demographic information of the child and their family.
2. Analysis of the child’s development and needs.
3. Family needs, resources, and parenting skills.
4. Items, frequency, expected goals, strategies and methods, and implementation schedule of the service.
5. Other assistance and welfare services related to child and family functions.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Social workers or other relevant professionals implementing the plan specified in Paragraph 1 of Article 3 shall produce work records and create a database to be retained for at least 7 years.
The records and files referred to in the preceding paragraph shall be registered or uploaded to the system according to the requirements of the central competent authority.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Competent authorities of the municipality and provincial county (city) governments can commission their subordinate authorities or delegate related juridical persons or group to perform all of these tasks in these Regulations.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Regulations have come into effect on the promulgation date.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
