<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Regulations on Management of Volunteer Service Certificates and Service Record Books</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>志願服務證及服務紀錄冊管理辦法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawContent.aspx?PCODE=D0050132</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20010420</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated on April 20, 2001]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulations are enacted pursuant to Paragraph 2, Article 12 of the Volunteer Service Act.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[After a volunteer finishes the training, the volunteer service exerciser shall grant him a volunteer service certificate and a service 
record book (hereinafter referred to as “Service Certificate” and “Record Book”).
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[A Service Certificate shall include such contents as volunteer service mark, name and photo of the volunteer, the organization 
granting the certificate, and serial number etc., and shall be fabricated, granted and managed by the volunteer service exerciser. 
Service Certificates are used for identification of volunteers, and may not be used for other purposes.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[A Record Book records all the services provided by a volunteer, and the format shall be prescribed by the central competent 
authority; Record Books shall be printed by the central regulating department of objective undertaking.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[A volunteer service exerciser shall submit a list of the volunteers and two pieces of half-length photos of each volunteer to the 
local regulating department of objective undertaking to apply for the record books, and transfer them to the volunteers. The 
volunteer service exercisers that are not subordinate to local regulating departments of objective undertaking shall claim the 
record books from the central regulating department of objective undertaking. 
The above-mentioned list of volunteers shall include such contents as name, sex, date of birth, and ID card number or passport 
number.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[A Service Certificate and a Record Book shall be used and stored by the volunteer himself/herself, and may not be borrowed to 
others, used by someone else, or used inappropriately; otherwise, the volunteer service exerciser shall correct and record the 
action, and not adopt the service records.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Where a volunteer works for another volunteer service exerciser, the Record Book shall continue to be used.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[In case of damage or loss of a Record Book, the volunteer may request the volunteer service exerciser to apply for a new 
Record Book according to Article 5.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Registration in a Record Book shall be performed by the personnel designated by the volunteer service exerciser, and attention 
shall be paid to the following provisions:
1.Service items shall be filled in according to the fact, and service contents shall be listed in detail.
2.Hours of service refer to the hours of providing actual service, and shall not include the round-trip time.
3.The name of the recorder shall be signed and seal stamped.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 10</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[A volunteer service exerciser may call back the Service Certificate of a volunteer who is unfit for the work, and write off the 
certificate number.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 11</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[A volunteer service exerciser shall establish individual service archives of the volunteers, so as to establish complete service 
information.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 12</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Regulating departments of objective undertakings may randomly examine the usage status of Service Certificates and Record 
Books at any time.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 13</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulations will take effect as of the date of promulgation.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
