<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Establishment Standards of Senior Citizens’ Welfare Institutions</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>老人福利機構設立標準</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=D0050039</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20210205</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated by Order Tai -Nei-She-Tzu No.58495 on Nov. 30th, 1981
2.Amended and promulgated by Tai-Nei-She-Tzu No8782311 and Department of Health Yi-Tzu No. 87032697 on June 17th, 1998.
3.Amended and promulgated by Nei-Shou-Zhong-She-Tzu No960714040 and Department of Health Zhou-Tzu No. 0962801277 on June 30th, 2007
4.Amended of Article 17, 21, 22, 37 and 38 and promulgated by Nei-Shou-Zhong-She-Tzu No1015935358 and Department of Health Zhou-Tzu No. 1012800484 on December 3rd, 2012
5.Amended and promulgated by Wei- Shou-Chia-Tzu No1090800910 on Feb.fifth,2021]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <編章節>   Chapter 1 General Principles</編章節>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These standards are stipulated according to paragraph 2 of Article 34 and paragraph 6 of Article 36 of the Senior Welfare Act( hereinafter referred to as “the Act”).]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Senior citizen welfare institutions defined in these standards are categorized on the basis of care recipient as follows
(1).long-term care institutions: with the following three categories:
A. long-term care: services for senior citizens with long-term chronic diseases requiring nursing services.
B. nursing: services to senior citizens lack of capability to take care of himself or herself and in need of other’s caring, or senior citizens in need of nursing services such as nasogastric tube, gastrostomy tube, or catheter.
C. caring for dementia senior citizens: caring services to senior citizens who are diagnosed as middle degree dementia and capable of moving by himselves or herselves but needs caring services by doctors of neurology or psychiatry, or other.
(2).Domiciliary care institutions: services to senior citizens in need of care services from others, or senior citizens who can take care of himselves or herselves for daily life but without any relative with legal support obligation, or relative with legal support obligation but unable to fulfill this obligation.
(3).Other Senior Citizens’ Welfare Institutions: care for senior citizens requiring other welfare services.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Establishment of Senior Citizens’ Welfare Institutions should comply with the following rules:
(1).Designs, structure, and equipments of the building should comply with Building Law and related regulations.
(2).The maximum number of floors is limited to 10.
(3).Safety issues for fire control such as fire control equipments, fire control management, non-flame retardant substances should comply with Fire Act and related rules and regulations.
(4).The land to be used should comply with related regulations on land use control.
(5).Supply of drinking water should be sufficient and water quality should meet with quality standards for drinking water.
(6).Maintenance of cleaning and hygiene of environments and proper measures to prevent and control media and resources harmful to hygiene.
(7).Stipulations in other rules and regulations.
The second subparagraph of the preceding paragraph does not apply to other regulations that have been established and approved before the implementation of this amended standard on February 7, 2021.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[In addition to the requirements stipulated in the previous Article, long term care institutions and nursing institutions should possess following qualified facilities and equipment:
(1).Dormitory:
A. Good ventilation and sufficient lights. Windows with natural lighting should be established.
B. Location in basement is not allowed.
C. There should be closets and bed side cupboards for each bed located in-doors. Emergency call system should be set up. The distance between two beds should be at least 80 centimeters wide.
D. At least one door with net-width of at least 80 centimeters.
E. For rooms with 2 or multiple beds, screens to isolate eyesight should be set up.
F. The compartments separating the dormitories must reach the floor.
G. Corridor with direct access to the dormitory without passing through the corridors of other dormitories.
(2).Nursing stations:
A. Equipped with whistles, portable loudspeakers, batons, and antismoke masks or gas masks that can protect the eyes, mouth, and nose.
B. Institutions larger than two floors must be equipped with radios and spare batteries.
(3).Bathing and hygiene facilities :
A. At least one door with net-width of at least 80 centimeters.
B. Adequate walls or curtains should be set up for bathing and hygiene facilities utilized by multiple persons.
C. Bathing and hygiene facilities should be set up in the care zones with emergency call system.
D. Bathing and hygiene facilities suitable for senior citizens lying on the beds or using wheelchairs.
(4).Kitchen:
A. Food-heating, storage, and freezing equipment must be installed.
B. A location to install washing facilities must be designated, and a sufficient supply of running tap water must be ensured. Regular inspections of non–tap water sources must be conducted, and dishwashing and sterilization facilities must be provided.
C. Oil exhaust facilities and other required equipment must be installed.
D. Facilities must maintain proper air pressure and room temperature.
(5).Other facilities and equipment:
A. Equipment such as railings and handrails must be installed at care zones, the cafeteria, bathrooms, corridors, stairways, and landings. Proper antislip and lighting equipment must be installed in the stairways, corridors, and bathrooms of each floor.
B. Public telephones must suit the needs of senior citizens with physical or mental disabilities or impaired mobility.
C. Storage facilities for quilts, bed sheets, supplies, wheelchairs, and other miscellaneous items must be established.
D. Emergency lighting equipment.
Unless otherwise specified in these standards, the institutions in the preceding paragraph may create social lounges, physiotherapy rooms, functional therapy rooms, prayer rooms, hospice care rooms, emergency observation wards, and facilities for catering and waste disposal depending on their needs.
Established senior citizen welfare institutions and those that received construction permits but were incomplete before the implementation of the amended standards are not subject to the restrictions of Article 1, Subsection 1, Item 6.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[For senior citizen welfare institutions providing home and day care services, the scale, area, facilities, staffing, qualifications, registration process, and continued education program must comply with the Long-Term Care Services Act and related regulations.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Regarding the standards for floor areas of institutions and facilities, the calculation does not include space of parking lot and dormitories for employees. As for the rule on the floor of dormitory, the floor areas of bathroom and toilet are not included in the calculation.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Long-term care and care institutions established by the various levels of the government, registered as foundations, or affiliated with foundations are limited to 200 persons. However, this limitation does not apply to institutions that have been permitted to register or operate before February 2, 2007.
Small-scale long-term care or care institutions as described in paragraphs 2 and 6 of Article 36 of the Act are limited to 49 persons.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[One full-time personnel in charge of overseeing the comprehensive operations of the institutions should be employed for long term care and nursing institutions. He or she will be in charge of the business for the institution and supervise his or her subordinate to fulfill their duties. Following personnel should also be set up:
(1).Nursing personnel: responsible for nursing business and records.
(2).Social workers: responsible for business related to social work.
(3).Care givers: responsible for taking care of the daily life of the senior citizens.
(4).Other professionals related to the services provided.
The personnel in the preceding paragraph must possess the required qualifications and training experience for senior welfare professionals and report to the competent authority within 30 days after appointment, resignation, or any other change in employment status.
In the event that the individual in charge of operations is unable to perform his or her duties, an individual with the same qualifications shall be appointed as a delegate for no more than 1 year. If the delegation exceeds 30 days, it must be reported to the competent authority.
Unless otherwise stipulated in these standards, personnel from subparagraph 1 to 3 in paragraph 1 should work full-time while personnel of subparagraph 4 could be either full-time or contracted personnel.
A minimum of one-quarter of all social workers must possess social worker certifications and practicing licenses as prescribed in paragraph 1, subparagraph 2. As prescribed in subparagraph 3, the number of foreign caregivers must not exceed the number of full-time Taiwanese caregivers unless otherwise specified in these standards.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <編章節>   Chapter 2 Long term caring institutions</編章節>
  <編章節>      Section 1 Long term care institutions</編章節>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Long-term care institutions must have an average area of at least 16 m2 per senior citizen receiving care.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 10</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[In addition to rules stipulated in Article 4, facilities and equipment of long term care institutions should also qualify for the following:
(1).Dormitory:
A. Floor area per person should be more than 7 square meters. The number of beds should not exceed 6 beds per room.
B. Handrail and height-adjustment gears should be set up on each bed. The distance between the end of the bed and the wall should be at least 1 meter.
C. Simple hygiene facilities should be set up on each room for institutions with more 50 senior citizens accommodated.
(2).Nursing stations:
A. Preparation area and working cart.
B. Closet for nursing records and closet for medicine, medical equipments, and refrigerators for medicine.
C. Adequate equipments for emergency rescue: oxygen, nasal passage, artificial air passage, oxygen mask, sucking equipments, laryngoscopes, inner tube for air passage, resuscitation bags, regular emergency medicines.
D. Wheelchair.
E. Pollutant or medical waste collection equipment.
(3).Width of the aisle in the nursing area should be at least 140 centimeters and the width should be at least 160 centimeters for aisles with dormitories on either side.
(4).Locations for daily activities: Cafeteria, space and facilities needed for recreational activities should be set up with the average space per person of at least 4 square meters. However, the corridor area is not included.
(5).Air conditioning equipments: Central air-conditioning systems must be equipped with an automatic power-off function through fire alarm systems or other equipment.
(6).Generators or other power-generating equipment.
(7). Other facilities: dedicated ramps for hospital beds or wheelchairs must be installed at the main corridor steps.
For senior citizen welfare institutions established before the implementation of these amended standards on February 7, 2021, corridors used as a space for daily activities may be included in the total activity area.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 11</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The work and staffing requirements of long-term care institutions, in addition to those for the directors overseeing the institutions, are as follows:
(1).Nursing personnel
A. Maintain a minimum of one person on duty at all times.
B. One nurse must be appointed for every 15 senior citizens cared for. Any number less than 15 is treated as 15.
(2).Social workers: One social worker must be appointed for every 100 senior citizens cared for. Any number less than 100 is counted as 100. However, special arrangements can be made for cases of fewer than 49 senior citizens. In such cases, social workers must work a minimum of 16 hours per week.
(3).Care givers:
A. Maintain a minimum of one Taiwanese caregiver on duty at all times.
B. One caregiver must be appointed for every five senior citizens cared for during the daytime. Any number less than five is treated as five.
C. One caregiver must be appointed for every 15 senior citizens cared for during the night. Any number less than 15 is treated as 15.
Welfare institutions may employ part-time personnel in addition to the personnel described in the preceding paragraphs. However, part-time personnel must not exceed one-third of the professionals in a certain category, and each staff member must work for minimum of 16 hours per week.
“Daytime” in paragraph 1, subparagraph 3 refers to 8 am to 8 pm, and “night” refers to 8 pm to 8 am.
Institutions may appoint administrative staff, medical staff, and other staff members depending on their operational needs. Such staff members must comply with all medical laws and regulations when providing medical care services.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 12</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Senior citizens attended by the long term care institutions should be diagnosed by doctor and at one visit per month by the doctor depending on the medical needs of the senior citizens.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 13</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Long term care institutions should, following laws related to medical staffs, keep good record of dossier abstracts from referral services and doctor’s diagnosis as well as record of nursing history.
The dossier abstract and the record of nursing history shall be managed by designated staff.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <編章節>      Section 2 Nursing institutions</編章節>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 14</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Nursing institutions established by the various levels of the government and registered as foundations (hereinafter referred to as “public and foundation nursing institutions”) must have an area of at least 16 m2 per senior citizen cared for.
Small nursing institutions must have an average area of at least 10 m2 per senior citizen cared for.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 15</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Facilities and equipment of public and foundation nursing institutions should comply with rules stipulated in Article 4 as well as the rules of the followings:
(1).Dormitory:
A. Floor area should be more than 7 square meters per person. Maximum number of beds for every room is 6.
B. Simple hygiene facilities should be set up in every dormitory for institutions with more than 50 senior citizens accommodated.
(2).Nursing station:
A. Preparation areas and working carts.
B. Nursing record cabinets, storage cabinets for medicine and medical equipment, and refrigerators for medicine.
C. First aid equipment.
D. Wheelchairs.
E. Pollutants or medical waste collection equipment.
(3).Location for daily activities: Space and equipments needed for facilities such as cafeteria and recreational activities should be set up with floor area of more than 4 square meters per person. However, the corridor area is not included.
(4).Central air-conditioning systems must be equipped with an automatic power-off function through fire alarm systems or other equipment.
(5).Other facilities and equipment: Other facilities and equipment: pollutant treatment room, laundry room, and other spaces and equipment
For senior citizen welfare institutions established before the implementation of these amended standards on February 7, 2021, corridors used as a space for daily activities may be included in the total activity area. However, this is not applicable to newly built institutions and those with newly added buildings or renovated partition walls.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 16</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The work and staffing requirements of public and foundation nursing institutions, in addition to those for the directors overseeing the institutions, are as follows:
(1).Nursing personnel:
A. Maintain a minimum of one person on duty at all times.
B. One nurse must be appointed for every 20 senior citizens cared for. Any number less than 20 is treated as 20.
(2).Social workers: One social worker must be appointed for every 100 senior citizens cared for. Any number less than 100 is treated as 100. However, special arrangements can be made for cases of fewer than 49 senior citizens. In such cases, social workers must work a minimum of 16 hours per week.
(3).Care givers:
A. Maintain a minimum of one Taiwanese caregiver on duty at all times.
B. One caregiver must be appointed for every eight senior citizens cared for during the daytime. Any number less than eight is treated as eight.
C. One caregiver must be appointed for every 25 senior citizens cared for during the night. Any number less than 25 is treated as 25.
Institutions mentioned in the preceding paragraph that provide care for senior citizens requiring care services that involve nasogastric tubes, gastrostomy tubes, and urinary catheters must employ nursing staff in accordance with Article 11.
Welfare institutions may employ part-time personnel in addition to the personnel described in the preceding paragraphs. However, part-time personnel must not exceed one-third of the professionals in a certain category, and each staff member must work for minimum of 16 hours per week.
“Daytime” in paragraph 1, subparagraph 3 refers to 8 am to 8 pm, and “night” refers to 8 pm to 8 am.
Institutions may appoint administrative staff, medical staff, and other staff members depending on their operational needs. Such staff members must comply with all medical laws and regulations when providing medical care services.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 17</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[In addition to the rule stipulated in Article 4, facilities and equipment of small size nursing institutions should also comply with the following rules:
(1).Dormitory: Floor area should be more than 5 square meters per person. Maximum number of beds for each room is 6.
(2).Nursing station:
A. Preparation areas and working carts.
B. Nursing record cabinets, storage cabinets for medicine and medical equipment, and refrigerators for medicine.
C. First aid equipment.
D. Wheelchairs.
E. Pollutants or medical waste collection equipment.
(3).Location of daily activities: Multi-functional space and facilities should be set up.
(4).Central air-conditioning systems must be equipped with an automatic power-off function through fire alarm systems or other equipment.
(5).Toilet: At least one toilet for man and two toilets for woman for every 16 senior citizens attended. The number would be treated as 16 if the actual number of senior citizens attended is less. Another set of toilet for man and two toilets for woman will be added for any additional 16 senior citizens.
The added toilets specified in preceding paragraph 5 can be replaced by removable potty seats.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 18</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The work and staffing requirements of small nursing institutions, in addition to those for the directors overseeing the institutions, are as follows:
(1).Nursing personnel:
A.Maintain a minimum of one person on duty at all times.
B. One nurse must be appointed for every 20 senior citizens cared for. Any number less than 20 is treated as 20.
(2).Social workers: social workers are employed as full-time staff or recruited through special arrangements, in which case they must work a minimum of 16 hours per week.
(3).Care givers:
A. Maintain a minimum of one Taiwanese caregiver on duty at all times.
B. One caregiver must be appointed for every eight senior citizens cared for during the daytime. Any number less than eight is treated as eight.
C. One caregiver must be appointed for every 25 senior citizens cared for during the night. Any number less than 25 is treated as 25.
Institutions accepting senior citizens in need of nursing services such as nasogastric tube, gastrostomy tubes, or catheter should establish nursing staff according to the rules stipulated in Article 11.
Welfare institutions may employ part-time personnel in addition to the personnel described in the preceding paragraphs. However, part-time personnel must not exceed one-third of the professionals in a certain category, and each staff member must work for minimum of 16 hours per week.
“Daytime” in paragraph 1, subparagraph 3 refers to 8 am to 8 pm, and “night” refers to 8 pm to 8 am.
Institutions may appoint administrative staff, medical staff, and other staff members depending on their operational needs. Such staff members must comply with all medical laws and regulations when providing medical care services.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 19</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Nursing institutions that provide care services for senior citizens who require nasogastric tubes, gastrostomy tubes, and urinary catheters must report to the competent authority for permission. The number of senior citizens stated above should not exceed 1/2 of the total number originally approved. Article 12 and Article 13 will also be applied.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 20</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Floor area, facilities, equipment, and establishment of personnel for small nursing institutions registered as foundations or affiliated with foundations will apply the rules stipulated in the 1st paragraph of Article 14, Article 15 and Article 16.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <編章節>      Section 3 Institutions caring for dementia senior citizens</編章節>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 21</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Institutions caring for senior citizens with dementia must have an area of at least 16 m2 per senior citizen.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 22</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Institutions caring for dementia senior citizens should apply unit caring pattern. Basically, the number of senior citizens attended per unit shall not be more than 16 persons.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 23</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Facilities and equipment for institutions caring for dementia senior citizens should comply with the rules stipulated in Article 4 and the followings:
(1).Dormitory:
A. Floor area should be more than 7 square meters per person with one senior per room in principle. Each room shall not be equipped with more than four beds; the number of beds of all rooms for four senior citizens shall not exceed half of beds of the total units. Rooms for two senior citizens or more shall be equipped with barriers for the separation of personal living space.
B. Simple hygiene facilities should be set up in each dormitory.
C. Entrance and exit of each dormitory should connect with aisles or living rooms. Definite division between dormitories should be set up. Objects such as screen or curtain are not allowed to be used to divide dormitories.
(2).Nursing station:
A. Preparation areas and working carts.
B. Nursing record cabinets, storage cabinets for medicine and medical equipment, and refrigerators for medicine.
C. First aid equipment.
D. Pollutants or medical waste collection equipment.
(3).Basic facilities for the daily life of every unit should, in addition to dormitory, include living room, cafeteria, simply kitchen, bathing and hygiene facilities (lavatories, bathroom and toilets) and other necessary facilities.
(4).Locations for daily activities: space and equipments needed for recreational activities should be established.
(5).Central air-conditioning systems must be equipped with an automatic power-off function through fire alarm systems or other equipment.
(6). Other facilities and equipment: pollutant treatment room, laundry room, and other spaces and equipment]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 24</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The work and staffing requirements of institutions providing care for senior citizens with dementia, in addition to those for the directors overseeing the institutions, are as follows:
(1).Nursing personnel:
A. Maintain a minimum of one person on duty at all times.
B. One nurse must be appointed for every 20 senior citizens cared for. Any number less than 20 is treated as 20. Nurses not overseeing nursing beds for senior citizens who require care services related to nasogastric tubes, gastrostomy tubes, and urinary catheters may also be appointed.
(2).Social workers: One social worker must be appointed for every 100 senior citizens cared for. Any number less than 100 is treated as 100. However, special arrangements can be made for cases of less than 49 senior citizens. In such cases, social workers must work a minimum of 16 hours per week.
(3).Care givers:
A. Maintain a minimum of one Taiwanese caregiver on duty at all times.
B. One caregiver must be appointed for every three senior citizens cared for during the daytime. Any number less than three is treated as three.
C. One caregiver must be appointed for every 15 senior citizens cared for during the night. Any number less than 15 is treated as 15.
The caregivers mentioned in subparagraph 3 of the preceding paragraph can be part-time caregivers.
Welfare institutions may employ part-time personnel in addition to the personnel described in the preceding paragraphs. However, part-time personnel must not exceed one-third of the professionals in a certain category, and each staff member must work for minimum of 16 hours per week. Full-time and part-time personnel must have fixed positions, and foreigners cannot be hired as caregivers.
“Daytime” in paragraph 1, subparagraph 3 refers to 8 am to 8 pm, and “night” refers to 8 pm to 8 am.
Institutions may appoint administrative staff, medical staff, and other staff members depending on their operational needs. Such staff members must comply with all medical laws and regulations when providing medical care services.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <編章節>   Chapter 3 Domiciliary caring institutions</編章節>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 25</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Care institutions established by the various levels of the government and registered as foundations (hereinafter referred to as “public and foundation nursing institutions”) must have an area of at least 20 m2 per senior citizen cared for.
Small care nursing institutions must have an average area of at least 10 m2 per senior citizen cared for.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 26</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Facilities and equipment for domiciliary caring institutions should comply with the rules stipulated in Article 4 and the followings:
(1).Dormitory:
A. Floor area should be more than 7 square meters per person with the maximum number of 3 beds for each dormitory.
B. Simple hygiene facilities should be set up in each dormitory.
C. Entrance and exit of each dormitory should connect with aisles or living rooms. Definite division between dormitories should be set up. Objects such as screen or curtain are not allowed to be used to divide dormitories.
(2).Nursing station:
A. Preparation areas and working carts.
B. Nursing record cabinets, storage cabinets for medicine and medical equipment, and refrigerators for medicine.
C. First aid equipment.
D. Pollutants or medical waste collection equipment.
(3).Locations for daily activities: Cafeteria, guest room, reading room, leisure and recreation activities room, religious services locations and other necessary facilities or equipments should be set up. Floor space for guest room, reading room, leisure and recreation activities room should be more than 6 square meters per person. However, the corridor area is not included.
The institutions in the preceding paragraph may install air-conditioning equipment to suit the needs of the individuals they provide care for. Central air-conditioning systems must be equipped with an automatic power-off function through fire alarm systems or other equipment.
For senior citizen welfare institutions established before the implementation of these amended standards on February 7, 2021, corridors used as a space for daily activities may be included in the total activity area. However, this is not applicable to newly built institutions and those with newly added buildings or renovated partition walls.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 27</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The work and staffing requirements of public and foundation care institutions, in addition to those for the directors overseeing the institutions, are as follows:
(1).Nursing personnel: Maintain a minimum of one person on duty at all times.
(2).Social workers: One social worker must be appointed for every 80 senior citizens cared for. Any number less than 80 is treated as 80. However, special arrangements can be made for cases of less than 49 senior citizens. In such cases, social workers must work a minimum of 16 hours per week.
(3).Care givers:
A. Maintain a minimum of one Taiwanese caregiver on duty at all times.
B. One caregiver must be appointed for every 15 senior citizens cared for during the daytime. Any number less than 15 is treated as 15.
C. One caregiver must be appointed for every 35 senior citizens cared for during the night. Any number less than 35 is treated as 35.
Welfare institutions may employ part-time personnel in addition to the personnel described in the preceding paragraphs. However, part-time personnel must not exceed one-third of the professionals in a certain category, and each staff member must work for minimum of 16 hours per week.
“Daytime” in paragraph 1, subparagraph 3 refers to 8 am to 8 pm, and “night” refers to 8 pm to 8 am.
Institutions may appoint administrative staff, medical staff, and other staff members depending on their operational needs. Such staff members must comply with all medical laws and regulations when providing medical care services.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 28</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Facilities and equipment for small size domiciliary caring institutions should comply with rules of Article 4 and the followings:
(1).Dormitory: Floor area should be more than 5 square meters per person with the maximum number of 3 beds for each dormitory.
(2).Locations for daily activities: Space and equipments for multi-functional activities should be set up.
(3).Nursing stations
A. Preparation areas and working carts.
B. Nursing record cabinets, storage cabinets for medicine and medical equipment, and refrigerators for medicine.
C. First aid equipment.
D. Pollutants or medical waste collection equipment.
The institutions in the preceding paragraph may install air-conditioning equipment to suit the needs of the individuals they provide care for. Central air-conditioning systems must be equipped with an automatic power-off function through fire alarm systems or other equipment.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 29</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The work and staffing requirements of small-scale care institutions, in addition to those for the directors overseeing the institutions, are as follows:
(1).Nursing personnel: Maintain a minimum of one person on duty at all times.
(2).Social workers: social workers are employed as full-time staff or recruited through special arrangements, in which case they must work a minimum of 16 hours per week.
(3).Care givers:
A. Maintain a minimum of one Taiwanese caregiver on duty at all times.
B. One caregiver must be appointed for every 15 senior citizens cared for during the daytime. Any number less than 15 is treated as 15.
C. One caregiver must be appointed for every 35 senior citizens cared for during the night. Any number less than 35 is counted as 35.
Welfare institutions may employ part-time personnel in addition to the personnel described in the preceding paragraphs. However, part-time personnel must not exceed one-third of the professionals in a certain category, and each staff member must work for minimum of 16 hours per week.
“Daytime” in paragraph 1, subparagraph 3 refers to 8 am to 8 pm, and “night” refers to 8 pm to 8 am.
Institutions may appoint administrative staff, medical staff, and other staff members depending on their operational needs. Such staff members must comply with all medical laws and regulations when providing medical care services.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 30</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Establishment of floor area, facilities, equipment, and personnel for small care institutions registered as foundations or affiliated with foundations should follow the rules of the 1st paragraph of Article 25, Article 26 and Article 27.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <編章節>   Chapter 4 Other Senior Citizens’ Welfare Institutions</編章節>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 31</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Cultural and recreational institutions and service organizations for senior citizens established before the implementation of the amended Act on February 2, 2007, shall provide home-based and community-based services as specified in Articles 17 and 18 of the Act. They may also provide voluntary recreational, cultural, artistic, technical, training, and social activities as required.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 32</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Cultural and recreational institutions and service organizations for senior citizens established before the implementation of the amended Act on February 2, 2007, shall have an indoor area of at least 200 m2, and the following facilities and equipment must be provided:
(1).Office, social worker office or service office.
(2).Multi-functional activities room.
(3).Classroom.
(4).Hygiene facilities .
(5).Other necessary facilities and equipment related to services.
Facilities of subparagraph 2 and 3 of previous paragraph could be adjusted and combined for use depending on actual situation. Facilities such as conference room, counseling room, reading room for library, hygiene and safety room, and other related facilities could be established depending on the business needs.
Institutions in the first paragraph that provide catering services must have cafeterias and kitchens.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 33</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Cultural and recreational institutions and service organizations for senior citizens established before the implementation of the amended Act on February 2, 2007, must appoint a minimum of one of the following personnel:
(1).Director.
(2).Social worker.
(3).Administrative personnel or service personnel.
For institutions in the preceding paragraph that provide home-based services as described in Article 17 of the Act or community-based services as described in Article 18 of the Act, labor resource allocation must be based on service content in accordance with the laws and medical regulations for long-term care services.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <編章節>   Chapter 5 Supplementary Provisions</編章節>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 34</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Long term care institutions and domiciliary care institutions adopting combined processing method should comply with the following rules:
(1).Standards for facilities and personnel for institutions with individually utilized areas and planning for fixed compartments and independent areas should follow rules stipulated in Chapter 2 and Chapter 3 respectively.
(2).Standards for facilities and personnel for institutions without fixed compartment and planning for independent area should be higher.
Scales for institutions of the previous paragraph should be calculated respectively according to various standards. Scale for the institutions with original establishment approval should exceed 1/2.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 35</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[After the implementation of the Long-Term Care Service Act on June 3, 2017, the establishment, expansion, or relocation of senior citizen welfare institutions providing long-term care services must comply with the act and related laws and regulations.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 36</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Welfare institutions that applied to the municipal or county (city) governments for the establishment, expansion, relocation, resumption of business and change of person in charge in accordance with the relevant regulations before the implementation of the amended Act on February 2, 2007, and whose application procedures are pending may be subject to the regulations in the amendment of these standards implemented on June 17, 1998.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 37</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Senior citizen welfare institutions that have been permitted to file for registration before the implementation of the amended Act on February 2, 2007, but fail to meet the requirements of the amendment implemented on July 30, 2008, shall complete improvement tasks for fulfilling the requirements within 5 years from the date of implementation of the amendment herein. Cases of failure to complete improvement within deadline will be handled in accordance with the Act. Senior Citizens’ Welfare Institutions stipulated in the previous Article will follow the same Act.
Senior citizen welfare institutions in remote areas, outlying islands, or indigenous community areas that have been permitted to file for registration before the implementation of the amended Act on February 2, 2007, and those that encounter challenges in the improvement process in accordance with the amendments implemented on July 30, 2007, may be exempted from the improvement tasks prescribed in the preceding paragraph after they have submitted exemption requests to the competent authority in the municipal and county (city) government for review and approved by the central competent authority.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 38</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These standards shall become effective after the promulgation date.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
