<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Regulations on Trust and Operation of Common Duct Construction Fund</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>共同管道建設基金收支保管及運用辦法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=D0070049</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20080108</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>廢</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.
2.Amended on April 15, 2002
3.Abolished on January 08, 2008]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The establishment of Common Duct Construction Fund (The Fund) is to meet the requirement of carrying Common Duct and various electric wires and electric cables into underground for all governmental, private and public organizations. The prescription of these regulations in accordance with Article 20 of Budget Law.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Income, payment, trust, and operation of the Fund shall follow these regulations, except otherwise specified by laws.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Fund, a special fund as specified in Item 2 Paragraph 1 Article 4 of Budget Law, is a sub-budget of division budget under the construction item. The Ministry of Interior (MOI) is the competent authority and the Construction and Planning Agency of MOI is the managing authority.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The sources of the Fund:
1.Governmental funding through recycled budgeting process.
2.Special amount provided by the utility agencies.
3.Interests income from the Fund.
4.Interests income from loan.
5.Donations.
6.Other related ones.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Use of the Fund:
1.As a loan to fund the cost of Common Duct construction in order to match the significant projects.
2.As a loan to fund the cost of Common Duct construction in the projects of new town and new community development.
3.As a loan to fund the construction cost of setting the various buried electric wires and cables into common duct on the same road.
4.Management and general administrative expenses.
2.Other related expenses.
The aforementioned amount of loan and the rate of interest shall be decided by the management committee of construction fund, under the condition that the fund can be continually operated. The interest of loans within the amount provided by the original utility agencies will be exempted.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Trust and operation of the fund shall emphasize profitability and safety, the banking process shall follow the Treasury Law and its related regulations.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Considering the operational need, the fund may be applied to purchase the governmental bond, Treasurer’s notes or other short-term notes.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The related budgeting and executing and final financial statement of the Fund shall follow the Budget Law, Accounting law, Statutory Law, Auditing Law and related regulations.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The accounting procedures of the Fund shall establish an accounting system in accordance with the related regulations.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 10</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Any balance exists after the final financial statement shall be entering as an additional fund or treated as undivided profit.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 11</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Fund shall close book upon its conclusion, and the rest profit shall be transferred to the Treasury.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 12</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These regulations shall become enforceable upon the date of promulgation.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
