<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Fee-charging Standard on Access to Government Information Provided by Ocean Affairs Council and its Subordinate Agencies (Organizations)</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>海洋委員會及所屬機關（構）提供政府資訊收費標準</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=D0090023</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20190723</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[The Fee-charging Standard Table for Duplicating or Copying Government Information.pdf]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000005888</下載網址>
  </檔案>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[The Fee-charging Standard Table for Duplicating or Copying Government Information.doc]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000005889</下載網址>
  </檔案>
</附件>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.The Coast Guard Administration, Executive Yuan enacted the Fee-charging Standard on Access to Government Information Provided by Coast Guard Authority on May 12, 2006.
  As the original Cost Guard Administration, Executive Yuan and its business have been transferred to the Ocean Affairs Council and its subordinate agencies (organizations), the relevant contents of Article 8 thereof is hereby amended accordingly, and the title of the Standard is amended to be "Fee-charging Standard on Access to Government Information Provided by Ocean Affairs Council and its Subordinate Agencies (Organizations)".
2.Amended on July 23, 2019.]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This Standard is enacted according to paragraph 2 of Article 22 of the Freedom of Government Information Law (hereinafter referred to as “the Law”).]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The fee for browsing, transcribing, or photographing government information is NT$20 for every two hours. Time spent less than two hours is counted as two hours.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The fee for duplicating or copying government information shall be charged in accordance with the Fee-charging Standard Table for Duplicating or Copying Government Information as set forth in the attachment.  The items undefined in the above Fee-charging Standard Table shall be charged in accordance with the actual costs of duplication or copying.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[If the applicant requests that the duplicated or copied government information be sent by mail, the applicant shall be charged for the actual mailing expenses.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The applicant that requests the government information for academic research or public interest purposes shall file the request with the relevant documentary proof attached. After the request is approved, except for mailing costs which are still charged based on actual expenses, all charges shall be reduced by half.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The requested government information that falls within the scope of business or educational promotions as defined in paragraph 1, Article 12 of the Charges and Fees Act may be provided free of charge.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The collection of fees as listed in this Standard shall comply with the budgetary procedures.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Ocean Affairs Council and its subordinate agencies (Affiliated institutions) with business of special nature may set forth their charging standards separately for providing government information pursuant to Paragraph 2, Article 22 of the Law.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This Standard shall be effective immediately upon the date of promulgation.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
