<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Regulations For Authentication of Civic Voluntary Organizations Assisting in Disaster Prevention and Protection Works</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>協助執行災害防救工作民間志願組織認證辦法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawContent.aspx?PCODE=D0120016</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20081119</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>廢</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1. Promulgated by Order Tai (90)-Nei-Hsiao-Tzu N0.9086638 of the National Fire Agency, Ministry of the Interior on June 1st, 2001.
2. Abolished on November 19, 2008]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This Method is enacted pursuant to the first section of Article 50 of the Disaster Prevention and Response Law.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Civil voluntary organizations assisting in disaster prevention and response shall submit the following documents tothe Ministry of the Interior (hereinafter referred to as “the Ministry”) to apply for authentication.
(1)Letter of application,
(2)List of organization members and their qualified certificates of professional training related to disaster rescue, and
(3)Registration in municipal, county (city) government or disaster prevention and response authority in the centralgovernment, as well as work permit.
The above-mentioned letter of application shall include name, location, and telephone of the organization, as well as name, age, occupation, address, telephone, special skills or knowledge of the principal of the organization.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The professional training mentioned in (2) of the above-said Article 2 must be held by the related disaster
preventionand response authorities or other entrusted departments, institutions, organizations, or schools that have disaster 
rescue-related specialties, pursuant to relevant prescriptions.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[For a civil voluntary organization assisting in disaster prevention and response who works solely in a county
(city),application shall be submitted to the local fire department and then transferred by the department to the Ministry. As for 
those who work in two or more counties (cities), applications shall be directly submitted to the Ministry for authentication.
In order to handle the above-mentioned authentication, the Ministry shall associate with the central regulating department of 
disaster prevention and relief as well as scholars and experts to organize an examination group to perform examinations.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[After a civil voluntary organization passes the authentication, the Ministry will grant it a certificate.
The period of validity of the above-mentioned certificate is two years. After the period expires, application shall be submitted 
again for re-authentication.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[If alteration of the members of an authenticated civil voluntary organization occurs, a new list of
organizationmembers shall be submitted to the original registration department for examination. In case of new members 
added, the qualified certificates of professional training related to disaster rescue shall be enclosed within the list.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Each authenticated civil voluntary organization shall, by the end of October every year, send the work plan of the
nextyear to the original registration department for approval, and by the end of February every year, report the work 
achievements of the last year for examination.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Each authenticated civil voluntary organization shall accept supervision and evaluation from the Ministry and theoriginal registration department.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The authentication certificate will be cancelled where the qualified professional training certificate of any member
ofa civil voluntary organization is proved to be false.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 10</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Authentication certificate will be abolished on occurrence of any of the following:
(1)The organization has less than 20 members.
(2)The organization disobeys the authority’s command and supervision, or its action exceeds the authorizedworking range, 
thus encumbering the process of disaster rescue and resulting in harmful effects.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 11</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Any civil voluntary organization whose authentication is cancelled or abolished can’t re-apply authenticationwithin 6 months since the date of cancellation or abolishment.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 12</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Any civil voluntary organization that have not been authenticated to be qualified can’t participate or assist indisaster rescue tasks.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 13</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This Method shall take effect on the date it is promulgated.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
