<法規>
<法規性質>法律</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Organization Act of Overseas Community Affairs Council, ROC (Taiwan)</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>僑務委員會組織法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawContent.aspx?PCODE=E0000005</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20111114</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated on December 07, 1931
2.Amended on August 13, 1932
3.Amended on Novenber 05, 1936
4.Amended on July 16, 1947
5.Amended on September 27, 1947
6.Amended on August 15, 1972
7.Amended on December 21, 1981
8.Amended on January 21, 1998
9.Amended on Novenber 30, 2005
10.Amended on Novenber 14, 2011]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Executive Yuan shall establish Overseas Community Affairs Council, ROC (Taiwan) (hereinafter referred to as “OCAC”) to administer all affairs related to overseas Chinese.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[OCAC shall be in charge of the following matters:
1. Planning and handling of overseas Chinese educational development and economic activities; assistance and contact with overseas Chinese groups.
2. Handling all projects related to overseas Chinese groups and overseas Chinese youth; provide counseling and liaison services.
3. Certification services and protection of rights for overseas Chinese.
4. Collecting and reporting information related to overseas Chinese affairs.
5. Handling of all cases related to overseas Chinese.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[OCAC shall have one Minister (political appointment); two Vice Ministers equivalent to senior grade 14.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[OCAC shall appoint 90 to 180 members for a three-year term without pay.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[OCAC shall have one Secretary-General at senior grade 12.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[If necessary, OCAC may dispatch its staff members and those of its subordinate agencies based on the Organization Act of Diplomatic Missions of the Republic of China (Taiwan).
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The ranks, grades and number of positions of OCAC staff are governed by a separate Personnel Establishment Table.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The date that this act enters into effect shall be announced by the Executive Yuan.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
