<法規>
<法規性質>法律</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Organization Act of the All-out Defense Mobilization Agency of the Ministry of National Defense</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>國防部全民防衛動員署組織法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=F0000093</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20210609</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Full text of 9 articles promulgated per Presidential Order No. Hua-Zong-Yi-Yi-Zi-11000052931 dated June 9, 2021; the effective date shall be decided by decree of the Executive Yuan]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Ministry of National Defense shall establish an All-out Defense Mobilization Agency (hereafter referred to as the “Agency”) for the purposes of undertaking military mobilization and assisting the Executive Yuan and its subordinate agencies (institutions) as well as municipal and county (city) governments in all-out defense mobilization affairs.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Agency shall be in charge of the following affairs:
1.Planning, supervising and executing military mobilization policies.
2.Assisting the Executive Yuan and its subordinate agencies (institutions) as well as municipal and county (city) governments in planning, supervising and executing all-out defense mobilization policies.
3.Planning, supervising and executing military mobilization and assisting Executive Yuan and its subordinateagencies (institutions) as well as municipal and county (city) governments in planning, supervising and executing all-out defense mobilization drills.
4.Planning and executing the arrangement, recruitment, drafting, training and mobilization readiness of reserve forces.
5.Planning and executing policies for management and service of military reserves, and mobilization management information system.
6.Planning and supervising mobilization policies on military supplies, military transportation, and military industry; assisting the Executive Yuan and its subordinate agencies (institutions) as well as municipal and county (city) governments in planning and executing related affairs.
7.Other affairs relating to the readiness of all-out defense mobilization and military mobilization.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Agency may set up divisions and offices under it to undertake the affairs specified in the preceding article, and set up sections under divisions and offices, if necessary.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Agency shall have a director-general whose rank shall be comparable to 14th-grade senior rank civil servant or lieutenant general; a deputy director-general who acts concurrently as chief executive officer and whose rank shall be comparable to 13th-grade senior rank civil servant; and two deputy directors-general with one of them ranking as 12th-grade senior rank civil servant and the other one ranking as major general.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Agency may establish institutions and troops for executing all-out defense and military mobilization operational affairs; the organizations of such institutions and troops shall be structured in accordance with the table of organization and equipment.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The ranks, grades and quota for each position title under the Agency shall be structured in accordance with the table of organization.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[For the sake of executing all-out defense mobilization operations, the Agency may submit to the Executive Yuan for approval of having agencies (institutions) subordinate to the Executive Yuan and municipal and county (city) governments to dispatch personnel to station at the Agency.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[For the needs of operations, the Agency may recruit military contract employees.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The effective date of this Act shall be decided by decree of the Executive Yuan.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
