<法規>
<法規性質>法律</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Organization Act of Veterans Affairs Council</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>國軍退除役官兵輔導委員會組織法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=F0000081</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20130703</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated on July 3, 2013 and enforced on November 1, 2013]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[In order to administer the overall ROC veterans affairs, Veterans Affairs Council(VAC) is established under the auspices of the Executive Yuan.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[VAC is in charge of the following affairs:
1.Those related to veterans assistance policy and planning.
2.Those related to veterans services and emergency assistance.
3.Those related to veterans homecare, nursing care, and benefits.
4.Those related to veterans educational assistance, employment assistance, and vocational training.
5.Those related to veterans medical care, healthcare, and long-term care.
6.Those related to veterans retirement payment.
7.The supervision, coordination and implementation of matters related to veterans services, homecare, vocational training, medical care, joint venture enterprises, labor service, and veterans farms of all VAC’s affiliated units.
8.All other matters related to veterans assistance.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[VAC shall have one minister, a special political appointee, in charge Of overall council’s affairs, and three deputy ministers. Two of the three deputy ministers are senior level 14 political appointees, and the other one is senior level 14 executive deputy minister.
The VAC shall have 9-13 councilors, selected and appointed by Premier Of the Executive Yuan.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[VAC shall have a senior level 12 secretary general.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The ranks and pay grades of all VAC officials and the number of employees shall be listed in VAC’s Table of Organization.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This Act shall come into force on the date of the Executive Yuan's order.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
