<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Organization Regulations of the Combined Logistics School</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>聯合後勤學校組織規程</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawContent.aspx?PCODE=F0000064</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20140604</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>廢</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.The Organization Regulations of the Combined Logistics School (hereinafter referred to as CLS) enacted in accordance with Paragraph 1of Article 19 of the Act Military Education, and was put into practice and promulgated by the Ministry of National Defense (hereinafter referred to as MND) on December 12, 2001. 
2.The Regulations was amended by the MND on October 10, 2004.
3.The Regulations was amended by the MND on February 16, 2007.
4.The Republic of China on June 4, 2014 the Ministry of Defense National Committee of the National People's Congress No. 1030000169,abolish the Organization Regulations of the Combined Logistics School.]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This Organization Regulations of the CLS is enacted in accordance with Paragraph 1 of Article 19 of the Act Military Education.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The CLS is subordinate to the ministry of The MND. The Combined Logistics Command (hereinafter referred to as CLC) could be authorized to act the founding of the school.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The main objectives of the CLS are to train armed forces officers and sergeants with logistics and maintenance specialties.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The pursuing further education plans designed in accordance with the features and policies of the CLS.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The CLS is departmentalized into Divisions, Centers and Offices, each of which being in charge of following items:
（1）Academic Section: in charge of enrolment, register, curriculum affairs, teaching materials, student status, and other academic affairs.
（2）Students' Affairs Section: in charge of psychological counseling, life counseling, health care, extracurricular activities guidance, patriotic education, counseling service, military discipline inspection, military security.
（3）General Affairs Section: in charge of personnel, logistics, construction, and other general affairs.
（4）Information Library Center: in charge of the collection of teaching research resources, construction of the informational environment of logistic school, training of broadcast of system, information security and providing information service.
（5）Finance Office: in charge of budgeting, general accounting, and statistics.
（6）Operation Research and Development Office: in charge of the publishing of Combined logistics manning and equipping, doctrines, material research and development, military academic journals, and other operational research developments.
The CLS could apply the organizational change or extension to the MND for the needs of teaching and research.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The CLS has Supply-Transport Branch, Medical-Education Branch, Instructor-General's Office, Training and Practical Support Factory, Student Squadron, Logistics Training Inspect Center, and Headquarter Company. The Branches could set Student Squadron, Motor Vehicle Training Support Company, and Service Group. The Branches may further set up Bureau and Institution to meet executive needs.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The CLS has one principal, Major General, in charge of general school affairs；one Executive Director and one Director of Political Warfare, both of who are Colonel , assisting the principal in dealing with school affairs.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The CLS has Director, Executive Director, Commander, Instructor-General, Brigade Commander, Division Director, Vise Division Director, Section Director, Section Deputy Director, Chief Counselor, Deputy Commander, Instructor-Director, Chief, Factory Director, Group Commander, Instructor, Staff, Deputy Factory Director, Institution Chairman, Company Commander, Squadron Commander, Medical Officer, Captain, Deputy Company Commander, Platoon Leader, and Element Leader.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The official rank and prescribed number of personnel listed in the Regulation is specified by the Table of Organization.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 10</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Military employees will ont add from the Regulations were amended on February 16.2007；and those whom have been employed,could be employed continually till leaving jobs.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 11</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Regulations will take effect on the date decided by the MND.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
