<法規>
<法規性質>法律</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Organization Act of the Medical Affairs Bureau of the Ministry of National Defense</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>國防部軍醫局組織法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=F0000076</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20121212</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated by the Presidential Decree on Dercember 12 , 2012.]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Under the command of the Ministry of National Defense, the Medical Affairs Bureau (hereafter referred to as the Bureau) is to execute medical affairs and sanitary services for the armed forces.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Bureau is responsible for the following affairs:
1.Planning of military medical policies and institutions.
2.Management of training, evaluation, and careers of military medical personnel.
3.Operation, manpower and rewarding as well as operating and managing affairs of military hospitals.
4.Planning, and supervising military medical treatment, health care and research development.
5.Planning, and supervising military medical logistics and medical supplies.
6.Planning and supervising medical affairs and sanitary services.
7.Other military medical affairs.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Bureau is in charge of the precedent items listed in Article 2 and, based on service needs, has the authority to assign the implementation of them to separate divisions.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Bureau is headed by one director general, whose position shall be 13th grade of Selected Appointment Rank, or at the rank of Lieutenant General, one Deputy Director General, whose position shall be 12th grade of Selected Appointment Rank, or at the rank of a major general.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Bureau may establish medical organs and professional organs to execute medical affairs and sanitary services, and the organization of the foresaid organs shall be described in Grouping and Equipment Table.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[All the positions, ranks and quantity of members in the Bureau will be structured in accordance with the Organization Table.
In each department, one of the directors or deputy directors shall be attained by a qualified physician in accordance with the Medical Personnel Regulation when necessary.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[In order to fulfill its mission, the Bureau may hire civilian employees.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The effective date of this Act shall be determined by the Executive Yuan.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
