<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Organization Regulation for the Army Headquarters of the Ministry of National Defense</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>國防部陸軍司令部組織規程</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawContent.aspx?PCODE=F0000041</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20121230</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Article 17 enacted and promulgated  by Ministry of National Defense with Gang─ sher order 1150 on 4,13,1991
2.Article 3,8,12,13,14 and 15 amended and  promulgated by Ministry of National  Defense with Dwao─Gue order 7145 on 8,5,1993
3.Article 11 amended and promulgated by Ministry of National Defense with  Dwao─Gue order 890017675 on  30,12,2000
4.Article 3,4,7 and 11 amended and promulgated by Ministry of National  Defense with Zhi─Kai order  0930000511 on 5,18,2004
5.Article 7 amended and promulgated by  Ministry of National Defense with Zhi─Chuang order 0950000130 on  2,15,2006. The regulations will be put into practice from the promulgation of date
6.Amended and promulgated by the Ministry of National Defense o Dec.30,2012,on the orders of Girzhi-Lossix1010001127.The Regulations,totally 8 articles,shall be put into force from the date of Jan,1,2013.]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Ministry of National Defense has under it the Army Command Headquarters (hereinafter referred to as the Army HQ) that is in charge of army military affairs.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Army HQ is in charge of army military affairs which are as follows:
1. Planning, supervising, and implementing of political warfare.
2. Planning, supervising, and implementing of inspection and legal affairs. 
3. Planning, supervising, and implementing of the manpower management and service, general administrations, history compilation and translation, and education.
4. Planning, supervising, and implementing of the military intelligence distribution and application.
5. Planning, supervising, and implementing of the operational readiness, troops training, doctrine development and application, and HA/DR assistance.
6. Planning, supervising, and implementing of the reserve component mobilization affairs.
7. Coordinating, controlling, and supervising of the logistic affairs; planning, supervising, and implementing of the materials management, general purpose and services’ logistic readiness.
8. Planning, supervising, and implementing of the military build-up policies and weapon systems. 
9. Planning, supervising, and implementing of the affairs concerned with information, communication, and electronics corps, chemical corps, and engineer corps. 
10. Planning, supervising, and implementing of other affairs.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Army HQ may establish agencies for commanding and managing the affairs the preceding article mandates, and may establish sub-agencies for transacting businesses according to the requirement of practices.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Army HQ, for the purposes of implementing army operations and military buildup and readiness, may establish agencies for command, training, professional, execution, support, military research and development, and troops；The structure of each agency and troops will be stipulated in Table of Organization and Equipment (TOE).
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Army HQ has one commanding general, at the rank of general, two deputy commanding generals, both at the rank of lieutenant general, and one chief of staff, also at the rank of lieutenant general.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Each position in the Army HQ, including its rank and amount of personnel, will be stipulated in TOE.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Army HQ, when deeming it necessary, may employ civilian staff.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Regulations shall be put into force from the date of Jan, 1, 2013.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
