<法規>
<法規性質>法律</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Organization Act of the Comptroller Bureau of the Ministry of National Defense</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>國防部主計局組織條例</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawContent.aspx?PCODE=F0000067</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20140129</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>廢</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated on February 06, 2002
2.On January 29, 2014, the President of the People 's Republic of China, No. 10300011901，abolish the regulations of the Ministry of Defense.]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This Regulation is based on the 9th Article of the Organization Law of the Ministry of the National Defense.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Under the command of Minister of Ministry of National Defense, the Comptroller Bureau of The Department of Defense (hereafter refers to as the Bureau) administers in charge of budget accounting and statistics of the military of the ROC.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Bureau is responsible for the following the affairs:  
Subparagraph 1 
Policy-making of the comptroller ship.
Subparagraph 2 
Planning, supervising, control, execution as well as research and development of the business of comptroller ship.
Subparagraph 3 
Financial management and budgeting of the fiscal year.
Subparagraph 4  
Management of the （special funds）military revolving funds.
Subparagraph 5  
Electronic data processing practice within the scope of comptrollership.
Subparagraph 6  
Training， personel and management of human resources of the comptrollers.
Subparagraph 7
Supervising all units under its comma.
Subparagraph 8
Other affairs not mentioned above.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Bureau is consists the following units respectively in charge of the precedent items listed in Article 3 ，and may regard the service needs to divide them into separate divisions to handle matters:
Subparagraph 1
Division of Policy-making and Planning.
Subparagraph 2
Division of Budgeting.
Subparagraph 3
Division of Financial Management and Accounting.
Subparagraph 4
Division of Interior Auditing.
Subparagraph 5
Division of military revolving fund.
Subparagraph 6
Division of Statistics.
Subparagraph 7
Electronic Data Processing Center.
According to the specified number of personnel in this Regulation, the ministry of national Defense may regard the military needs to make adjustment of organization of  the Bureau.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[In order to fulfill the military services of budget accounting and statistics, the bureau may set up the specialized and executive agencies, whose organizations will be structured in accordance with the table of organization and equipment.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Bureau is headed by a lieutenant general (the Comptroller General of MND). Two assistant Comptroller Generals are under its command. Both are major generals.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Either a major general or a colonel (Director) heads each Department. The posts under the Director are：Manager(1), Vice Directors & Vice Managers (13-19) and the heads of the Divisions (2-4), all are colonels; Staff Director (1), full or lieutenant colonel; staff officers (165-255), are lieutenant colonels or majors, excluding the post of 30-56 staff officers could be colonels.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Bureau establishes the Accounting Office, headed by a full colonel (Manager), legally in charge of the Bureau and its subordinates' budget accounting and statistics affairs; the remaining necessary staffs are dispatched according to the specified number of personnel in this Regulation.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The staffing of the comptrollers in all echelons is not only supervised by his immediate senior officers, but also by the Comptroller General of MND.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 10</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[In order to fulfill its mission, the Bureau may employ 5-7 civilian consultants and hire the employees.
The above consultants are honorary posts, but may be subsidized the traffic allowance.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 11</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Bureau has to make the bylaw of this  Regulation and submits it to the MND level for approval.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 12</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The execution date of this Regulation has to be Officialized by Executive Yuan.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
