<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Organization Regulations of the Chung Cheng Armed Forces Preparatory School</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>中正國防幹部預備學校組織規程</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=F0000047</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20070611</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated on December 28, 2001
2.Amended on June 11, 2007]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Organization Regulations of the Chung Cheng Armed forces Preparatory School (hereinafter referred to as the Regulations) is drafted according to Section 2, Article 19 of the Military Education Act.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Chung Cheng Armed Forces Preparatory School (hereinafter referred to as the School) is subordinate to the ministry of National Defense, stipulates to the relevant education laws, and is under the direction of the Ministry of Education.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The purpose of this School is to provide the Senior High School and Preparatory School education for those who will eventually become the cadres of the Army, Navy, Air Force, and the Political Warfare Academy.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The School provides basic education according to special characteristics and developmental prospects.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The School has set up the following units to be responsible for its respective affairs:
1. Academic Affairs Division: responsible for recruitment, registration, curriculum, teaching material and equipment, admission and degree and other affairs related to education.
2. Student Affairs Division: responsible for students’ psychological counseling, life guidance, healthcare, extra-curriculum, patriotic education, counseling service, military discipline and control, and military security, etc.
3. General Affairs Division: responsible for documents, personnel, logistics, construction and other related affairs.
4. Information and Library Center: responsible for the collection of education and research material and for providing information services.
5. Comptroller Office: responsible for annual budget, accounting and statistic affairs.
The School may report to and be approved by the Ministry of National Defense to adjust and reestablish other units for teaching and research requirements.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The School has set up Cadet Battalions and the School Service Company.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The School has set one Commandant whose position shall be Major General in charge of overall school affairs; one Executive Director and one Director for the Political Warfare Department whose positions shall be colonels to assist the Commandant in handling School affairs respectively.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The School has set up Directors and Deputy Directors for divisions, Battalion Commanders, Section Chiefs, Staff, Instructors, Chief Counselor, Company Commanders and Deputy Commanders, Military Medical Doctors, Platoon Leaders, and Group Leaders.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Teachers shall be appointed on a full-time basis, but under special circumstances, part-time teachers could be appointed. The employment of teachers defined above is subject to the Teachers’ Law.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 10</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The above-mentioned positions in the Regulations whose ranks and total numbers shall be regulated by another organization list.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 11</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The School shall establish various committees based on its need to comply with Senior High School Law.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 12</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Committees of various purposes can be organized for the needs of this School and the numbers of their staff are listed in other articles in the Regulations.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 13</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The School should not employ any staff after the amended regulations dated on June 11, 2007. The employed staff will be continuously employed until they leave their positions.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 14</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Regulations will take effect on the date of their proclamation.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
