<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Organization Regulations for the Army Chemicals School</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>陸軍化學兵學校組織規程</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=F0000063</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20140604</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>廢</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.2001.12.12 stipulate article 1-11.
2.2007.05.22 amendment article 2,5,6,8,10,preparation of tables.
3.2014.06.04 abolished.]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This Regulation is prescribed in accordance with Military Education Regulation, the Nineteenth Clause, Rule One.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Subordinated to the Ministry of National Defense（MND）,the Army Chemical School（ACS） is charged by General Headquarter of the Army.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The objective of the ACCS is to train Army officer and sergeant's chemical corps, and maintenance specialty.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The further education of the School is designed in accordance with school's features and policies.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[For conducting respective missions, the ACS may establish divisions, centers and offices as below:
（1）Education Affairs Office takes charge of recruiting new students, students’ registration, books, materials and equipments.
（2）Student Affairs Office is responsible for students' service and safety, physical and mental health, and to counsel the students’ life and guidance of extracurricular activities.
（3）General Administration Office manages the official documents, personnel matters, supporting logistics, construction of buildings, and other general affairs.
（4）Library & Information Center conducts the collection of teaching and research materials, and the supplies of information
（5）Comptroller Office manages the accounting department, financial and statistics affairs.
（6）Operations Research & Development Office takes charge of the organization and equipments of Army Chemical Troops, and to conduct the military regulations, doctrines, research and development of equipments, and the publication of the periodical, etc.
（7）The school may on the authority of MND, establish or adjust the divisions for the need of teaching and research.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The ACS may set up Instructors’ Departments, Battalion of Trainee, Chemical Troops Training & Eveluation Center(CTT&EC), and HQ Company.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The ACCS has one principal, Major General, in charge of general school affairs; one Executive Director and one Director of Political Warfare, both of which are Colonel, assisting the principal in dealing with school affairs.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The ACS may organize the positions：Commander of CTT&EC, Chiefs, Directors, Commander of Trainee Battalion, Deputy Commander, Deputy Directors, Chief  Instructors, Staff Officers, Instructors, Company Commander, Chief Counselor in Company, Executive Officers in Company, Medical Officers and Platoon Leaders.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The official rank and prescribed number of personnel listed in the Regulation is specified by the Table of Organization.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 10</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[After The regulations amended and promulgated on May 22nd, 2007, the ACS stops to employ more civilian personnel. Those who were already employed could work till they quit.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 11</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Regulation shall be implemented upon officializtion.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
