<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>The Military Police School (MPS) Organization Regulations</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>憲兵學校組織規程</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawContent.aspx?PCODE=F0000056</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20140604</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>廢</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated by the President on July 18, 2001
2.Amended on August 17, 2004
3.Amended on December 29, 2006
4.Amended on March 8, 2013
5.On June 4, 2014, the Ministry of National Defense of the Ministry of National Defense of the People's Republic of China issued the order No. 1030000169 Cloth abolished]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This Regulation shall be governed by the provisions of Paragraph 1 of Article 19 of the Military Education Ordinance.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Gendarmerie (hereinafter referred to as the school) under the Ministry of Defense, may appoint the Ministry of Defense gendarmerie command.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The school to cultivate gendarmerie professional and technical officers, noncommissioned officers for the purpose.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The school according to the school characteristics and development direction, for further education.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The school has the following places, centers, rooms, respectively, the following matters, and sub-group services:
1.Academic Affairs Office: Services such as recruitment, registration, schooling, teaching materials, student status and other educational affairs.
2.Student service: psychological counseling, life counseling, health care, extracurricular activities , Patriotic education, counseling services, military discipline monitoring, military security and other matters.
3.General Affairs Office: Mastering documents, personnel, logistics, engineering construction and other general affairs matters.
4.Information Book Center: the overall development of information systems  and personnel education and training, teaching research. The collection of information and the provision of information services.
5.Combat research and development office: control gendarmerie equipment, standards, tactical tactics, service technology, professional. Equipment research and development, academic quarterly issue and other research and development issues.
6.Statistics office: the management of age, accounting and statistics and other matters.
7.Chief instructor office: to master the military training, physical fitness skills planning and training implementation.
The school must report to the Department of Defense for approval, adjustment or other necessary units for the teaching and research needs.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The school set up a student staff team, service even.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The school principal of a school, colonel, comprehensive school; education long, political warhead of the one, are Colonel, To help principals to deal with school.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[(Delete)
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The rank and post of the titles listed in this Code shall be formulated separately.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 10</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Rules shall not be used for general employment after the amendment of December 29 of the Republic of China on December 29 2006 ,Personnel; have been users, have to continue to hire until the date of stay.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 11</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This procedure is implemented on the date of issue.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
