<法規>
<法規性質>法律</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Armed Forces Uniforms Act</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>陸海空軍服制條例</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=F0060007</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20140129</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Enacted and promulgated on November Seventh, 2007.
2.Full text (11 articles) has been amended on 29 January 2014 by Presidential Decree Hua- tzung-1 Yi Tzu No. 10300011821 and enforced from the date of promulgation.]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Armed Forces Uniforms are regulated by this Act.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Paragraph 1
For active duty servicemen, there are three kinds of uniforms as follows:
Subparagraph 1
Dress Uniforms; the fashion shall be correspondent to Attached Photo 1.
Subparagraph 2
Garrison Service Uniforms; the fashion shall be correspondent to Attached Photo 2.
Subparagraph 3
Field Service Uniforms; the fashion shall be promulgated by the Ministry of National Defense.
Paragraph 2
Active duty servicemen wearing Dress Uniforms and Garrison Service Uniforms shall wear cockades, cap tassels, and rank insignias; the fashion shall be correspondent to Attached Photo 3. Active duty servicemen wearing Field Service Uniforms shall wear rank insignias; the fashion shall be promulgated by the Ministry of National Defense.
Paragraph 3
The Ministry of National Defense is empowered to promulgate the subject, region, and fashion of other insignias which shall be worn.
Paragraph 4
The uniforms, cockades, cap tassels, and rank insignias of active duty servicemen shall be distinguished among Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and the Military Police.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Wearing Dress Uniforms on the following occasions:
Subparagraph 1
a formal visit to the President or Head of State of our Allies;
Subparagraph 2
attending a grand ceremony or banquet of our own or foreign countries’;
Subparagraph 3
a formal visit or a repaying visit to officials and officers of our Allies;
Subparagraph 4
attending important ceremonies or other formal occasions;
Subparagraph 5
ordinary working days or outing.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Wearing Garrison Service Uniforms on the following occasions:
Subparagraph 1
attending all kinds of military ceremonies;
Subparagraph 2
ordinary working days or outing.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Wearing Field Service Uniforms on the following occasions:
Subparagraph 1
fighting;
Subparagraph 2
manoeuvres or trainings;
Subparagraph 3
operating inside or outside the camp;
Subparagraph 4
ordinary working days or outing.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[When wearing uniforms, active duty servicemen are required to wear those awarding with decorations, badges, and medals according to relative regulations.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Non-active duty servicemen are entitled to wear the uniforms stipulated by this Act on the following occasions:
Subparagraph 1
servicemen retired or out of commission being invited by the Ministry of National Defense to attend ceremonies;
Subparagraph 2
reservists being promoted;
Subparagraph 3
other circumstances approved by the Ministry of National Defense.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The fashion of fatigue dresses, sweat suits, raincoats, jackets, sweaters, outer coats, maternity clothes, caps, and the clothes for particular missions or comity of nations are promulgated by the Ministry of National Defense and its sub-division.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Paragraph 1
The supply and distribution of uniforms, cockades, cap tassels, rank insignias, other emblems, clothes, underwear, underpants, army socks, army boots for active duty servicemen are stipulated by the Ministry of National Defense; those who are appointed to other agencies may be supplied and distributed via entrusting by the Ministry of National Defense.
Paragraph 2
the provisions of preceding paragraph shall apply mutatis mutandis to the supply and distribution for cadets.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 10</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The circumstances of active duty servicemen to wear uniforms, the switching time for seasonal uniforms, and the occasions Article 3 to Article 5 applied to are promulgated by the Ministry of National Defense.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 11</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This Act will be put into practice from the date of promulgation.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
