<法規>
<法規性質>法律</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>All-Out Defense Education Act</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>全民國防教育法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawContent.aspx?PCODE=F0080014</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20050202</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Enacted and promulgated according to Zung Tung Hua Yi Zi 09400014051on February 2, 2005; the Act shall be put into force one year after promulgation. ]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[In order to promote All-out defense education, advance national defense knowledge and awareness to defense our country of the public, complete national defense development, and to ensure national security, the Act was enacted.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The competency agency referred in the Act at the central level is Ministry of National Defense; at special municipalities, the county (city) level governments shall be the authority agencies. 
For matters governed by the Act and involved the authorities of various business competency agencies, the related business competency agencies shall be in charge.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Items below shall be administered by the Central competency agency:
Paragraph 1
Studies and enactment of rules and regulations and policies of All-out defense education.
Paragraph 2
Studies and development of research and development of All-out defense education.
Paragraph 3
Planning and evaluation of All-out defense education.
Paragraph 4
Subsidies and appraisal of national All-out educational work.
Paragraph 5
Trainings and vocational trainings of All-out defense educators .
Paragraph 6
Promotions and publicities of national wide national defense.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Items below shall be administered by the special municipality, county (city) competency agencies.
Paragraph 1
Planning, execution, and supervision of All-out defense educational work.
Paragraph 2
Subsidies and evaluation of All-out defense educational work carried out by schools and agencies (organizations) in their districts.
Paragraph 3
On-the-job educations of All-out defense educators.
Paragraph 4
Promotions and publicities of All-out defense education.
Paragraph 5
Other matters related to All-out defense education.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[All-out defense education referred to in the Act shall be conducted and the scope shall include:
Paragraph 1
School education.
Paragraph 2
On-the-job training s at governmental agencies (institutions).
Paragraph 3
Social education.
Paragraph 4
Protection, promotion, and education of national defense artifacts.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Executive Yuan shall establish All-out Defense Education Day and organize various relevant activities to enhance All-out defense education.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Schools at each level shall promote All-out defense education and according to actual needs, it shall be included in teaching curriculum and diverse teaching activities shall be organized.
The above course contents and implementation methods shall be regulated by agencies of Ministry of Education and the central competency agency.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Each governmental agency shall conduct All-out defense education of its personnel periodically according to the nature of work.
The above course contents and implementation methods shall be regulated by agencies of Directorate-General of Personnel Administrational Executive Yuan , Civil Service Protection and training Commission and the central competency agency.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The competency agencies and those of purposive businesses at each level shall produce films, video tapes, or literature for All-out defense education and through the broadcasting and publishing of the mass communication media to actively build and develop collective awareness of the general public towards national security and defense.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 10</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The competency agency at each level shall incorporate with drill exercises and plan educational activities or courses on national defense mobilizing exercises. In addition, during mobilized drill exercises, national defense education shall be conducted accordingly.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 11</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The competency agency at each level shall properly manage historical military sites, museums, memorial halls, and other cultural sites and enhance the collection, studies, interpretation, and protection works for meaningful artifacts of All-out defense education. 
The implementation methods in the previous paragraph shall be enacted by agencies of Council for Cultural Affairs, Ministry of Education, and the Central competency agency.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 12</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Leaves on business shall be given to personnel from the governmental agencies (institutions), schools, and business units that participate in All-out defense education.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 13</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The competency agencies and those of purposive businesses at each level shall allocate budgets to promote matters related to All-out defense education.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 14</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Proper encouragements shall be given to agencies (institutions), groups or individuals that have outstanding contributions to All-out defense educational work. 
The above encouragements shall be regulated by the central competency agency.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 15</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Act shall be put into force one year after promulgation.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
