<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>The Regulations for Departmental Affairs of the Central Bank of the Republic of China (Taiwan)</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>中央銀行處務規程</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=G0300050</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20110520</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1. Promulgated on May 20, 2011]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Central Bank of the Republic of China (Taiwan) (hereafter called the Bank) sets forth these Regulations to delineate the duties of administrative units within the organization.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The responsibilities of Counselors and Advisors are as follows:
1.Making suggestions on important work plans and projects.
2.Studying, improving and advising on regulations, systems and important operations.
3.Assisting important operations in administrative units.
4.Other matters as instructed.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Bank shall establish the following departments and offices:
1.Department of Banking, comprising seven sections.
2.Department of Issuing, comprising five sections.
3.Department of Foreign Exchange, comprising twelve sections.
4.Department of the Treasury, comprising six sections.
5.Department of Financial Inspection, comprising six sections.
6.Department of Economic Research, comprising seven sections.
7.Secretariat, comprising six sections.
8.Department of Accounting, comprising five sections.
9.Department of Information Management, comprising four sections.
10.Personnel Office, comprising two sections.
11.Ethics Office, comprising two sections.
12.Legal Affairs Office, comprising two sections.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Department of Banking shall be charged with the following duties:
1.Matters pertaining to discount window facilities.
2.Matters pertaining to the receipt and audit of reserve requirements.
3.Matters pertaining to open market operations.
4.Matters pertaining to the acceptance of re-deposits from financial institutions.
5.Auditing liquidity of financial institutions.
6.Implementing selective credit controls.
7.Regulating the posting and reporting of interest rates by financial institutions.
8.Administration of accommodations extended by banks to securities finance companies or securities firms.
9.Regulating the financial payment systems and conducting the operation pertaining to the transfer and settlement of interbank funds.
10.Other matters pertaining to monetary management.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Department of Issuing shall be charged with the following duties:
1.The design and issuance of national currency.
2.Custody, receipt and release of reserves against circulating currency, and uncirculating national currency in vaults.
3.Planning the printing and minting of national currency.
4.Announcement and recall of national currency withdrawn from circulation.
5.Collection, redemption and destruction of damaged or soiled national currency.
6.Supervision of the operation of the Central Engraving and Printing Plant and the Central Mint.
7.Seizure, nullification and destruction of counterfeited (or altered) national currency and the establishment of database on counterfeited (or altered) national currency cases.
8.Issuance of gold and silver coins and commemorative notes and coins.
9.Entrustment and supervision of matters associated with the issuance of the New Taiwan dollar.
10.Other matters pertaining to issuance of national currency.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Department of Foreign Exchange shall be charged with the following duties:
1.Management of foreign exchange reserves and planning of receipts and disbursements of foreign exchange.
2.Trading of foreign securities and foreign currencies.
3.Adjustment of demand and supply of foreign exchange and maintaining an orderly foreign exchange market.
4.Approval of, review, and supervision of foreign exchange business conducted by authorized banks and other enterprises.
5.Examination and approval of overseas remittance.
6.Approval, supervision, data collection, analysis, research, and reporting relating to international financial businesses of offshore banking units.
7.Communication with foreign correspondent banks, international financial institutions or organizations.
8.Calculation, compiling, analysis and reporting the receipts and payments of foreign exchange.
9.Supervision of private enterprises' foreign borrowings guaranteed by authorized banks, with reference to their repayment schedule.
10.Other matters pertaining to the foreign exchange business.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Department of the Treasury shall be charged with the following duties:
1.Management of the National Treasury's cash accounts.
2.Management of designated custodian cash accounts of the Central Governmental agencies.
3.Transfers and allocation of the National Treasury funds.
4.Safekeeping of the Central Governmental agencies’ securities and other asset documents.
5.Management of donations to the central government.
6.Delegating the National Treasury business and related supervision.
7.Management of affairs concerning central government bonds and treasury bills.
8.Delegating central government bonds and treasury bills business and related supervision.
9.Other matters pertaining to the management of the National Treasury.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Department of Financial Inspection shall be charged with the following duties:
1.Inspection or targeted examination of financial institutions' businesses activities related to the Bank's monetary, credit and foreign exchange policies and the payment systems and others under the Bank's authority.
2.Correction and guidance with respect to deficiencies identified during the inspection or examinations of financial institutions.
3.Enforcement for financial institutions violating the Bank's regulations.
4.Collection, review and analysis of data of financial institutions.
5.Collection, compilation, analysis and research of data regarding financial stability.
6.Financial stability assessment and the preparation and release of financial stability reports.
7.Conducting research on financial supervision and the coordination and cooperation with other financial authorities.
8.Other matters pertaining to financial examination.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Department of Economic Research shall be charged with the following duties:
1.Research of monetary policies and financial systems and related businesses.
2.Research of domestic and international economic and financial situations and collection and analysis of related data.
3.Compilation and analysis of financial statistics.
4.Compilation and analysis of balance of payments statistics.
5.Compilation and analysis of flow of funds statistics.
6.Forecasting and analysis of economic, financial and monetary conditions.
7.Preparation and publication of research papers and statistical reports.
8.Information exchange with international financial institutions or organizations.
9.Library management regarding economic and financial information and resources.
10.Other matters pertaining to economic research.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 10</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Secretariat shall be charged with the following duties:
1.Document and file management, collection and routing of all incoming and outgoing correspondence, and providing postal services.
2.Compilation and review of the Bank's documents, and management of Bank’s official seals.
3.Monitoring and follow-up of major affairs and important meetings as well as conferences of the Bank.
4.Maintaining liaison and communication with the parliament and the media.
5.Matters pertaining to property management, leasing, sale and insurance.
6.Administration of general affairs of the Bank.
7.Expense disbursements and receipts.
8.Management of worker safety and hygiene.
9.Supporting the Bank's employee benefits and welfare committee affairs.
10.Matters not managed by other offices or departments.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 11</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Department of Accounting shall be charged with the following duties:
1.Formulating the Bank's accounting system and handling accounting affairs.
2.Directing and supervising budgetary and accounting affairs of administrative units, branch offices, representative offices and subsidiary institutions.
3.Planning, drafting, and reviewing budgets, and allocating approved budgets.
4.Preparation of annual and semiannual financial reports.
5.Inspection of cash, bills, securities and assets.
6.Review of handling procedures for procurement and disposal of properties.
7.Execution of financial and operational audits and preparation of audit reports.
8.Preparation and analysis of the Bank's financial statements, and conducting related statistics work.
9.Proposing the selection, training, incentives and discipline, performance evaluation of the Bank's accounting personnel.
10.Other matters pertaining to accounting and audit.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 12</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Department of Information Management shall be charged with the following duties：
1.Formulating the goals and strategies for the Bank's overall information management and operations.
2.Overall planning, training, research and development of information management and operations.
3.Planning, developing and maintaining the application systems.
4.Establishing, maintaining and managing the environments of information operation and database.
5.Establishing, operating and managing the environments of computer and network.
6.Planning and handling information and communication security.
7.Exchange of information and coordination with other agencies.
8.Auditing the information management and operations of subsidiary institutions.
9.Other matters pertaining to information management.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 13</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Personnel Office shall be charged with the duty of the Bank's personnel management matters.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 14</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Ethics Office shall be charged with the duty of the Bank's ethics matters.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 15</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Legal Affairs Office shall be charged with the following duties:
1.Review of draft regulations.
2.Compilation and review of regulations.
3.Study and clarification of regulatory questions.
4.Drafting administrative appeal cases.
5.Handling disputes and litigation cases.
6.Proposal for Mainland-related affairs.
7.Study and analysis of contracts to be signed with domestic or foreign entities.
8.Other matters pertaining to legal system and administrative appeals.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 16</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Bank, in conducting its business, adopts a hierarchical delegation system that decisions are made in accordance with the established table of authority delegations.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 17</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulations shall become effective on April 29, 2011.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
