<法規>
<法規性質>法律</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>The Organic Act of Insurance Bureau, Financial Supervisory Commission</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>金融監督管理委員會保險局組織法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=G0300045</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20110629</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1. The full text (six articles) was promulgated by Presidential Order No. Hua-Zong-Yi-Yi-Zi-09700002291 dated January 9, 2008 and implemented on the same day of promulgation.
2. Amendments to the title and full text (six articles) were promulgated by Presidential Order No. Hua-Zong-Yi-Yi-Zi-10000136521 dated June 29, 2011; the date of implementation on July 1, 2012 was determined by the Executive Yuan by Order No. Yuan-Shou-Zong-Zi-1002261392 dated October 31, 2011.]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[(Purpose of Establishment)
The Financial Supervisory Commission establishes the Insurance Bureau (hereinafter referred to as the “Bureau”) for purposes of the supervision and regulation of the insurance market and insurance enterprises, and the formulation, planning and implementation of related policies and regulations.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[(Primary Duties)
The Bureau shall be in charge of the formulation, planning, and implementation of the following matters:
1. Supervision and regulation of insurance enterprises.
2. Review, supervision and regulation of insurance products.
3. Supervision and regulation of compulsory automobile liability insurance and residential earthquake insurance.
4. Supervision and regulation of reserves valuation, pricing, actuarial matters, and solvency of insurance enterprises.
5. Supervision and regulation of foundations and associations associated with the entities or businesses mentioned in Subparagraph 1 hereof.
6. Consumer protection in relation to the businesses of the Bureau.
7. Processing of examination reports on financial institutions in relation to the businesses of the Bureau and conducting necessary follow-up and assessments.
8. Supervision and regulation of other matters relating to insurance enterprises.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[(Appointment of Director-general and Deputy Director-generals)
The Bureau shall have one director general, who shall be a regularly appointed senior civil servant at occupational grade 13, and two deputy directors general, who shall be regularly appointed senior civil servants at occupational grade 12.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[(Appointment of Secretary General)
The Bureau shall have one chief secretary, who shall be a regularly appointed senior civil servant at occupational grade 11.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[(Prescription of Official Titles, Grade Levels and Quotas)
The civil service rank, occupational grade, and staffing quotas for each occupational title within the Bureau shall be separately specified in a personnel organization table.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[(Implementation Date)
The Executive Yuan shall prescribe by order the implementation date of this Act.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
