<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Hygiene Standards for Alcohol Products Containers</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>酒盛裝容器衛生標準</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=G0330031</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20131204</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Appendix：Table of Test Standards for Alcohol Products Containers.PDF]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000004616</下載網址>
  </檔案>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Appendix：Table of Test Standards for Alcohol Products Containers.doc]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000002182</下載網址>
  </檔案>
</附件>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1. The MOF and The DOH, pursuant to Tai-Tsai-Ku-Tzu No.09603508740 and Wei-Shu-Shih-Tzu No.0960404465, promulgated “Hygiene Standards for Alcohol Products Containers” on June 22ed, 2007.
2. The MOF and The DOH, pursuant to Tai-Tsai-Ku-Tzu No.10103618560 and Wei-Shu-Shih-Tzu No.1011300678, promulgated the amendment of Article 6 and Appendix of Article 5 of “Hygiene Standards for Alcohol Products Containers” on March 29th, 2012.
3. The MOF and The MOHW, pursuant to Tai-Tsai-Ku-Tzu No.10203758210 and Bu-Shou-Shih-Tzu No.1021351402, promulgated the amendment of Article 6 and Appendix of Article 5 of “Hygiene Standards for Alcohol Products Containers” on December 4th, 2013.]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Standards enacted herein are pursuant to Article 27, Paragraph 2 of The Tobacco and Alcohol Administration Act.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Standards is applicable to entire alcohol products containers, including the capping of covers, pads and stoppers.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The plastic alcohol products containers shall not be recycled for reuse.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The alcohol products containers shall not have any of the following circumstances; unacceptable discoloration, unusual odor and flavor, contamination, mould, contain foreign matter or fibre fall off.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The alcohol products containers shall meet requirements prescribed in the Table of Test Standards for Alcohol Products Containers (refer to the appendix)]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Standards shall be enforced on January 1, 2008.
The amended articles hereof shall come into effect as of the day of promulgation. However, the appendix of Article 5 of the Regulation amended on December 4, 2013 shall be implemented six months after the promulgation of this Act.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
