<法規>
<法規性質>法律</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>1973 Public Bond Issuance Act</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>中華民國六十二年度公債發行條例</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=G0360014</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>19740125</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Full text of 13 articles enacted and promulgated by the President on June 3, 1972.
2.Article 5 amended and promulgated by the President on January 25, 1974.]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Issuance of the 1973 Public Bond (hereinafter, "the Bond") shall be conducted in compliance with the provisions of this Act.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Bond will be issued for a limited total amount of NTD 2.6 billion, and will be issued at full face value in separate issues during the fiscal year 1973. The number of issues of the Bond and the amount and date of each issue shall be prescribed by the Executive Yuan.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The face value of the certificates of each issue of the Bond shall be respectively determined at the discretion of the Ministry of Finance.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The term for redemption of each issue of the Bond is 6 years. The payment of the principal shall begin 3 years from the issue date. The principal shall be paid once per year, and fully paid up in four installments of one-fourth of the principal each.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The interest rate of the certificates of each issue of the Bond shall be determined by the Executive Yuan. However, when an adjustment is made to the interest rate, the adjusted interest rate may not be lower than the one set at the time of issue.
The interest will be paid once every 6 months from the issue date.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The issuance of the certificates of each issue of the Bond will be in bearer form. However, a purchaser at the time of purchase may apply for certificates in registered form.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[If a certificate of any issue of the Bond is lost, stolen, or destroyed, it may not be reported lost nor payment stopped, nor shall Article 720, paragraph 1 (proviso), Article 725, and Article 727 of the Civil Code apply. However, if a lost, stolen, or destroyed certificate is in registered form, the holder may follow the loss reporting procedures of the original selling institution and apply for reissuance of the certificate.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Funds for redemption of the certificates of each issue of the Bond shall be put on allocation on an annual basis in the national general budget, and shall be appropriated to the managing bank in advance to be held on deposit in preparation for payment.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The issuance and sale and the principal and interest payments of the certificates of each issue of the Bond shall be managed by the Central Bank.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 10</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The certificates of any issue of the Bond may be freely traded, pledged, or used as guarantees in official dealings. However, in the case of a registered bond certificate, title transfer procedures must be carried out with the original selling institution before doing so.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 11</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Unmatured principal and interest coupons of certificates of any issue of the Bond may, no more than two months prior to the date of payment of the principal, be used at full face value to offset income tax, estate tax, custom duties, commodity tax, mining concession tax, and public real estate auction purchase prices.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 12</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Interest on the certificates of each issue of the Bond is exempt from income tax.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 13</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This Act shall come into force from the date of promulgation.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
