<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Regulations Governing Foreign Exchange Control</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>外匯管制辦法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawContent.aspx?PCODE=G0450008</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>19970702</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1. Promulgated on July 2, 1997]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulations are prescribed pursuant to the provision of Paragraph 2, Article 19-1 of Foreign Exchange Control Act 
(hereinafter referred as the Act).
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[In the event that any of the situations described in Paragraph 1, Article 19-1 of the Act arises, the Executive Yuan may decide 
and announce with a public notification to adopt any or all of the following measures for a specific time period:
1.Suspend or restrict trading of foreign exchange futures and forward contracts.
2.Suspend or restrict purchase of foreign exchange for overseas securities investment.
3.Suspend or restrict purchase of foreign exchange for payment of principals and interest of foreign loans.
4.Suspend or restrict purchase of foreign exchange for outward direct investment.
5.Suspend or restrict purchase of foreign exchange for other capital transactions.
6.Suspend or restrict outward remittance of foreign exchange deposits relevant to the capital transactions mentioned in 
Subparagraphs 1-5.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[In the event that any of the situations described in Paragraph 1, Article 19-1 of the Act arises, the Executive Yuan may also 
announce with a public notification, if deemed necessary, to adopt any or all of the following measures for a specific time 
period in conjunction with the measures(s) specified in the preceding article:
1.Order that all or part of foreign exchange incomes be sold to the Central Bank of China or any bank authorized by the Central 
Bank of China, or be deposited in any bank authorized by the Central Bank of China.
2.Request that payment of foreign exchange for the imported goods, service, income or gratuitous transfers shall not be made 
without approval. 
3.Close the foreign exchange market.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The measures taken as provided in Article 2 and Subparagraph 2, Article 3 shall be applicable to the companies, businesses, 
associations or individuals that make payment by foreign exchange or conduct foreign exchange transactions within the 
territory of the Republic of China.
The measures taken as provided in Subparagraph 1, Article 3 shall be applicable to the companies, businesses, associations or 
individuals within the territory of the Republic of China.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The term “a specified time period” depicted in Articles 2 and 3 refers to a period that shall not be longer than one month. 
The specified period stipulated pursuant to the provision of the preceding paragraph shall not be longer than 20 days, provided 
the Legislative Yuan is not in session. 
The measures adopted under Articles 2 and 3 and the period specified under this Article shall be reported to the Legislative 
Yuan for ratification within 10 days after such measure or period has been decided. In the event that the Legislative Yuan does 
not approve such measure or period, the decision made by the Executive Yuan shall be void immediately.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Intentional violation of the measures taken pursuant to these Regulations herein shall be punishable pursuant to the provision of 
Paragraph 1, Article 19-2 of the Act. Notwithstanding of the foregoing provision, the violator shall be exempt from 
punishment provided the Legislative Yuan disapproves of the subsequent recognition of the measures.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulations shall become effective on the date of promulgation.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
