<法規>
<法規性質>法律</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Organization Act of the Bureau of Audiovisual and Music Industry Development,Ministry of Culture</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>文化部影視及流行音樂產業局組織法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=H0000104</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20110629</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated by Presidential Decree Hua Zong (1)Yi No. 10000135141 on June 29, 2011]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Ministry of Culture shall establish the Bureau of Audiovisual and Music Industry Development (hereinafter referred to as the Bureau) to administer governmental affairs pertaining to the motion picture, radio, television, and popular music industries.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Bureau shall be charged with the following functions:
(1) Drafting and explanation of regulations concerning provision of assistance and guidance, as well as awards and incentives, to encourage development of the motion picture, radio, television, popular music, and associated popular-culture content industries.
(2) Conduct of surveys and research on trends relating to the motion picture, radio, television, popular music, and associated popular-culture content industries.
(3) Provision of assistance and guidance, as well as awards and incentives, to motion picture, radio, television, popular music, and associated popular-culture content enterprises, as well as to related individuals.
(4) Provision of assistance and guidance concerning the preservation and promotion of use and reuse of motion pictures, radio and television programs, and popular music recordings.
(5) Oversight of the operations of motion picture-related enterprises and of radio and television program content providers.
(6) Administration of the nation’s viewer rating system for motion pictures and video programs.
(7) Oversight of importation into Taiwan of motion pictures, radio and television programs, video programs, and popular music audio recordings from mainland China, Hong Kong and Macau.
(8) Promotion and implementation of international exchange programs concerning motion pictures, radio and television programs, and popular music recordings.
(9) Other affairs concerning assistance and guidance, awards and incentives, and oversight pertaining to the motion picture, radio, television, popular music, and associated popular-culture content industries.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Bureau staff shall include one director of Grade 13 Senior Civil Service rank, and two deputy directors of Grade 12 Senior Civil Service rank. If deemed necessary, one of the deputy directorships may be filled by a specially recruited person with the equivalent of professor-status qualification.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Bureau staff shall include one chief secretary of Grade 11 Senior Civil Service rank.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Other Bureau positions and personnel quotas shall otherwise be determined.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This Act shall come into force on the date ordered by the Executive Yuan.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
