<法規>
<法規性質>法律</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Organization Act of the National Taiwan Science Education Center</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>國立臺灣科學教育館組織條例</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=H0000016</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20140115</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>廢</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Announced Date 1962.06.26
2.Abolished Date 2014.01.15]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[NTSEC is subordinate to the Ministry of Education, handling Taiwan's Populace scientific education, guiding preliminary and junior schools and non-governmental education organizations, and promoting Taiwan's scientific education matters.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[NTSEC is divided into the following Divisions:
1. Experiment Division: Handles scientific experiments; laboratory tests; model and exhibit designs; teaching plans; etc.
2. Exhibition Division: Handles surveys of science education; exhibitions; collection, registration, and storage of exhibition articles; etc.
3. Promotion Division: Handles the promotion and demonstration of science education and matters related to guidance, contacts, exchanges, editing and publishing, etc.
4. General Affairs Division: Handles secretarial, cashier, and general affairs.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[NTSEC sets one Director, who is a selected appointment.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[NTSEC sets one Secretary,who is a recommended appointment, and four Division Chiefs. The General Affairs Division Chief is a recommended appointment; the rest of Division Chiefs can be either selected appointments or recommended appointments. In addition, NTSEC sets one to two Editors and two to three Counselors, both positions are recommended appointments; also three to five Technicians and two to three Clerks, both positions are designated appointments.
Those positions that are recommended and selected appointments, excepting the Secretary and the General Affairs Division Chief, in the preceding paragraph can be appointed by invitation, if necessary.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Director of NTSEC is responsible for the overall management of NTSEC affairs.The Secretary works under the Director in supervising documentation and handling assigned tasks. Respective Division Chiefs are responsible for overall management of the Divisions. The Editors, Counselors, Technicians and Clerks work under their Divisions in handling their job tasks accordingly.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[NTSEC shall have an Accounting Office,staffed by one chief accounting officer, whose position can be by either selected appointment or recommended appointment. The office of accounting shall administer budgeting, accounting, and statistics in accordance with the law.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[NTSEC shall have a Personnel Office, staffed by one personnel assistant, whose position is a designated appointment. The personnel assistant shall administer personnel matters.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[NTSEC can employ clerks (limited to3~5 persons) in view of business requirements.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[NTSEC, by necessity, should establish various Commissions upon the approvals of the Ministry of Education. Specialists are engaged as commissioners to assist in relevant affairs.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 10</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Bylaws of the Act shall be regulated by NTSEC and published upon approval of the Ministry of Education.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 11</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Act shall become effective from the date of promulgation.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
