<法規>
<法規性質>法律</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>The Organizational Act of the National Human Rights Museum</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>國家人權博物館組織法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=H0000170</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20171213</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated on December 13, 2017 and enforced on March 15,2018]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The National Human Rights Museum (hereinafter the “Museum”) is established by the Ministry of Culture for handling the research, collection, exhibition, education, promotion and other affairs in relation to human rights.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Museum shall be responsible for the following matters:
1. The collection, research, exhibition, education and promotion of human rights files, historical materials and documents during the authoritarian rule era.
2. The operation and management of the Green Island White Terror Memorial Park and the Jing Mei White Terror Memorial Park, and assistance in the preservation and revitalization of such sites of infamy during the authoritarian rule period.
3. Assist in the development of organizations working to realize and promote current human rights philosophies, as well as the exchange and cooperation between related museums in Taiwan and abroad.
4. Any other matter related to the history of human rights and cultural education, as well as the compilation and distribution of human rights publications.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Museum shall have one (1) Curator, whose position shall be of the twelfth to thirteenth grade senior level public official, and may be hired in the same manner as a principal or a professor of a junior college or higher if necessary; and one (1) Vice-Curator, whose position shall be of the eleventh grade senior level public official, and may be hired in the same manner as an assistant professor if necessary.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The official titles, grade levels and numbers of the staff at the Museum shall be separately set out by an organization chart.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The implementation date of this Act shall be prescribed by the Executive Yuan.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
