<法規>
<法規性質>法律</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Organization Act of National Museum of Marine Biology and Aquarium</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>國立海洋生物博物館組織法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawContent.aspx?PCODE=H0000119</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20120203</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Presidential Announcement Hua-Zong-Yi-Yi-Zi No. 10100022821 on 3rd February 2012]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[National Museum of Marine Biology and Aquarium (referred to as “The Museum”) was specially established by Ministry of Education for the marine scientific research, marine education, enhance the society on concept for conservation of marine resources and sustainable development.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Museum is responsible for the following:
1. Marine scientific research, international cooperation, and planning and publishing of  professional journal in marine biology
2. Planning and promoting marine science education, compiling and publishing marine science-related publications.
3. Planning, designing, specimen collections and marine organisms display in special exhibitions
4. Marine organism breeding, diseases treating, aquarium life support system operation and management, conservation of marine organism, and ecological research.
5. Operation, management and planning of the facilities and landscape in the museum.
6. Other marine organism related matters.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Museum has a president, rank from grade twelve to thirteen, or can be appointed similar to the qualification of president in independent college when necessary. A vice president, rank grade twelve, or can be appointed similar to professor in independent college when necessary.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[All other positions are listed separately.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The implementation date of this regulation is subjected to the command from Executive Yuan.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
