<法規>
<法規性質>法律</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Organization Act of National Chiang Kai-shek Memorial Hall</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>國立中正紀念堂管理處組織法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=H0000111</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20110629</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.The enacted act with all 5 articles was promulgated by Presidential Decree Hua-Zhong-1-Yi-Zi No. 10000135251 on June 29, 2011]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[National Chiang Kai-shek Memorial Hall (hereinafter referred to as the “the Hall”) is established by the Ministry of Culture for the purpose of collecting, preserving, and exhibiting former President Chiang Kai-shek’s cultural objects and arts promotion.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Hall shall be in charge of the following matters:
1. Collection, exhibition, preservation, maintenance and management of former President Chiang Kai-shek’s memorial cultural relics and historical data.
2. Research, promotion and international cooperation and exchange of former President Chiang Kai-shek’s historical records.
3. Study, communication and publishing of the arts.
4. Collection, exhibition, preservation, maintenance and management of art works.
5. Development, application and promotion of arts education and cultural and creative products.
6. Planning, maintenance and management of public facilities.
7. Other matters related to the commemoration and arts promotion of former President Chiang Kai-shek.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Hall shall have one Director, whose position shall be at the twelfth grade senior-level civil servant, and may be hired in the same manner as a principal or a professor of a junior college or higher if necessary; and one Deputy Director, whose position shall be at the eleventh grade senior-level civil servant, and may be hired in the same manner as an associate professor if necessary.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The ranks, grades and number of positions of the staff shall be governed by a separate organization chart.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The date that this Act enters into effect shall be gazetted by the Executive Yuan.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
