<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Ministry of Education’s Regulations Governing the Establishment of the National Professorship</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>教育部設置國家講座辦法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawContent.aspx?PCODE=H0020039</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20170323</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated on May 28, 1997
2.Amended on July 07, 2000
3.Amended on May 28, 2002
4.Amended on March 15, 2004
5.Amended on October 03, 2006
6.Amendment to all Article promulgated on January 8,2008.
7.Amended on 2013.03.18
8.Amendment to all Article promulgated on March 23,2017.]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[In order to provide incentives for academic development, enhance teaching and research standards, and encourage universities to develop their own individual strengths, the Ministry of Education (hereunder “ the Ministry ” ) establishes National Chair Professorships, in accordance with the provisions of Paragraph 2 of Article 17 of the University Act, and has formulated these Regulations.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Each National Chair Professorship shall be awarded to a full-time university professor who when recommended or selected is still actively engaged in ongoing academic research and teaching; held in high esteem; playing a leading role in shaping the direction of academic thought; and an exemplary role model in the academic community. In addition, the person shall satisfy one of the following requirements:
1. Be an academician of Academia Sinica;
2. Have received a Ministry of Education Academic Award; or
3. Have some outstanding achievement equivalent to being an Academia Sinica academician or to receiving an Ministry of Education Academic Award, in an academic or professional field in Taiwan or in another country.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Candidates who meet the eligibility requirements for a National Chair Professorship set out in the preceding article shall be recommended to the Ministry by universities after each candidate ’ s eligibility has first been officially reviewed by their university and approved by the Teacher Evaluation Committee. Each university may recommend up to three candidates in each field and the selection shall be made by the Ministry.
The Ministry ’ s procedures to select National Chair Professors are as follows:
1. A separate Review Board will be set up for each of five categories, based on different academic fields: the Humanities and Arts; Social Science; Mathematics and Natural Science; Biology and Medical and Agricultural Science; and Engineering and Applied Science. From nine to eleven prestigious scholars and experts shall be appointed to be members of each Review Board. The Standing Committee of the Ministry of Education Academic Review Committee (hereunder abbreviated to “ the Academic Review Committee ” )shall designate the convener of each Review Board.
2. The Review Boards shall conduct the first review, after undertaking a detailed evaluation of the academic research and teaching performance of each of the candidates and fully discussing and analyzing each.
3. Each Review Board shall forward all the material pertaining to each candidate who has passed the first review to three or four scholars or experts for further evaluation, after which it will conduct its second review. Each Review Board will then give their recommendations of candidates for a National Chair Professorship to the Standing Committee.
4. The Standing Committee shall review and discuss the results of each evaluation of each of the recommended candidates referred to in the preceding subparagraph, and then draw up and submit a list of candidates for a National Chair Professorship to a meeting of the Academic Review Committee to discuss and deliberate over.
5. The decisions shall be made with the agreement of two thirds of the members present, after discussion and deliberation at a meeting of the Academic Review Committee attended by at least half of its members. The National Chair Professors are selected based on the number of votes received by each of the candidates.
6. If any National Chair Professorship remains vacant after the selection procedure, a further ballot may be cast if a majority of the members present at the meeting of the Academic Review Committee members attended by at least half of its members agree. If a second ballot still fails to result in anyone receiving the number of votes stipulated in the preceding subparagraph, that National Chair Professorship shall remain vacant.
If a member of the Academic Review Committee is one of the current recommended candidates for a National Chair Professorship , that person shall withdraw from participating in all associated review and ballot-casting procedures.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[A maximum of thirteen National Chair Professorships shall be approved and awarded each year. The number available in each different disciplinary category is stipulated in Subparagraph 1 of Paragraph 2 of the preceding article. There is an annual quota of two such professorships in the Humanities and Arts category, two such professorships in the Social Sciences category , and three such professorships in each of the other disciplinary categories
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The term of each National Chair Professorship is three years. If it is necessary for a National Chair Professorship to be extended beyond the end of this term, the procedures set out in the provisions of Article 3 shall be conducted before the term ends.
Any person who has served two terms as a National Chair Professor shall become an honorary life-time National Chair Professor, without participating in any further recommendation or selection process.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[During the period when they are receiving the associated grant, National Chair Professors shall set up elective courses that students from other universities may enroll in, deliver lectures around the country, and publicize research and teaching achievements, in order to enhance the quality and general climate of academic research and teaching in Taiwan.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[In addition to the necessary resources provided by each university that recommended a particular National Chair Professorship, the Ministry shall provide NTD one million annually, which shall be allocated each year as follows:
1. A personal grant for each National Chair Professor: a maximum of NTD 500,000.
2. Teaching and research funds: for employing assistants, operating costs, transportation, and equipment.
Any person selected to be a National Chair Professor is not permitted to concurrently receive any other grant from the public affairs budget of any other government agency (organization).
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[If any of the following circumstances occur, a National Chair Professor ’ s personal grant shall be handled in accordance with the following provisions:
1. If a National Chair Professor does not continue working in a position as a full-time professor at their original university, their grant shall be terminated, beginning from the next semester. The university where the person is newly taking up an appointment may, however, continue providing similar administrative resources, and a similar research environment, and offer National Chair Professorship related courses, and if so, the person may continue to receive the grant.
2. If a National Chair Professor takes research leave, they shall report this to the Ministry which shall suspend their grant starting from the month immediately after the period of leave begins. Grant payments will resume when the period of research leave ends and will continue until the expiration of the term of the National Chair Professorship.
3. If a National Chair Professor is temporarily transferred in accordance with relevant regulations, for a period of less than two years, their grant shall be suspended starting from the month immediately following the temporary transfer. The grant payments will resume when the temporary transfer ends and will continue until the expiration of the term of the National Chair Professorship.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8-1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[If a National Chair Professor was involved in a case of violation ofacademic ethics before their selection that would have adversely affected the decision to select them, or if any material presented during their selection procedure contained false or incorrect details, the Ministry shall revoke their eligibility to be a National Chair Professor and require the personal grant money referred to in Article 7, Paragraph 1, Subparagraph 1 to be repaid.
If a National Chair Professor becomes involved in a case of violation of academic ethics after being appointed as a National Chair Professorship and the circumstances are serious, the Ministry shall deem that person ineligible to have been awarded a National C hair Professorship and shall cease paying the personal grant money that was paid in accordance with the provisions of Article 7, Paragraph 1, Subparagraph 1.
If the Ministry deems a person ineligible to hold a National Chair Professorship and revokes their eligibility during the period in which the associated grant is being paid, the Ministry shall cease its all ocation of the teaching and research funds referred in to Article 7, Paragraph 1, Subparagraph 2. If any such funds have been released for a particular use but have not yet been spent, the operations for which the funds were to be spent use shall be discontinued and the unspent funds must be returned.
The procedures for the deeming a person ineligible to be a National Chair Professor and for revocation of such eligibility referred to in Paragraph 1 and Paragraph 2 are as follows:
1. The Ministry shall organize an investigation team if a candidate is reported or found to be or have been involved in a case of the kind referred to in Paragraph 1 or Paragraph 2.
2. After the investigation team makes a professional judgement, it shall draw up and submit a written report of its investigation to a meeting of the Academic Review Committee for discussion and consideration.
3. The meeting of the Academic Review Committee that discusses and considers the findings shall be attended by at least half of its members and a decision motion will be passed if two thirds of the members present agree
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulations shall take effect on the date of promulgation.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
