<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Enforcement Rules of Degree Conferral Law</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>學位授予法施行細則</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawContent.aspx?PCODE=H0030011</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20110919</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Announced on August 28,1979
2.Amended on September 5,1983
3.Amended on November 13,1987
4.Amended on December 7,1990
5.Amendment to all Articles promulgated on April 17,1995
6.Amended on September 17,2004
7.Amended on September 19,2011]]></沿革內容>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Enforcement Rules are hereby enacted pursuant to Article 16 of the Degree Conferral Law (hereinafter called the “Law”).
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Each university shall determine the research fields for their master degree programs within the areas of fine arts, applied science or technology as referred to in Article 6, paragraph 2 of the Law.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[(Repealed)
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[A summary of the written report or technical report to be submitted in lieu of a master’s thesis as provided for in Article 6, Paragraph 2 of the Law.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[A thesis used for an acquired domestic or overseas degree shall not be used as the thesis required in Article 6, Paragraph 1 and Paragraph 2 and Article 7 or as the professional research paper required in Article 10 of the Law.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5-1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[After a university revokes a degree and issues a public notice to announce the invalidation of the previously issued degree in accordance with Article 7-2 of the Law, the university shall notify the student involved to return their degree and inform other colleges and relevant agencies (organizations) of such revocation and invalidation.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The professional research paper of a student who applies for the doctoral program in accordance with Article 10 of the Law shall be determined by each university.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[(Repealed)
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[(Repealed)
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The honorary doctoral degree conferral list to be reported to the Ministry of Education in accordance with Article 15 of the Law shall contain the name, gender, date of birth, nationality, educational background, professional experience of the person to whom the honorary degree is conferred as well as the title of the conferred degree.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 10</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Enforcement Rules shall enter into effect from the date of their promulgation.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
