<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Regulations for Selection of the Land, Establishment, Operation, Management, and Compensation and Rewards for Launch Center</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>發射場域土地之選址設置營運管理補償及回饋辦法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=H0160081</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20220118</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated on January 18, 2022]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <編章節>   Chapter 1 General Provisions</編章節>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulations are established in accordance with Article 12, paragraph 4 of the Space Development Act (the "Act").]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[For purpose of these Regulations, the management entity of launch center refers to the competent authority. In case where a juristic person is specifically mandated for operation and management of the national launch center under Article 4 of the Act, as appointed by the competent authority in accordance with Article 12, paragraph 2 of the Act, the management entity refers to the specially mandated juristic person.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <編章節>   Chapter 2 Selection of the Site, Acquisition of Land and Establishment of Launch Center</編章節>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[To establish the national launch center and handle matters of selection of the site of national launch center, the competent authority shall convene the review meetings to review the following:
1. Program of selection of the site of national launch center.
2. Evaluation of location of the national launch center.
3. Candidate site of the national launch center.
4. Other work relating to selection of the site.
Matters relating to convention, formation of, review and deliberation at the review meetings in the preceding paragraph shall be regulated by the competent authority separately.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The competent authority shall publish the candidate site and hold public hearings prior to selection of the site of the national launch center. The publication period shall be 30 days or more.
For public hearings in the preceding paragraph, a written notice shall be sent to the relevant government authorities/agencies, groups and interested parties 20 days before the hearing date, notifying them to attend the public hearing on the scheduled date, or express their opinions in writing to the competent authority within five days after the public hearing.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Selection of site of the national launch center shall comply with the applicable laws, and take into consideration industrial needs, and the potential impact of the launch center on the ecology, nature and environment, culture and landscape and residents in the area neighboring the center.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Acquisition of the land necessary for the national launch center shall comply with the applicable laws.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <編章節>   Chapter 3 Operation and Management of Launch Center</編章節>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Use of the launch center and related facilities and services is subject to payment of fees according to the fee rate standards
The fee rate standards in the preceding paragraph shall be established and announced by the competent authority in accordance with the Charges and Fees Act.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The management entity of launch center may announce and designate a certain area within the launch center as the controlled area, and establish operational regulations for restricted access to the controlled area and prohibitions and limitations within the controlled area.
To maintain the safety of the launch center and launch activities, the management entity of launch center shall request the related authorities to impose control over people, transportation, maritime and aviation traffic and other necessary control over activities in the neighboring area and other areas that may be impacted by launch activities.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The management entity of launch center shall establish a safety management organization for the launch center to be responsible for preparation and implementation of the safety plan for the launch center.
The launch center safety plan in the preceding paragraph shall cover the following matters:
1. Legal basis.
2. Operating unit and its mission.
3. Formation, powers and functionalities of the safety management organization of launch center, and related matters thereof.
4. Reporting and notification of safety matters for the launch center.
5. General condition of facilities at launch center.
6. Safety measures at launch center and matters for compliance
7. Emergency response plan.
8. Safety trainings at launch center.
9. Supervision and performance review.
10. Other related matters.
All public and private organizations and their staff operating at the launch center shall comply with the regulations of the launch center safety plan.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 10</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The management entity of launch center shall perform safety check on owners and users of launch vehicles or spacecraft prior to launch.
The management entity of launch center may perform security check on operating staff entering the controlled area of launch center, and may request related authorities to assist in investigation.
When entering the launch center to perform operation, owners or users of launch vehicles or spacecraft shall follow the instructions of the management entity of launch center, and help the management entity of launch center monitor people and transportation vehicles in action nearby to prevent unauthorized people and transportation vehicles from approaching launch vehicle/spacecraft.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 11</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The competent authority may send staff to audit, inspect, test or evaluate the safety measures for launch center adopted by operating unit at the launch center.
The operating units in the preceding paragraph include owners or users of launch vehicles or spacecraft, public and private agencies and the safety management organizations established by the management entity of launch center.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 12</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[All space security and safety information, except that without a confidential nature and so designated by the competent authority, shall be kept in confidentiality.
The space security and safety information in the preceding paragraph includes the following:
1. Launch center safety plan.
2. The operating safety plan for launch center adopted by the owners or users of launch vehicles or spacecraft using the launch center
3. Other information to be kept in confidentiality as determined by the competent authority.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <編章節>   Chapter 4 Compensation and Rewards</編章節>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 13</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[A land owner or user who has suffered losses due to establishment and use of a launch center or its facilities may submit an application and supporting documents such as evidence of losses to the management entity of the launch center for compensation.
In the event of multiple parties as land owners or users who have suffered losses in the preceding paragraph, the parties shall agree to have one of them to file an application on their behalf.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 14</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Where compensations are required as determined by the management entity of launch center, the value of compensations shall be negotiated between the applicant and the management entity of the launch center. If no such agreement is reached, after review of a compensation for loss of rights and interest review panel formed by the management entity of the launch center, the case shall be submitted to the competent authority for determination
Matters related to formation, makeup and deliberation of the review panel as in the preceding paragraph shall be separately regulated by the management entity of launch center and then reported to the competent authority for recordation.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 15</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The local government of the town/city/district where the launch center is located and where launch takes place may, based on the purpose of rewards, file an application every year to the management entity of the launch center to apply for rewards.
The management entity of launch center shall evaluate the maximum budget of rewards every year
The management entity of launch center shall establish a reward review team to handle reviews of budget of rewards.
Matters related to formation, makeup and deliberation of the review team as in the preceding paragraph shall be separately regulated by the management entity of launch center and then reported to the competent authority for recordation.
Rewards received by the local government of the town/city/district where the launch center is located and where launch takes place shall be included in the budget for utilization.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 16</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The rewards in the preceding paragraph may be used for the following purposes:
1. Activities relating to maintenance of health and wellbeing of residents.
2. Scholarships and financial aids.
3.  Social welfare.
4. Cultural activities
5. Funding for community-based construction projects
6. Activities that promote public interest.
7. Other purposes specified or approved by the competent authority.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 17</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The management entity of launch center shall prepare budgets for compensation and rewards.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 18</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulations shall come into force upon publication.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
