<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Precision Instrument Development Center, National Science Council, The Executive Yuan Tentative Memorandum of Organization</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>行政院國家科學委員會精密儀器發展中心暫行組織規程</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=H0160003</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20050302</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>廢</廢止註記>
<附件>
  <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000000940</下載網址>
  <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000004348</下載網址>
</附件>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1. Approved by the Executive Yuan under Letter No. 63-0690 dated Jan. 31, 1974.
2. Amended on August 9 , 1974
3. Amended on August 6 , 2001；Revision approved by the Executive Yuan under Letter No. 90-039187 dated Jun. 24, 2001
4. Abolished on March 2 , 2005]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[1.The Precision Instrument Development Center ("the Center") is set up by the National Science Council ("the Council") to promote scientific development in the nation and to support the need in economic development.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[2.The Center's duties are as follows:
(1)Research and development related to precision instrument;
(2)Production and maintenance mend of precision instrument;
(3)Survey, communication, supply and professional training for precision instrument; and
(4)Other matters related to precision instrument that are assigned by the superior authorities.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[3.The Center shall have a Director to manage the affairs and activities, and to guide supervise all the employees of the Center.  The Center shall have a Deputy Director to assist the Director in management of the affairs and activities of the Center.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[4.The Center shall have the following divisions and offices for the respective duties and administration set forth in Article 2 hereof.  Each division may have a number of sections for different affairs and activities, and the head of each section shall be designated from personnel who are concurrently senior engineers of the division, at the Center.
(1)Research and Development Division;
(2)Manufacturing and Maintenance Division;
(3)Technical Service Division; and
(4)Administration Office.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[5.The Center shall be staffed with division chief, vice division chief, chief of office, secretary general, section head, engineer, associate engineer, assistance engineer, technician, section staff, junior staff and clerk.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[6.The Center shall have an Accounting Office headed by a director and staffed with a number of assistances for auditing, accounting and statistics in compliance with the laws.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[7.The Center shall have a Personnel Office headed by a director and staffed with a number of assistances for personnel management in compliance with the laws.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[8.Rank requirement and number of authorized personnel for the Center are specified in the attached personnel organization.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[9.The Center may, subject to approval from the Council, employ researchers, associate researchers and assistant researchers to research and develop special and precision instrument.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 10</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[10.The Center may, upon need in its affairs and activities, appoint working committee members with pay for committees from various professional fields, each for a period of one year, eligible for re-appointment.  Personnel for working in these respective committees shall be among the authorized personnel.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 11</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[11.The Center may, subject to approval from the Council, employ professional technicians for need in its affairs and activities.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 12</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[12.Rules for operation of the Center shall be framed separately.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 13</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[13.This memorandum shall be effective from the date of promulgation.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
