<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Regulations on the Conferment of the National Cultural Award by the Executive Yuan, R.O.C.</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>行政院文化獎頒給辦法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=H0170002</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20170222</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件>
  <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000002776</下載網址>
  <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000002777</下載網址>
  <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000004735</下載網址>
  <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000004736</下載網址>
</附件>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated by Executive Yuan Decree No. Tai 69 Jiaozidi 4030, issued April 12, 1980
2.Revised by Executive Yuan Decree No. Tai 69 Jiaozidi 6524, issued June 6, 1980
3.Revised by Executive Yuan Decree No. Tai 71 Huazidi 15232, issued September 7, 1982
4.Revised by Executive Yuan Decree No. Tai Wenzidi 0910037461, issued July 31, 2002
5.Revised by Executive Yuan Decree No. Tai Wenzidi 0940041540, issued October 7, 2005
6.Revised by Executive Yuan Decree No. Tai Wenzidi 0960048241, issued December 5, 2007
7.Revised by Executive Yuan Decree No. Tai Wenzidi 0970039504, issued October 13, 2008
8.Revised by Executive Yuan Decree No. Tai Wenzidi 1020059945, issued March 10, 2014
9.Revised by Executive Yuan Decree No. Tai Wenzidi 1030045220, issued October 21, 2014
10.Revised by Executive Yuan Decree No. Tai Wenzidi 1040025682, issued July 2, 2015
11.Revised by Executive Yuan Decree No. Tai Wenzidi 1060002579, issued February 22, 2017]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These regulations are drawn up in accordance with Article 9, Paragraph 1 of the Medal Award Act.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Executive Yuan’s National Cultural Award (hereafter “NCA”) recognizes individuals making outstanding contributions to the preservation and enhancement of the Republic of China’s culture.
Attachment 1 is an illustration of the NCA medal.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Nomination for the NCA is held annually. The Ministry of Culture selects up to five potential NCA recipients. The list of recipients shall be approved by the Premier.
The following may nominate candidates by writing the candidate’s name and achievements:
1. NCA jury members;
2. Heads of cultural/academic organizations;
3. Heads of arts and cultural departments or institutes at universities; and
4. The responsible person of legally registered foundations or associations for the promotion of arts and culture.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Each NCA medal is given in conjunction with an Award Certificate, the format of which is illustrated as Attachment 2.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The awards will be presented in a public ceremony. A monetary award will also be presented.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These regulations shall be effective as of the date of promulgation.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
