<法規>
<法規性質>法律</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Act to Implement the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights and the International Covenant on Economic, Social and Cultural Rights</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>公民與政治權利國際公約及經濟社會文化權利國際公約施行法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawContent.aspx?PCODE=I0020028</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20090422</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated on April 22, 2009]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This Act is made to implement the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights and the International Covenant on Economic, Social and Cultural Rights (hereafter the two Covenants), which were both adopted by the United Nations in 1966, and to strengthen our country’s human rights protection system.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Human rights protection provisions in the two Covenants have domestic legal status.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Applications of the two Covenants should make reference to their legislative purposes and interpretations by the Human Rights Committee.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Whenever exercise their functions all levels of governmental institutions and agencies should confirm to human rights protection provisions in the two Covenants; avoid violating human rights; protect the people from infringement by others; positively promote realization of human rights.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[All levels of governmental institutions and agencies should take the responsibility for preparing, promoting and implementing human rights protection provisions in the two Covenants within their functions that are governed by existing laws and regulations. When multi functions are involved distinct governmental institutions and agencies should contact and coordinate themselves to carry out their responsibilities. The government should cooperate with other national governments and international non-governmental organizations and human rights institutions to realize promotion and protection of human rights provisions in the two Covenants.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The government should set up human rights reports system in accordance with the two Covenants.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[All levels of governmental institutions and agencies should preferentially allocate funds to implement human rights protection provisions in the two Covenants according to their financial status, and take steps to enforce.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[All levels of governmental institutions and agencies should review laws ， regulations, directions  and administrative measures within their functions according to the two Covenants. All laws, regulations, directions and administrative measures incompatible to the two Covenants should be amended within two years after the Act enters into force by new laws, law amendments, law abolitions and improved administrative measures.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The date of coming into force of the Act shall be decided by the Executive Yuan.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
