<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Regulations Governing the Permission for Foreign Attorneys to Employ ROC Attorneys or to Partner with ROC Attorneys to Operate a Foreign Law Firm</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>外國法事務律師僱用中華民國律師或與中華民國律師合夥經營法律事務所許可及管理辦法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=I0020018</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20020220</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated on February 20, 2002 by the Order of Ministry of Justice of No. 0910800356.]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These regulations are formulated in accordance with the proviso in the provisions of Article 47-10 of the Attorney Regulation Act (hereinafter referred to as this Act).]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Foreign attorneys may apply to the Ministry of Justice, pursuant to these regulations, for permission to employ ROC attorneys, or to form a partnership with ROC attorneys, in order to operate a foreign law firm.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[When a foreign attorney applies for permission to employ an ROC attorney, following documents should be submitted:
1.Two copies of the Application Form (as shown in appendix 1);
2.Two copies of the Identification documentation for the foreign attorney and ROC attorney, attorney license and Bar Association Membership certificate.
3.Two copies of the Employment contract.
The following items should be stated in an employment contract, as mentioned in the third subparagraph of the preceding paragraph:
1.Name of the foreign attorney, the Ministry of Justice Permit Number, nationality, passport number, domestic and overseas domicile and residence addresses, and name of the law firm and address.
2.Name of the ROC attorney intended to be employed, attorney license number and domicile or residence address.
3.Job description of the ROC attorney intended to be employed;
4.Salary;
5.Employment duration and the start and ending dates of the employment contract.
The employment contract as mentioned in subparagraph 3 of the first paragraph shall be written in Chinese or English; if English is used, a copy of a Chinese translation should be included.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[When foreign attorneys apply for permission to form a partnership with ROC attorneys, the application should be submitted in the name of natural persons of all partners of foreign attorneys and ROC attorneys, along with the following documents:
1.Application Form in duplicate (as shown in appendix 2);
2.Identification documentation for the foreign attorney and ROC attorney, attorney license and Bar Association Membership certificate, all in duplicate.
3.Partnership contract in duplicate.
The following information should be specified in the partnership contract, as mentioned in subparagraph 3 of the preceding paragraph:
1.Name and address of the partnership office;
2.Names of the foreign attorneys, the Ministry of Justice Permit Number, nationality, passport number, domestic and overseas domicile and residence addresses;
3.Name of the ROC attorney, attorney license number and domicile or residence address;
4.Job description of each partner.
The partnership contract as mentioned in subparagraph 3 of the first paragraph shall be written in Chinese or English; if English is used, a copy of a Chinese translation should be included.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[If any one of the following conditions exists in the applications as described in the preceding two articles, the permission will not be granted:
1.The application does not comply with the proviso in the provisions of Article 47-10 of this Act;
2.Required documents, pursuant to the provisions of preceding two articles, were not submitted with the permit application;
3.The submitted documents lack details or compliance with regulations, and where required corrective action was not made within the prescribed deadline after receiving notification of such requirements, or where the correction made was incomplete pursuant to specified corrective items;
4.There are sufficient facts to support the likelihood of violating the provisions of Article 11 of these regulations;
5.The attorney who applies for a partnership or employment violates the provisions of Article 47-8 of this Act, and the circumstances are serious in nature;
The Ministry of Justice shall make an approval/rejection decision within 60 days from the next day following the receipt of the application as described in the preceding two Articles. However, this provision does not apply to an application, where submitted documents lack details or compliance with regulations, to which a notification of corrective action within a prescribed deadline is sent.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Prior to granting permission for foreign attorneys to employ or form partnerships with ROC attorneys, the Ministry of Justice shall consult with the local Bar Association where the foreign law firm is located, and its National Bar Association for their opinions.
After consulting with local and national bar associations for their opinions pursuant to the provisions of preceding paragraph, the Ministry of Justice shall notify the said bar associations of the approval/rejection status of the said application.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[After obtaining permission to form a partnership with ROC attorneys, if any of the partners in the foreign law firm is changed, and the partnership with ROC attorneys continues, the foreign attorneys must submit a proof of agreement signed by all partners, and apply for permission to change. However, if all partners of either contingency, the foreign attorneys or ROC attorneys, change at the same time, which then brakes the foundation of the original partnership, the resulting law firm shall re-apply for permission.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Where foreign attorneys employ or partner with ROC attorneys, the term “foreign law firm” should be added to the name of their law firm, and each foreign attorney's practice permit, as well as each ROC attorney's Attorney License, shall be displayed in clearly visible spaces in the law firm.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[When a foreign attorney, or an ROC attorney, of an approved foreign law firm hires an ROC attorney, an application for permission of such a hiring is still required, pursuant to the provisions of these regulations.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 10</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Foreign attorneys, who have been granted permission to employ or partner with ROC attorneys, must immediately submit a report to the Ministry of Justice when the employment or partnership is terminated. The local Bar Association and National Bar Association shall also be notified of such a termination.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 11</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Foreign attorneys, who have been granted permission to employ or partner with ROC attorneys, may not use such employment or partnership as a guise to conduct legal affairs other than as prescribed in provisions of Article 47-7 of this Act.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 12</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Foreign attorneys, who have been granted permission to employ or partner with ROC attorneys, shall abide by the laws of the Republic of China, the Attorneys' Code of Ethics of ROC lawyers, and the charter of the Bar Association.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 13</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[If any one of the following conditions occurs, the Ministry of Justice shall revoke or cancel the permission granted for foreign attorneys to partner with or employ ROC attorneys:
1.A foreign attorney's application to employ or partner with ROC attorneys is fabricated or false;
2.The employment or partnership is terminated;
3.The practice permit of the foreign attorney, who is applying to employ or partner with ROC attorneys, has been revoked by the Ministry of Justice;
4.Any violation of the provisions of Articles 7 through 11 of these regulations occurs;
5.Violation of the provisions of Article 12 of these regulations, where the circumstances are serious in nature.
The Ministry of Justice shall, prior to implementing a revocation or cancellation of a permit as described in the preceding paragraph, consult with the local and national bar associations for their opinions on such an action, and then notify the party receiving such sanction and the local and national bar associations after the permit is revoked or cancelled.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 14</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulations shall come into force on the date of their promulgation.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
