<法規>
<法規性質>法律</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Organizational Act of the International Trade Administration, Ministry of Economic Affairs</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>經濟部國際貿易署組織法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=J0000092</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20230607</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated on June 7, 2023]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Ministry of Economic Affairs shall establish the International Trade Administration (hereinafter referred as the Administration) to manage international trade-related affairs.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Administration shall be charged with:
1. Planning trade policies and formulating related rules and regulations;
2. Engaging in international trade cooperation, participating in the activities of international economic and trade organizations, promoting and implementing economic and trade agreements, and protocols for foreign trade delegations;
3. Formulating and implementing policies for trade promotion and MICE industry development.
4. Investigating and removing trade barriers, responding to trade remedies initiated by foreign counterparts, and handling trade disputes;
5. Collecting and analyzing data on international trade environment and dynamics;
6. Administering the import and export regime, and managing export control and trade security control;
7. Managing commodity classification, Certificate of Origin, and registration of exporters and importers.
8. Investigating import relief cases and investigating the injury on industries with respect to anti-dumping and countervailing duty cases.
9. Other matters related to international trade.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Administration shall have one Director-General at a rank equivalent to senior appointment at the grade of thirteen; and two Deputy Director-Generals at a rank equivalent to senior appointment at the grade of twelve.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Administration shall have one Secretary-General at a rank equivalent to senior appointment at the grade of eleven.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The scale of the positions and the number of personnel of each official rank of the Administration shall be stipulated in a staffing chart.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The enforcement date of the Act shall be specified in an order from the Executive Yuan.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
