<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Regulations for Running Training and Workshops for Full-Time Technicians of Refrigeration and Air Conditioning Industries</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>冷凍空調業之專任技術士訓練講習實施辦法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawContent.aspx?PCODE=J0030080</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20041222</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Date：December 22,2004 (Announced)]]></沿革內容>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulations are enacted in accordance with Paragraph 2 of Article 14 of the Refrigeration and Air Conditioning Industries Governance Act.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The central competent authority may entrust other institutions to run training or workshops for full-time technicians of refrigeration and air conditioning enterprises.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[A full-time technician of a refrigeration and air conditioning enterprise shall attend training or workshops of eight hours duration every two years.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Training or workshop courses for refrigeration and air conditioning enterprises cover the following subjects:
1. Laws and regulations governing refrigeration and air conditioning enterprises.
2. Matters relating to the manufacturing of refrigeration and air conditioning equipment.
3. Matters relating to the construction, installation, testing, servicing or maintenance of refrigeration and air conditioning equipment.
4. Other related matters.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Upon the conclusion of a training or workshop course, all the attending full-time refrigeration and air conditioning enterprise technicians shall take a test.  
Technicians passing the test shall be issued a certificate of the training or workshop hours; otherwise, the training or workshop hours shall not be counted.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulations shall come into force from the date of promulgation.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
