<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Regulation on Businesses Electronically Processing the Accounting Data</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>商業使用電子方式處理會計資料辦法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=J0080029</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20061129</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated on September 11, 1996
2.Amended on November 29, 2006]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This Regulation is enacted according to the paragraph 1 of Article 40 of Business Entity Accounting Act.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The following terms are used in this regulation with the meanings specified:
1.Accounting data: Including accounting documents, account books, account items and financial statements, etc.
2.Data storage medium: The disks, magnetic sheet, magnetic tape, and CDs used to store accounting data when processing accounting affairs electronically.
3.Accounting software: The application programs used for processing accounting data.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Business entities shall set up internal control when processing accounting data electronically to ensure the hardware, software, data storage medium and accounting data safe, correct, and complete.
The internal controls mentioned in the previous paragraph shall regulate the following matters in written form:
1.Appropriate division of duties.
2.Management and supervision of the use rights of accounting software and data files.
3.Authorization and supervision of the change of accounting software.
4.Verification of accounting data input, processing and output.
5.Storage and maintenance of the data backup.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The procedures for processing accounting data electronically are as follow:
1.Get or give the source document.
2.Input and verify the accounting data.
3.Prepare the bookkeeping voucher, account books, and financial statements, etc.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Business entities processing accounting data electronically, the authorization for input accounting data shall be in writing. The signed or stamped of the responsible person, manager, host and accounting staff in the bookkeeping voucher and account books can be replaced by control program that set by authorization password.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[When processing accounting data electronically, if errors are found, they should be corrected after review, and make a record for checking.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The accounting documents, account books and financial statements of business entities, can be output electronically or store by data storage medium.
Business entities shall number sequentially and bound into volumes when processing the account books electronically.
The business entities who use the data storage medium to store accounting data, shall provide the accounting software and data storage medium of processing accounting data, and print out the accounting data in the data storage medium for examine.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Business entities processing accounting data electronically, their financial statements shall accordance with Regulation on Business Entity Accounting Handling.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[All the accounting documents in the data storage medium, except those which should be permanently kept or which are related to unsettled accounting events, must be kept for at least five years after the completion of annual closing procedures.
All the account books and financial statements in the data storage medium must be kept for at least ten years after the completion of annual closing procedures; but those unsettled accounting matters are not limited to this.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 10</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Business entities processing accounting data electronically, should prepare accounting data processing manual and update with changes in processing operations.
The accounting data processing manual must keep safely when the relevant manager or handling accountant dismissed or changing their duties, they should transfer it.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 11</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The accounting data processing manual mentioned in the previous article should include the following items:
1.The operation procedure for the processing of accounting data electronically.
2.The format of input and output the data.
3.The accounting data control methods, include the accounting data input, processing, output and storage.
4.The code number and Chinese name comparison table of the chart of account.
5.The operation procedure of wrong data.
6.The procedure of data backup and recovery.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 12</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The accounting software used by the business entities should include the following basic functions :
1.Create the file of the chart of account.
2.Log in the bookkeeping voucher.
3.Inspect and control the accounting data.
4.Posting the accounting journal.
5.Display and print of various accounting books, forms and financial statements.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 13</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Business entities processing accounting data electronically should audit its accounting processing system periodically.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 14</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This Regulation shall become effective from the date of issuance.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
