<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Enforcement Rules of the Business Registration Act</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>商業登記法施行細則</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawContent.aspx?PCODE=J0080005</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20160906</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>廢</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1. Promulgated on May 19, 1937 
2. Amended on October 2, 1946 
3. Amended on October 11, 1948
4. Amended on December 19 , 1952
5. Amended on October 8 , 1960
6. Amended on January 6, 1965
7. Amended on March 15, 1969
8. Amended and promulgated by Order Ching (62) Shang Tze No. 03833 on February 14, 1973 
9. Amended and promulgated by Order Ching (73) Shang Tze No. 41698 on October 26, 1984 
10. Amended and promulgated by Order Ching (80) Shang Tze No. 005927 on February 13, 1991 
11. Amended and promulgated by Order Ching (87) Shang Tze No. 86041358 on January 14, 1998 
12. Amended and promulgated by Order Ching (88) Shang Tze No. 88216066 on August 11, 1999 
13. Amended and promulgated by Order Ching (89) Shang Tze No. 89008177 on April 5, 2000 
14. Amended and promulgated by Order Ching (92) Shang Tze No. 09202027320 on February 26, 2003  
15. Amended and promulgated by Order Ching (97) Shang Tze No. 09702404450 on March 14, 2008
16. Amended on July 10 , 2009
17. Abolished on September 06, 2016]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Rules are prescribed pursuant to Article 36 of the Business Registration Act (hereinafter referred to as "this Act").
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The term "family agriculture, forestry, fishery, animal husbandry and handiwork business" referred to at Items 2 and 3 of Article 5 of this Act means any business operated by a sole proprietor or operated mainly by the sole proprietor owner with a limited amount of　help from its employees.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The relevant Authority of the municipality and the county (city) where the business is located shall maintain a business registration book which shall contain the following particulars:1. Those particulars prescribed at Paragraph 1 of Article 9 of this Act.2. The business registration of a person limited in capacity to make juridical acts being a sole proprietor or a partner of partnership.3. The business registration of a guardian running a business for a person who has no capacity or limited capacity to make juridical acts.4. The registration of managerial officers.5. Other registration particulars.The business registration book of the preceding paragraph may be replaced by computerized records.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The term "interested person" referred to at Articles 25 and 26 of this Act means, in addition to partners, the persons who are the creditors or debtors of the business or partners, or persons who have some other similar legal relationship.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[(Delete)
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[(Delete)
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The effective date of these Rules shall be prescribed by the Executive Yuan.
The Amendment to these Enforce Rules takes effect from the date of promulgation.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
