<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Regulations for Rewarding Informants in Cases Involving False Labeling of Origin of Goods by Exporters/Importers</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>出進口人產地標示不實案件檢舉處理及獎勵辦法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=J0090033</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20231115</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated on 21 February 2020 and effective on 21 February 2020
2.Amendment of the full text for 7 Articles promulgated on November 15, 2023]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulations are enacted pursuant to paragraph 2 of Article 17-1 of the Foreign Trade Act.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The competent authority for these regulations is the Ministry of Economic Affairs (MOEA), and the implementation shall be carried out by the International Trade Administration (hereafter referred to as TITA) of the MOEA.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The informant may report behavior involving the false labeling of origin of goods by exporters/importers to the TITA by means of written communication, including email and fax. The report shall include the following information:
1. The whistleblower's name, national identification number, address, and telephone number.
2. The informant's name, national identification number and address, or other identifiable information. If the violator is a juristic person, the name and address of the entity, as well as the name of the representative shall be provided.
3. Specifics about the violation, including the means of violation, other relevant information, or any leads that may help the investigation.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[No reward shall be granted if the report involves any of the following circumstances：
1. The report is made anonymously or under an alias.
2. No evidence is found based on the reported violation or the evidence does not match the report.
3. The competent authorities or other government agencies were already aware of the violation prior to the report.
4. Cases that have been published on the internet, newspapers, magazines, radio, television, other media, or public places.
5. Cases discovered while on-duty public servants were carrying out their regular duties.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The MOEA and TITA shall keep the informant’s name, national identification number, address, telephone number, and other identifiable information confidential.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Once the reported violation is substantiated by the TITA , the MOEA shall reward the informant with an award certificate.
If a severe violation results in the TITA nullifying a company's export/import registration, the MOEA shall reward the informant with a trophy.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulations shall enter into force from the date of promulgation.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
