<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Regulations on Import and Export of Endangered Species of Wild Fauna, Flora and Related Products</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>瀕臨絕種動植物及其產製品輸出入管理辦法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=J0090028</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20231114</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1. Promulagted on August 16, 2010
2. Amendment of the full text for 26 Articles promulgated on November 14, 2023]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These regulations are enacted pursuant to Paragraph 4 of Article 13-1 of the Foreign Trade Act (hereafter referred to as “the Act”).]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The management authority hereto is referred to the Ministry of Economic Affairs; and the executing agency hereto is referred to the International Trade Administration (hereafter referred to as “the TITA”).]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The endangered species of fauna, flora and products thereof, hereto are referred to the species listed in Appendix I, Appendix II, and Appendix III of the endangered species of wild fauna and flora (Hereafter referred to as “Appendix I, Appendix II, and Appendix III).]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Unless otherwise specified by the management authority, when importing endangered species of wild fauna, flora, and products thereof, importer shall submit a Convention on International Trade in Endangered Species of Wild Fauna and Flora (hereafter referred to as “CITES”) certificate or other certificates relating to importation.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[When importing endangered species of wild fauna, flora, and products thereof, importer shall list the following information of the imported goods in the import declaration: the scientific name, the common name, and the certificate number of the CITES certificate or other permit issued by the exporting country.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The import of endangered species of wild fauna, flora, and products thereof, shall comply with the CITES certificate or other permits issued by the exporting country.
Importer shall submit the CITES certificate or other permits issued by the exporting country, if the certificate or permit contains the fields for the actual quantity of exportation, and signature and stamp, then the exporting country shall list the quantity and display the stamp.
When performing verification, the importing customs shall mark down the import declaration number and the item number or those of the relevant documents, and proceeds to submit the original copies of the CITES certificate or other permits to the TITA.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Exporting Country, prior to issuing the CITES certificates for the endangered species of wild fauna, flora, and products thereof, included in Appendix I; if it requires to obtain a CITES import permit in advance, the importer shall submit the following documents to the TITA:
1.A complete CITES import permit application;
2.Approval documents issued by the central industry competent authority;
3.Other documents as specified.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The export of the endangered species of wild faunas and products thereof, included in Appendices I and II shall require a prior grant of the CITES export permit from the TITA.
Exporter applying for the aforementioned CITES export permit, shall submit the following documents:
1.A complete CITES export permit application;
2.Other documents as specified.
Exporter applying for exportation of the endangered species of fauna and its products thereof, in Appendix I and the wild animals and its products thereof, as referred to Article 13-1, paragraph 2 and stipulated by the Wildlife Conservation Law, in addition to complying with the preceding regulations, shall submit the approval documents issued by the central industry competent authority.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The re-export of the endangered species of fauna and products thereof, included in Appendices I and II shall require a prior grant of the CITES re-export permit from the TITA.
Exporter applying for the aforementioned CITES export permit, shall submit the following documents:
1.A complete CITES re-export permit application;
2.Import declaration form or other relevant documents issued by the importing customs;
3.A photocopy of the CITES export permit issued by the exporting country; verified and registered by the importing customs;
4.Other documents as specified.
Exporter applying for re-exportation of the endangered species of fauna and its related product included in Appendix I and of the wild animals and its products thereof, as referred to Article 13-1, paragraph 2 and stipulated by the Wildlife Conservation Law, in addition to complying with the preceding regulations, shall submit the approval documentation issued by the central industry competent authority.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 10</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The export of the endangered species of flora and products thereof, included in Appendices I and II, shall require a prior grant of the CITES export permit from the TITA.
Exporter applying for the aforementioned CITES export permit, shall submit the following documents:
1.A complete CITES export permit application;
2.Other documents as specified.
Exporter applying for the endangered species of flora and products thereof, included in Appendix I, in addition to complying with the preceding regulation, shall submit the approval documentation issued by the central industry competent authority.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 11</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The re-export of the endangered flora and products thereof, included in Appendices I and II, shall require a prior grant of the CITE re-export permit from the TITA.
Exporter applying for the aforementioned CITES re-export permit, shall submit the following documents:
1.A complete CITES re-export permit application;
2.Import declaration form or other relevant documents;
3.A photocopy of the CITES export permit issued by the exporting party, and verified and registered by the importing customs;
4.Other documents as specified.
Exporter applying for the endangered flora and products thereof, included in Appendix I, in addition to complying with the preceding regulation, shall submit the approval documentation issued by the central industry competent authority.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 12</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The export of the endangered fauna, flora, and products thereof, included in Appendix III, shall require a prior grant of the CITES export permit from the TITA.
Exporter applying for the aforementioned CITES other permit, shall submit the following documents:
1.A complete CITES other permit application;
2.Other documents as specified.
Exporter applying for exportation of the endangered species of fauna and its related product included in Appendix I and of the wild animals and its products thereof, as referred to Article 13-1, paragraph 2 and stipulated by the Wildlife Conservation Law, in addition to complying with the preceding regulations, shall submit the approval documentation issued by the central industry competent authority.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 13</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The re-export of the endangered fauna, flora and products thereof, included in Appendices III, shall require a prior grant of the CITE re-export permit from the TITA.
Exporter applying for the aforementioned CITES re-export permit, shall submit the following documents:
1.A complete CITES other permit application;
2.Import declaration form or other relevant documents;
3.A photocopy of the CITES permit issued by the exporting party, and verified and registered by the importing customs;
4.Other documents as specified.
Exporter applying for re-exportation of the endangered species of fauna and its related product included in Appendix III and of the wild animals and its products thereof, as referred to Article 13-1, paragraph 2 and stipulated by the Wildlife Conservation Law, in addition to complying with the preceding regulations, shall submit the approval documentation issued by the central industry competent authority.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 14</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The export of the endangered species of fauna, flora, and products thereof, shall be processed in accordance with the provisions of the CITES issued by the TITA or other certificates.
Exporting customs shall mark the actual quantity of exportation on the aforementioned permit and apply signature and seal of the exporting customs agency.
Exporter shall attach the aforementioned certificate, marked with the actual quantity of exportation, signed and sealed by the exporting customs, to the exporting commodities.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 15</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Exporter when exporting endangered species of fauna, flora, and products thereof, shall submit the following information singly in export declaration form or other relevant documents: the scientific name and the common name of the exporting goods; The permit number issued by the TITA or the number, items, and relevant information of other permits.
If the exporter declares exportation without the export declaration form, exporting customs shall transfer the permit or the photocopy thereof, to the TITA after verification.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 16</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[If exporter lost the permit issued by the TITA, prior to the exportation or during shipping, exporter shall apply to the TITA for de-registration of the permit.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 17</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[If exporter lost the permit issued by the TITA, prior to the exportation and applied for de-registration as the preceding item stipulates, exporter shall submit the following documents to the TITA for application of re-issuance:
1.A complete CITES export permit, re-export permit, or other permit application;
2.Documentary explanation of loss of the permit.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 18</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[If exporter lost the permit issued by the TITA, during the shipping and applied for de-registration as Article 16 stipulates, shall submit the following documents to the TITA for re-issuance:
1.A complete CITES export permit, re-export permit, or other permit application;
2.Documentary explanation of loss of the permit;
3.Export declaration or other relevant documents issued by the exporting customs;
4.Proof of the responsible shipping firms;
5.Other documents as specified.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 19</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The TITA determines format of the CITES certificate and permit.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 20</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Application for the CITES permit or other certificates shall be done electronically; the TITA shall issue a documentary permit after approval. However, in the case of technical difficulties from the TITA system, application can be done documentarily.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 21</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The CITES certificate and other permits have a validity of no more than six (6) months, counting from the date of issuance, and hold a restriction of one-time export and import. However for certain specific goods, a certificate or permit of shorter validity length can be issued.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 22</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[If any error is found in the Certificate or other permits prior to customs declaration, shall submit the original permit and apply for de-registration and re-issuance. Application of editing is prohibited.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 23</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The CITES certificate and other permits shall be used within the validity period; extension of the validity period is prohibited.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 24</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The management authority shall proclaim other provisions related to endangered species of fauna, flora, and products thereof.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 25</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Export and Import of endangered species of fauna, flora, and products thereof, shall preserve all transaction documents and information related to the import and export, for no less than five (5) years, counting from the release of the exporting/importing goods.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 26</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These regulations will be in full force and fully effective from the date of announcement.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
