<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Regulations Governing Electronic Licensing for the Export and Import of Commodities</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>輸出入貨品電子簽證管理辦法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=J0090025</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20231123</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1. Promulgated on November 20, 2002
2. Amended on December 29, 2004
3. Revised on August 2, 2005
4. Amendment to Articles 8 promulgated on April 28, 2008
5. Amendment to Articles 8 promulgated on December 19, 2008
6. Revised on November 23, 2023]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulations are enacted pursuant to Paragraph 2, Article 15-1 of the Foreign Trade Act.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The term "electronic licensing" in these Regulations refers to a permit that an applicant applies for from the International Trade Administration (hereafter referred to as “TITA”), Ministry of Economic Affairs for import/export approval via electronic documents (hereinafter to be written "electronic documents") by means of electronic data transfer. The aforementioned means of electronic data transfer include two kinds:
1. Connecting and registering with the TITA's website in order to transfer the electronic document data.
2. Transferring the electronic data of the electronic documents through the "Facile Trade Net."
The Standard Message and Implementation Guidelines for Import/Export Approval Electronic Documents will be announced separately by the TITA.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulations shall be applied to the following electronic documents:
1. Import/Export Permits;
2. Application for Optical Disk Manufacturing
Implement Export/Import Declarations;
3. Convention on International Trade in Endangered Species of Wild Fauna and Flora (CITES) Permits;
4. Export Permits of Strategic High-Tech Commodities;
5. International Import Certificates of Strategic High-Tech Commodities;
6. Written Assurance Certificates of Strategic High-Tech Commodities Import;
7. End-Use Certificate for Chemicals of the Chemical Weapons Convention;
8. Other electronic documents that must be applied for electronically, as publicly announced by the TITA.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Applicants applying for electronic documents shall do so by electronic means, unless one of the following three situations exists, in which case they shall apply by written documents:
1. The TITA computer system breaks down;
2. Application is for replacement of lost documents.
3. Other electronic documents that must be applied for by written documents as publicly announced by the TITA.
The procedural methods in the aforementioned proviso shall be publicly announced by the TITA.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Before applying for electronic documents on the TITA website, the applicant must first access the TITA website and apply to the TITA for a user ID and password, except if the applicant is using a Certification Authority IC Card issued by the Ministry of Economic Affairs.
The applicant must submit relevant approval documents unless it is a government agency or state-run enterprise, or the applicant is not a qualified importer/exporter.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Required documents (or copies thereof) shall be sent by postal mail, faxed, or e-mailed by the applicant; otherwise, the applicant shall apply by means of electronic data transfer mentioned in Article 2 under the import/export regulations of the TITA. The document receipt numbers, along with the signature and/or seal of the applicant or person responsible, shall be affixed on each of the documents. If necessary, the original materials shall be provided to the TITA for verification.
When the contents of written documents are converted to the electronic data standard message format for electronic documents, the applicant is exempt from the requirement to submit written documents.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The electronic application form shall be considered successfully delivered to the TITA once it is recorded into the TITA computers.
Applicants who apply for electronic licensing applications through the TITA website may check the processing status of their applications through the Internet. If applicants who apply for electronic licensing applications through the Facile Trade Net need to check the processing status of their applications, they should apply to the TITA for a user ID and password in accordance with the provisions of Article 5 of these Regulations.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Written forms of all electronic documents approved by the TITA shall be issued to applicants, except the following items:
1. Export/Import Permits,
2. Optical Disk Manufacturing Implement Export/Import Declarations,
3. Export Permits of Strategic High-Tech Commodities,
4. Other electronic documents announced by the TITA.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulations shall enter into force from the date of promulgation.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
