<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Regulations on Awarding the Professional Medal of Atomic Energy Council, Executive Yuan</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>行政院原子能委員會專業獎章頒給辦法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=J0160078</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>19921202</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Attachment 1.odt]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000005220</下載網址>
  </檔案>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Attachment 2 Certificate.odt]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000005221</下載網址>
  </檔案>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Attachment 3 Form of Factual Descriptions for Applying Metal of Atomic Energy.odt]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000005222</下載網址>
  </檔案>
</附件>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated on December 2, 1992 by the Atomic Energy Council Per its decree No. Huei-Jen-Tsu-19356]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[To award people with outstanding contribution to atomic energy works, the Atomic Energy Council (AEC), Executive Yuan thereby establishes these regulations in accordance with the Article 9 of the Medal Award Act and Article 15 of the Enforcement Rules of the Medal Award Act.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Medal of Atomic Energy (henceforth, the Metal) will be awarded to any individual who arduously contributes on atomic energy works and meets any of the following conditions:
1.Lead major project or execute important policy and with significant merits.
2.Involve and excel works on design, construction, operation, maintenance and management in areas of nuclear safety, radiation protection, waste management, and environment detection.
3.Discover promptly of atomic energy facility’s deficiency or abnormal event, and take effective remediation for proper protection.
4.Mitigate significant nuclear accident to protect public health, property, safety, and with special contributions.
5.Perform related research invention, or publication which has been reviewed and certified by competent authority as significant values for atomic energy academics or the profession.
6.Assist or correspond to develop or promote atomic energy technology and with outstanding achievements.
7.Advance international cooperation.
8.Any other significant contribution that merits commendation.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Medal is categorized in first grade, second grade, or third grade, and will be awarded in the form of lapel pins. Aside from foreign nationals, non-civil servant, or special cases, the third grade Medal will be awarded to first-time awardees, and should be used for future promotion.
If the same achievement has been awarded the Merit Medal or Exemplar Medal, the Metal shall not be awarded repeatedly.
An illustration of the Metal and accompanying miniature medal is shown in Attachment 1.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[A certificate of shall be issued along with the Medal, in the form indicated in Attachment 2. An alternate certificate form shall be made for foreign national.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[In addition to AEC awarding the Medal, the recipients could also be recommended by government agencies, atomic energy academics/institutions, public or private enterprises, and civilian organization.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Prior to awarding the Medal to any person, the applicant shall fill out the form of factual descriptions along with relevant supporting documents. The form of factual descriptions is shown in Attachment 3.
The applications for the Medal shall be reviewed and passed by a committee organized by the AEC and shall be approved by the AEC Minister. The Metal shall then be presented in a public ceremony.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[If the Metal recipient is a civil servant, by rules it shall be processed to the Ministry of Civil Service for recording.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[If the Metal recipient is deceased, the award may be received by his or her spouse or an immediate family representative.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This regulation shall take effect on the date of its promulgation.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
