<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>The Regulations on Reasonable Matters as Exceptions to Rescind the Distance Sales</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>通訊交易解除權合理例外情事適用準則</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawContent.aspx?PCODE=J0170012</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20151231</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Amended on December 31, 2015]]></沿革內容>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The regulations are enacted pursuant to Paragraph 2, Article 19 of the “Consumer Protection Act”. (hereinafter referred to as the “Act”)
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[“Reasonable matters” as exceptions referred in Paragraph 1, Article 19 of the Act shall mean the right to rescind the distance sales is not applicable under the circumstances where the goods or services are provided or rendered with one of the following matters; provided, the traders have made notice to consumers: 
1. The supply of goods which are liable to deteriorate, with fairly short shelf life, or expire rapidly at the time to rescind the contract; 
2. The supply of goods or services made to the consumer’s specifications or clearly personalized;
3. The supply of newspapers, periodicals or magazines; 
4. The supply of sealed audio, video recording or computer software which have been unsealed after delivery;
5. The supply of digital content which is not supplied on a tangible medium, or online services which would be fully performed once begun, with the consumer’s prior consent; 
6. The supply of sealed personal hygiene products which have been unsealed after delivery; 
7. The supply of international airline passenger services.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Matters related to rescind the distance sales shall apply to provisions prescribed in the mandatory or prohibitory provisions of standard contracts set forth pursuant to Paragraph 1, Article 17 of the Act, by the competent authorities at the central government.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Regulations shall come into force on January 1, 2016.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
