<法規>
<法規性質>法律</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Organization Act of the Institute of Transportation, Ministry of Transportation and Communications</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>交通部運輸研究所組織法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=K0000210</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20230607</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated on June 7, 2023 and enforced on September 15, 2023
  Stipulation and promulgation of all 6 articles per Presidential Decree No. Hua-Zong-Yi-Yi-Zi-11200046781 dated June 7, 2023; the date of implementation shall be stipulated by an decree of the Executive Yuan.
  The Act shall come into effect on September 15, 2023 upon promulgation by the Executive Yuan per Decree No. Yuan-Shou-Ren-Zu-Zi-11220013051 dated July 20, 2023.]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[To handle affairs related to transportation research, the Ministry of Transportation and Communications establishes the Institute of
Transportation (hereafter, “IOT”).]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The IOT shall be in charge of the following tasks:
1.Transportation policy research and recommendations.
2.Transportation system planning research and development.
3.Transportation engineering research and development.
4.Transportation operations and management research and development.
5.Transportation safety research and development.
6.Transportation, energy, and environmental research and development.
7.Transportation technology and information technology research and development.
8.Transportation technique research and development.
9.Contact and collaboration with domestic and international transportation institutions.
10.Other transportation research-related matters.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The IOT shall have one Director-General with the rank of senior civil servant Grade 13 or, when necessary, employ the President at a qualification equivalent to that of a president or a professor of an independent college and two Deputy Directors-General with the rank of senior civil servant Grade 12.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The IOT shall have a chief secretary with the rank of senior civil servant Grade 11.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The number of staff in the IOT and their ranks and grades shall be stipulated in a separate staffing chart.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The date that this Act enters into force shall be determined by the decree of the Executive Yuan.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
