<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Regulations for Superficies Acquisition Compensation by Transportation Operation Overpass and Underpass</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>交通事業穿越私有土地之上空或地下地上權徵收補償辦法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=K0020051</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20020924</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[Date：2002.09.24 (Announced)]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Regulations are enacted according to Paragraph 4 of Article 57 of Land Acquisition Act (the Act hereinafter)]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Regulations are applicable to transportation operation stated in Subparagraph 2 of Article 3 of the Act, except for other requirements based in other laws.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Land superficies acquired by land users For transportation purpose according to Paragraph 1 of Article 57 of the Act, shall be limited to scopes necessary in the transportation operation.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Compensation for superficies acquisition shall be calculated as below:

Overpass

Land acquisition value multiple height-compensation rate (refer to Appendix Table 1)

Underpass

Land acquisition value multiple depth-compensation rate (refer to Appendix Table 2)

Land improvements and structures that need to be removed due to traffic construction overpass and underpass, shall refer to compensation standards stipulated in the Act.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Except for other requirements in other laws, superficies required for transportation operation according to the Regulations, shall be overall registered for land overpass beyond the bottom limit stipulated in Appendix Table 1, and for land underpass below the shadow limit stipulated in Appendix Table 2.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Regulations come into effect from the date of promulgation.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
