<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Standards for Telecommunications Terminal Equipment Statutory Fee</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>電信終端設備規費收費標準</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=K0060078</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20070426</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Attachment：Table for Telecommunications Terminal Equipment Statutory Fee.PDF]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000004391</下載網址>
  </檔案>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Attachment：Table for Telecommunications Terminal Equipment Statutory Fee.doc]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000000306</下載網址>
  </檔案>
</附件>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1. 7 Articles promulgated in full by the Ministry of Transportation and Communications（MOTC） on Jan. 10, 2006. Ref ：Jiao-Lu-Fa Tze No.09500850031
2. 6 Articles amended and Promulgated in full by National Communications Commission（NCC） on April 26, 2007. Ref： Tung-Chuan-Ji Tze No.09605041880]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These standards are promulgated pursuant to Article 70 of the Telecommunications Act.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The telecommunications terminal equipment statutory fees include type approval fees and license fees.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Authority(NCC) or Recognized Certification Bodies (hereinafter as RCB ) shall charge inspection fee as attached Table for “Telecommunications Terminal Equipment Statutory Fees”（hereinafter as Statutory Fee Table）with respect to every application for type approval of the Telecommunications Terminal Equipment（hereinafter as TTE）.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[If approving TTE is under the scope of family series product, the second and subsequent products are charged half. However,apply for DoC family series product are excepted.
The aforementioned family series product has defined in Article 2 of the “Compliance Approval Regulations of Telecommunications Terminal Equipment”.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Those, who have lost, damaged or modified approval certificates or DoC certificates, shall apply for reissue or replacement to the original RCB, and the said RCB shall charge the certificate fees according to Statutory Fee Table.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Regulations shall become effective as of the date of promulgation.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
