<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Preparation Standard for Legislations, Required Medicine, and Medical Equipment on Ships</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>船上法令規章必要藥品及醫療設備備置標準</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=K0070065</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20150806</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Attachment 1：List of medicines to be stored in marine medicine cabinets.PDF]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000005957</下載網址>
  </檔案>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Attachment 1：List of medicines to be stored in marine medicine cabinets.doc]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000005958</下載網址>
  </檔案>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Attachment 2：List of medical equipment to be prepared in marine medicine cabinets.pdf]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000005959</下載網址>
  </檔案>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Attachment 2：List of medical equipment to be prepared in marine medicine cabinets.doc]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000005960</下載網址>
  </檔案>
</附件>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.In accordance with No. Jiao-Hang-Fa-Zi-091B000140 of the Ministry of Transportation and Communications of December 6,2002, the complete text of five articles has been issued and took effect as of the issued date.
2.The amendment to Article 3 was promulgated by order of the Ministry of Transportation and Communications No. Jiao-Hang-Zi-10450101971 dated August 6,2015.]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Standard is established according to requirements under paragraph 2, Article 15 of the Seafarer Act.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[A ship shall have the following legislations prepared:
1.The Seafarer Act.
2.The Law of Ships.
3.Maritime Act.
4.The Commercial Port Law.
5.Marine Pollution Control Act.
6.Labor Standards Act.
7.Regulations related to occupational safety and health of labors.
8.Rules on Setting Ship Load Lines.
9.International Regulations for Preventing Collisions at Sea.
10.Port state navigation waterways and navigation pass rules.
11.International Convention for the Safety of Life at Sea
12.1982 United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea.
13.International Convention on Tonnage Measurement of Ships.
14.International Convention on Load Line.
15.International Convention for the Prevention of Pollution from Ships
16.1978 International Convention on Standards of Training, Certification and Watchkeeping for Seafarers.
17.Other regulations required by laws and regulations or designation.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[A ship shall have medical guides, as well as the following medicines and medical equipment, prepared:
1.Basic medicine for trauma.
2.Medicine for diseases commonly seen on ships.
3.First-aid medicine and equipment.
4.Medicine for detoxication.
5.Other medicine and medical equipment required by the requirements under the Conventions.
Vessels with a total tonnage of over 100 or passenger boats with over 150 passengers shall have AED or other necessary first-aid equipment announced by Ministry of Health and Welfare competent authority in place.
The medicine, medical equipment, and first-aid equipment in the preceding two paragraphs shall be managed by designated personnel and shall be updated according to the valid period.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The medicine in the previous Article shall be prepared according to the requirements under Schedule I, and may be replaced by medicine with equivalent effects, specification, or ingredients.
The medical equipment in the previous Article shall be prepared according to the requirements under Schedule II.
Where the medicine to be prepared involves controlled drugs, employers shall obtain controlled drugs registration license according to requirements under Article 16 of the Controlled Drugs Act.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Standard is implemented on the date of its promulgation.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
