<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>The Standards for Minimum Safety Manning for Seafarers on a Ship</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>航行船舶船員最低安全配置標準</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawContent.aspx?PCODE=K0070048</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20150810</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件>
  <下載網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/Law/law_getfile.ashx?FileId=0000002874</下載網址>
  <下載網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/Law/law_getfile.ashx?FileId=0000002875</下載網址>
  <下載網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/Law/law_getfile.ashx?FileId=0000002876</下載網址>
  <下載網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/Law/law_getfile.ashx?FileId=0000002877</下載網址>
  <下載網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/Law/law_getfile.ashx?FileId=0000002878</下載網址>
  <下載網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/Law/law_getfile.ashx?FileId=0000002879</下載網址>
  <下載網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/Law/law_getfile.ashx?FileId=0000002880</下載網址>
  <下載網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/Law/law_getfile.ashx?FileId=0000002881</下載網址>
  <下載網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/Law/law_getfile.ashx?FileId=0000002882</下載網址>
</附件>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Enacted by order of the Ministry of Transportation and Communications No. Jiao-Hang-Fa-Zi-091B000109 dated September 20, 2002.
  All 10 articles published and implemented from the date of promulgation.
2.Amendment to all articles was promulgated by order of the Ministry of Transportation and Communications No. Jiao-Hang-Zi-0950085047 dated August 25, 2006.
  All 10 articles published, and implemented from the date of promulgation, except the date of promulgation for Article 4, which was set by the MOTC.
  The date of promulgation for Article 4 was promulgated by order of the Ministry of Transportation and Communications No. Jiao-Hang-Zi-0950085055 dated September 22, 2006.
3.The amendment to Article 4 was promulgated by order of the Ministry of Transportation and Communications No. Jiao-Hang-Zi-0970085064 dated December 16, 2008.
4.The amendment to Article 9 was promulgated by order of the Ministry of Transportation and Communications No. Jiao-Hang-Zi-0980085013 dated March 17, 2009.
5.The amendment to Article 9, Attachment 2 & 3 of Article 4 and Attachment 7~9 of Article 10 was promulgated by order of the Ministry of Transportation and Communications No. Jiao-Hang-Zi-10350109411 dated September 3, 2014.
6.In accordance with Jiao-Hang-Zi Order No. 10450104601 of the Ministry of Transportation and Communications of August 10, 2015, the complete text of ten articles has been issued and took effect as of the issued date.]]></沿革內容>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These standards have been established pursuant to Paragraph 2, Article 70-1 of the Seafarer Act.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The staffing of seafarers on a ship shall be implemented pursuant to these standards. In the case that no relevant standards apply, staffing shall be subject to related regulations.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These standards have been classified into the following four categories based on shipping route, type, and length:
1. Vessels with international shipping routes are categorized as either ‘traditional’ or ‘automatic control’ types on the basis of the operational capacity of their engine room. The minimum safety staffing for seafarers on such vessels shall be subject to the standards set forth in Attachment 1 herein.
2. The minimum safety staffing for seafarers on vessels with domestic shipping routes shall be subject to the standards set forth in Attachment 2 herein.
3. The minimum safety staffing for seafarers on vessels sailing between Taiwan and mainland China shall be subject to the standards set forth in Attachment 3 herein.
4. The minimum safety staffing for seafarers working on board powered and unpowered workboats shall be subject to the standards set forth in Attachment 4 herein.
The engineering equipment of the ‘automatic control vessels’ from Item 1 in the previous paragraph shall have been determined to be in satisfactory condition by a surveying organization recognized by the competent authority, and the vessel shall hold the classification certificate of a valid ship.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[To apply for the minimum safety staffing of seafarers on board an automatic control vessel, the employer shall submit the following documents to the Maritime Administration, which shall examine them and approve the application if satisfactory.
1. Vessel particulars.
2. Seafarer staffing table.
3. Valid ship’s classification certificate.
4. Vessel equipment list.
5. Plan for the navigational watch, moorings, lifesaving, firefighting, and damage control.
6. Other relevant documents.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[In the case that these standards are not able to be applied because of the ship’s equipment, usage, or other special circumstances, and, as a result, the employer has to equip the vessel with fewer seafarers than the minimum safety staffing stipulated in these standards, such employer shall submit the plans and relevant documents regarding the seafarer’s navigational watch, moorings, lifesaving, firefighting, and damage control for said ship to the Maritime Administration for application.
In the case that a vessel type cannot comply with the attachments prescribed in each paragraph of Article 3, the situation shall be managed in accordance with the aforementioned provisions.
When the employers of automatic control vessels submit an application for Item 1, the Maritime Administration may demand that they first acquire at least six months of practical experience. Upon completing said period, the employer shall fill out a Practical Experience Report (see Attachment 5) and submit it with a photocopy of the logbook entries for these six months to the Maritime Administration to be handled according to the aforementioned provisions.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[In accordance with their different responsibilities, seafarers of navigation ships are categorized into the Deck, Engineering, Telecommunications, and General Affairs Departments. Except for the Telecommunications Department, the apt number of officers and ratings shall be stipulated for each department, provided that the certified seafarer from the Deck Department can hold a concurrent post with the telecommunication personnel.
With regards to automatic control vessels with international shipping routes, each department shall employ general ratings jointly instead of assigning them separately.
In accordance with their different responsibilities, the seafarers of powered and unpowered workboats are categorized into the Deck and Engineering Departments, and an apt number of officers and ratings shall be assigned to each department.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[In accordance with the radio communication equipment of the vessel, the telecommunications personnel of the navigating ship are categorized into non-Global Maritime Distress and Safety System ship’s radio sets and Global Maritime Distress and Safety System ship’s radio sets. The minimum safety staffing of each shall be subject to the standards set forth in the Global Maritime Distress and Safety System minimum ship’s navigational watch safety staffing table (see Attachment 6).
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[In any given 24-hour period, seafarers of a navigating ship shall have a minimum of 10 hours of rest, and in any seven-day period, a minimum of 77 hours of rest. However, these requirements are exempt in the case of emergency, drill, or force majeure.
The hours of rest stipulated in the paragraph above can be divided into two periods, of which one is required be at least six hours, and the intervals between consecutive periods of rest shall not surpass 14 hours.
The ten hours of rest mentioned in the previous two paragraphs may be altered into at least one period of six consecutive hours provided it does not surpass two days. The seafarers’ work schedules should be posted in an easily accessible location.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Employers shall submit the relevant application form (see Attachment 7) for navigating ships to the Maritime Administration for the issuance of minimum safety staffing certification (see Attachments 8 and 9), which shall be kept on board for inspections.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 10</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These standards shall take effect starting from the date of promulgation.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
