<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Charging Standard for the Issuance of Certificate and License Fees for Seafarer’s Applications</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>船員申請許可核發證照收費標準</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=K0070054</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20180723</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.In accordance with No.Jiao-Hang-Fa-Zi-092B000006 of the Ministry of Transportation and Communications of January 21,2003,the complete text of five articles has been issued and took effect as of the issued date.
2.The amendment to Article 3、4 was promulgated by order of the Ministry of Transportation and Communications No.Jiao-Hang-Zi-10700201281 dated July 23,2018.]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Standard is established according to requirements under Article 91 of the Seafarer Act.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The reviewing fees, and certificate and license fees for reviewing the application for a permit, or issuance of certificate or license shall be subject to the requirements under the Standard. For unaddressed matters in the Standard,comply with requirements under other relevant regulations.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Charging standards for reviewing fees are as follow:
1.Employment and Departure Certificate of Seafarers:NT$200 per copy.
2.Service Experience Certificate of Seafarers:NT$200 for the first copy,NT$20 per copy from the second copy.
3.Resumption of seafarers status:NT$500 per person.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Charging standards for certificate and license fees are as follow:
1.The issuance,renewal,and reissuance of seafarers service book:NT$500 per copy.
2.The issuance,renewal,and reissuance of foreign seafarers:NT$500 per copy.
3.The issuance,renewal,and reissuance of a certificate of competency as a captain or chief engineer:NT$1,000 per copy.
4.The issuance, renewal, and reissuance of a certificate of competency as a first class officer or first class engineer:NT$800 per copy.
5.The issuance, renewal, and reissuance of a certificate of competency as a deck officer, engineer, third class captain, third class officer, third class chief engineer, third class engineer, as well as telecommunications personnel and electrical technician for vessels:NT$800 per copy.
6.The issuance, renewal, and reissuance of a certificate of competency as a foreign class A crew: NT$800 per copy.
7.The issuance, renewal, and reissuance of a certificate of competency as a petty officer:NT$500 per copy.
8.The issuance, renewal, and reissuance of a certificate of competency as a foreign class B crew: NT$500 per copy.
9.The issuance, renewal, and reissuance of minimum safe manning:NT$1000 per copy.
10.Extension for seafarers service book and seafarers certificate of competency:NT$200 per copy.
Fees may be exempted for any overall renewal for certificate and license by the maritime authority.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Standard is implemented on the date of its promulgation.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
