<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Fee-charge Regulations for Visiting Guishan Island</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>龜山島登島收費辦法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=K0110041</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20160415</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated and announced according to Decree No. 1050300280 by the Northeast and Yilan Coast National Scenic Area Administration, Tourism Bureau, Ministry of Transportation and Communication on April 15th, 2016, and taken into force since 1st July, 2016.]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulations are enacted in accordance with Paragraph 1 of Article 10 of the Charges and Fees Act.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Fees for visiting Guishan Island are as follows:
1. Environment cleaning and maintenance fee: NT$40.
2. Island facility maintenance fee: NT$60.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Visitors who meet any one of the following conditions are eligible for receive a 50% discount upon providing identification documents:
1. Aged 65 and above during holidays.
2. Conditions set forth in Paragraph 3 of Article 20 of the Volunteer Service Act.
3. Other conditions for 50% discount announced by the Ministry of Transportation and Communications.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Visitors who meet any one of the following conditions are eligible for free admission upon providing identification documents:
1. Aged 65 and above during weekdays.
2. Disabled persons with proof of disability and one assistant if necessary.
3. Volunteer holding a Service Honor Card.
4. Other conditions for free admission announced by the Ministry of Transportation and Communications.
5. Participants in local and ecological education events organized by　agencies, schools and residents of Yilan County.
6. Persons holding official documents of this Administration for the conduct of assistance by agencies or schools, or for academic surveys.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[In the event an applicant cannot travel to the island on the reserved date due to reasons not attributable to the applicant, e.g. weather conditions, fees already paid by the applicant will be refunded without interest, or retained for use before the island is closed for the year.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulations shall take effect on 1st July, 2016.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
