<法規>
<法規性質>法律</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>The Organizational Act of The National Research Institute of Chinese Medicine, Ministry of Health and Welfare</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>衛生福利部國家中醫藥研究所組織法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawContent.aspx?PCODE=L0000059</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20130619</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.June 19th, 2013 Hua-Zong (1) Yi-Zi-Di No.: 10200113941]]></沿革內容>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The National Research Institute of Chinese Medicine (hereinafter referred to as NRICM) is established by the Ministry of Health and Welfare to carry out the research on Chinese medicine.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[NRICM shall be in charge of the following matters:
1. To investigate theories of Chinese medicine and diagnostic criteria.
2. To assess therapeutic efficacy by Chinese medicine based therapeutic technique.
3. To study the origin, identification, preservation, and cultivation of Chinese material medica.
4. To study the extraction, fractionation, purification, and structure determination of bioactive constituents from Chinese medicine, and matters related to medicinal chemistry.
5. To evaluate pharmacology, toxicology, efficacy and safety-related issues of Chinese medicine.
6. To study the standardization and quality control of Chinese medicine and related preparations.
7. To collect, preserve, research on and develop for literature and classics of Chinese medicine.
8. To train professionals, and establish international collaborations, in the field of Chinese medicine
9. Other matters related to research of Chinese medicine.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[NRICM shall have one Director , ranked Senior 12th grade and will follow the precedent of appointing a candidate whose credentials include employment as university president (or higher) ; a Deputy Director is served by a Research Fellow.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[NRICM shall have one chief secretary, ranked Senior 10th grade.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[NRICM shall appoint Research Fellows , Associate Research Fellows, Assistant Research Fellows, and Research Assistants , following the relevant laws of Act of Governing the Appointment of University Faculty; including the retirement and compensation benefits following the relevant regulations of university faculty, all items of which shall be submitted to the Ministry of Health and Welfare for approval.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The official ranks, grades and headcounts of personnel at the NRICM shall be  regulated by a separate Personnel Establishment Table.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This Act shall come into force on the date prescribed by the Executive Yuan.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
