<法規>
<法規性質>法律</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Organic Act for Ministry of Health and Welfare</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>衛生福利部組織法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=L0000055</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20180613</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.ROC one hundred June 19, 2002 presidential order Decree Yi No. 10200113911
  Develop full announcement 8; enforcement date determined by the Executive Yuan
  ROC one hundred July 10, 2002 the Executive Yuan Zi No. 1022260532 granted comprehensive study issued Decree
  Cloth set from one hundred 23 July 2002 implementation
2.Amended on June 13, 2018]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Ministry of Health and Welfare (hereinafter referred to as the Ministry) is to be established by the Executive Yuan to engage in health and welfare affairs nationwide.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Ministry will be responsible for the following matters:
1.planning, management and supervision of health and welfare policies, regulations and resources, as well as relevant investigation, control, evaluation, policy promotion, technological development and international collaboration;
2.planning, management and supervision of policies regarding national health insurance, national pensions and long-term care financing;
3. planning, management and supervision of policies regarding fertility and child care.
4.planning, management and supervision of policies regarding social relief, social work, utilization of social resources and community development;
5.planning, management and supervision of policies regarding prevention of domestic violence, sexual assault and sexual harassment, as well as other protection services;
6.planning, management and supervision of policies regarding medical personnel, medical institutions, medical groups, national medical network and emergency care;
7.planning, management and supervision of policies regarding nursing, long-term care services and early intervention services;
8.planning, management, supervision and investigation of policies and regulations regarding medical treatment, health care, medical manpower training and disease prevention and control for indigenous people and offshore island residents;
9.planning, management and supervision of policies regarding mental health, prevention and control of mental illness, as well as prevention and control of substance addiction;
10.planning, management, supervision and investigation of policies regarding Chinese medicine development and folk therapies;
11.supervision, coordination and promotion regarding the subordinate Chinese medicine research organizations, Chinese medical care institutions and social welfare institutions;
12.planning, management, supervision and investigation of policies regarding oral health and medical care;
13.other health and welfare-related matters.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Ministry shall have one minister who is specially appointed, two deputy ministers ranked at Grade 14 for selected appointment, and one administrative deputy minister ranked at Grade 14 for selected appointment, if necessary, may be held by related Class I senior ranking medical personnel who has served for at least six years, in accordance with the Medical Personnel Act.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Ministry shall have a chief secretary ranked at Grade 12 for selected appointment.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The subordinate agencies of the Ministry and their duties will be as follows:
1.Centers for Disease Control: plan and implement the prevention and control of communicable diseases;
2.Food and Drug Administration: plan and implement the management, inspection and testing of food, pharmaceutical and cosmetic products;
3.National Health Insurance Administration: plan and implement national health insurance programs;
4.Health Promotion Administration: plan and carry out national health promotions and non-communicable disease prevention programs;
5.Social and Family Affairs Administration: plan and conduct affairs related to the welfare of senior citizens, people with physical and mental disabilities, women, children and youth as well as family support;
6.National Pension Bureau: implement the national pension system.
Prior to the establishment of the National Pension Bureau, its duties may be carried out by other government entities (or agencies).]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[If operational needs arise, the Ministry may deploy its personnel overseas for handling related matters in accordance with the Organization Act of Diplomatic Missions after obtaining the approval of the Executive Yuan.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[If necessary, the office of either director or deputy director of the medical affairs-related departments under the Ministry, as well as one fifth of the total number of counselors and senior specialists may be assumed by related Class I senior ranking medical personnel pursuant to the Medical Personnel Act.
The official ranks, grades and quotas for the positions within the Ministry will be stipulated separately via an organizational chart.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The effective date of this act shall be stipulated by the Executive Yuan in the form of orders.
The amended articles of the Act shall become effective on the date of promulgation.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
