<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Regulations for the Assessment and Approval Process of Hazardous Medical Device</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>危險性醫療儀器審查評估辦法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=L0020019</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20170811</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Appendix for Article 4.pdf]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000003820</下載網址>
  </檔案>
</附件>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated by Order Wei-Shu-Yi-Tzu No. 429940 of the Department of Health, Executive Yuan on July 7, 1983
2.Amended Title and Regulations Promulgated by Order Wei-Shu-Yi-Tzu No. 737925 of the Department of Health, Executive Yuan on July 22, 1988
3.Amended Title, Regulations and Appendix Promulgated by Order Wei-Shu-Yi-Tzu No. 0970201669 of the Department of Health, Executive Yuan on July 14, 2008
4.Amended Title, Regulations and Appendix Promulgated by Order Wei-Shu-Yi-Tzu No. 0980261439 of the Department of Health, Executive Yuan on August 12, 2009
5.Amended Appendix Promulgated by Order Wei-Shu-Yi-Tzu No. 0990262653 of the Department of Health, Executive Yuan on July 9, 2010
6.Amended Appendix Promulgated by Order Wei-Shu-Yi-Tzu No. 1061665908 of the Department of Health, Executive Yuan on August 11, 2017]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Guideline is stipulated pursuant to Paragraph 3, Article 93 of the Medical Care Act (hereinafter referred to as the Act).
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The so-called medical device which may cause hazard (hereinafter referred to as hazardous medical device) in the Act means that its use shall be strictly regulated, for any misuse may cause material harm to human health or environmental safety.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Hazardous medical device shall be kept and employed by designated physicians in charge; operators shall undertake specialized training.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Information and criteria for the types of hazardous medical device, physicians in charge, medical institution which may install such device (hereinafter referred to as the installed institution) are shown in the Appendix.
The applicable symptoms of hazardous medical device, qualification and condition for operators, and other issues shall comply with the Regulation Governing the Application of Specific Medical Examination Technique and Medical Device.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[In order to install hazardous medical device, the installed institution shall apply to the central authority with an application form and documents below; the institution may install such device after the review and approval.
1. The registration license of the medical institution and a copy of the supporting documents set forth in the Appendix;
2. A copy of the physician- in- charge qualification;
3. The diagram and manual of the device;
4. A copy of the medical device’s import or manufacture permit.
If for special reasons, the permit specified in Subparagraph 4 shall be applied together along with the building expanding project and cannot be acquired in advance, the central authority may agree to replace it with the import documents.
The central authority may request the installed institution to submit a report on the hazardous medical device approved in Paragraph 1.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The central authority may invite experts or authorize professional groups to review the application of hazardous medical device.
The central authority may announce restrictions on the number of hazardous medical device installed in a single medical region or sub-medical region.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[In case the hazardous medical device is wasted or no longer in use, the installed institute shall report to the central authority within 30 days for recordation.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Guideline is effective upon promulgation.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
