<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Fee-charging Standards for Licensure Exam Application for Nurse Practitioners</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>專科護理師申請甄審收費標準</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=L0020126</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20210512</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.All the four articles were established and promulgated as per the Department of Health's Order Wei-Shu-Zhao-Zi No. 0952800889 dated June 29, 2006; the four articles came into effect on the date of promulgation.
2.The provisions of Article 2 were amended and promulgated as per the Department of Health's Order Wei-Shu-Zhao-Zi No. 0962802216 dated November 13, 2007.
3.The title and the provisions of Articles 2 and 3 were amended and promulgated as per the Ministry of Health and Welfare's Order Wei-Bu-Zhao-Zi No. 1101560212 dated May 12, 2021 (the previous title: Fee Standard for Applications for Examination of Nurse Practitioners Specializing in Internal Medicine and Surgery; the new title: Fee-charging Standards for Licensure Exam Application for Nurse Practitioners).
]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This Standard is established in accordance with Article 10 of the Charges and Fees Act.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This Standard is applicable to the following:
1. Fees for applying for written and oral tests in accordance with the Regulations Governing Specialties and Examination of Nurse Practitioner;
2. Fees incurred by investigation of certificate renewal applications submitted in accordance with the Regulations Governing Specialties and Examination of Nurse Practitioner.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The amount of fees charged for licensure exam application for nurse practitioners is as follows:
1. NT$1,500 per person for each written test;
2. NT$2,000 per person for each oral test;
3. NT$500 per person for each nurse practitioner certificate renewal investigation.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This Standard shall come into effect on the date of promulgation.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
