<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Sanitation Standard for Processing Aids</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>加工助劑衛生標準</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawContent.aspx?PCODE=L0040131</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20160217</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件>
  <下載網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/Law/law_getfile.ashx?FileId=0000003153</下載網址>
</附件>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.MOHW Food No. 1051300445Announced. 02/17/2016]]></沿革內容>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Standards are prescribed in accordance with the provisions ofArticle 17 of the Act Governing Food Safety and Sanitation.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Processing aid means any substance or material, not including apparatus or utensils, and not consumed as afood ingredient by itself, intentionally used in the processing of raw materials, foods or its ingredients, to fulfilla certain technological purpose during treatment or processing and which may result in the non-intentional butunavoidable presence of residues or derivatives in the final product.Any residues of processing aids remaining in the food after processing should not perform a technological function in the final product.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The quantity of the substance used as processing aid shall be limited to the lowest achievable level necessary toaccomplish its desired technological purpose. Residues or derivatives of the substance remaining in food should be reduced to the extentreasonably achievable and should not pose any health risk.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The use of processing aids shall meet appendix 1.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The specification of processing aids shall meet appendix 2.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Standards shall be implemented from the date of promulgation.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
