<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Sanitation Standard for Contaminants and Toxins in Food</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>食品中污染物質及毒素衛生標準</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=L0040138</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20180508</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Appendix 1.pdf]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000004164</下載網址>
  </檔案>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Appendix 2.pdf]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000004165</下載網址>
  </檔案>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Appendix 3.pdf]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000004166</下載網址>
  </檔案>
</附件>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Full text including 6 articles promulgated per MOHW Food No. 1071300778 on May 8, 2018, which shall be implemented from January 1, 2019.]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This Standard is prescribed in accordance with the provision of Article 17 of the Act Governing Food Safety and Sanitation.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The contaminants in this standard shall mean the substance not intentionally added to food, which present in food as a result of production or pollution during the manufacturing, processing, preparing, packaging, transportation, storage, or selling, or as a result of environmental contamination. It does not include insect fragments, hairs and other extraneous matters.
The toxins in this standard include the mycotoxins, marine bio-toxins and natural toxins in plant origin.
The scope of this standard does not include the residues of pesticides, veterinary drugs and processing aids; the tolerance of atomic dust and radioactivity contamination, polychlorinated biphenyl and dioxins; and the microorganisms and microbial toxins that are within the sanitation standard for microbiological in foods.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The maximum levels of metals in food shall meet the standard on Appendix 1.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The maximum levels of mycotoxins in food shall meet the standard on Appendix 2.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The maximum levels of other contaminants and toxins in food shall meet the standard on Appendix 3.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This standard shall be implemented from January 1, 2019.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
