<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Penalty Standards of Fine under Paragraph 1, Article 44 of the Act Governing Food Safety and Sanitation</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>食品安全衛生管理法第四十四條第一項罰鍰裁罰標準</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=L0040134</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20160512</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件>
  <下載網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000003189</下載網址>
  <下載網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000003190</下載網址>
  <下載網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000003191</下載網址>
  <下載網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000003192</下載網址>
  <下載網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000003193</下載網址>
  <下載網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000003194</下載網址>
  <下載網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000003195</下載網址>
  <下載網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000003196</下載網址>
</附件>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.MOHW Food No. 1052000998 promulgated, May 12, 2016.]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Standards are prescribed in accordance with Paragraph 2, Article 44 of the Act Governing Food Safety and Sanitation (hereinafter “the Act”).]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Standards are applicable to fines imposed in accordance with Paragraph 1, Article 44 of the Act.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Standards for fines imposed for violation of Paragraph 1, Article 8 of the Act are provided in Appendix 1.
The Standards for fines imposed for violation of Paragraph 2, Article 8 of the Act are provided in Appendix 2.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Standards for fines imposed for violation of Subparagraph 1, 2, 6, 8 or 9, Paragraph 1, Article 15 or Subparagraphs 2 to 4, Article 16 of the Act are provided in Appendix 3.
The Standards for fines imposed for violation of Subparagraph 3, 7 or 10, Paragraph 1, Article 15 or Subparagraph 1, Article 16 of the Act are provided in Appendix 4.
The Standards for fines imposed for violation of Subparagraph 4, Paragraph 1, Article 15 of the Act are provided in Appendix 5.
The Standards for fines imposed for violation of Subparagraph 5, Paragraph 1, Article 15 or Paragraph 4, Article 15 of the Act are provided in Appendix 6.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Standards for fines imposed for incompliance with order by the competent authority to recover or destruction in accordance to Paragraph 2, Article 52 of the Act are provided in Appendix 7.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Standards for fines imposed for violation of the public announcement by the central competent authority to ban the manufacture, sale, import or export in accordance to Paragraph 1, Article 54 of the Act are provided in Appendix 8.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[To review and determine the facts of violations and the amounts of fines to be imposed, the competent authority may invite scholars, experts and representatives from authorities to form a review committee.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[When a fine is imposed, the number of administrative penalty shall be determined in accordance to the Criteria for Determining the Number of Administrative Penalty of the Act Governing Food Safety and Sanitation.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Standards shall be implemented from the date of promulgation.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
