<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Regulation for the implementation of Smoking Cessation Education</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>戒菸教育實施辦法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=L0070014</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20200108</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated on February 18, 1998
2.Amended on February 22, 2008
3.Amended on January 8, 2020]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulations are stipulated in accordance with Paragraph 3 of Article 28 of the Tobacco Hazards Prevention Act.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Smoking cessation education includes school-based smoking cessation education, outside-of-school smoking cessation education, and correction agency smoking cessation education.
Correction agency smoking cessation education is defined as smoking cessation education targeting inmates incarcerated in correction agencies.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[School-based and correction agencies smoking cessation education shall be executed by respective schools and correction agencies; outside-of-school smoking cessation education shall be executed by the local competent authority.
The aforementioned smoking cessation education may be entrusted to relevant agencies or institutions and organizations for execution and assistance.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Schools, correction agencies and local competent authorities shall designate a person in charge of smoking cessation education.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Smoking cessation education shall include knowledge regarding tobacco hazards, anti-smoking, refusal skills, motivation for smoking cessation and other measures relevant to smoking cessation.
Measures pursuant to the preceding smoking cessation education refers to lectures and consultation guidance, which may be implemented through telecommunication networks, computer networks and other media.
The length of the smoking cessation education shall be two hours in principle. However, the length may be extended for persons under the age of eighteen who are guilty of repeating the violation within one year.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The competent authority may present awards to commend excellent institutes, groups, agencies, and individuals which provide smoking cessation education programs and smoking cessation counseling services.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The budget for these regulations shall be arranged by municipality or county government.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulations shall come into force as of the day of its promulgation.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
