<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Regulations for the Implementation of Smoking Cessation Education</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>戒菸教育實施辦法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=L0070014</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20230322</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated on February 18, 1998
2.Amended on February 22, 2008
3.Amended on January 8, 2020
4. Amended on March 22, 2023.
]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulations are enacted in accordance with Article 42 Paragraph 3 of the Tobacco Hazards Prevention Act (hereinafter referred to as "this Act").]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Smoking cessation education includes in-school smoking cessation education, outside-school smoking cessation education, and smoking cessation education at correctional institutions.
Smoking cessation education at correctional institutions is targeted at imprisoned persons.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[In-school smoking cessation education and smoking cessation education at correctional institutions shall be conducted by schools and correctional institutions. Outside-school smoking cessation education shall be carried out by the competent authorities of the respective special municipalities and counties (cities).
The aforesaid smoking cessation education activities may be delegated to any relevant authorities, institutions, or bodies as required.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Schools, correctional institutions, and competent authorities of special municipalities or counties (cities) shall designate qualified persons to deliver smoking cessation education.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The contents of smoking cessation education shall include knowledge of the health risks of tobacco, the methods of preventing or refusing tobacco, enhancement of awareness of smoking cessation, and other matters related to smoking cessation.
Smoking cessation education may be implemented via class seminars, consultations, instruction, electronic communication, the internet, or other communication media.
Smoking cessation education sessions shall generally last for not less than two hours. Smoking cessation education sessions shall be extended for any person aged under 20 years age who violates Paragraph 1 of Article 16 of the Act within one year following their initial violation.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Regulations shall be enforced on March 22, 2023.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
