<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Regulations for Signs and Warnings at Places for Selling Tobacco Products</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>販賣菸品場所標示及展示管理辦法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=L0070033</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20230322</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Attached Diagram under Article 2.pdf]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000007978</下載網址>
  </檔案>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Attached Diagram under Article 2.doc]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000007979</下載網址>
  </檔案>
</附件>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1. Promulgated on June 23, 2008.
2. Amended on March 22, 2023.
]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulations are enacted in accordance with Article 13 Paragraph 3 of the Tobacco Hazards Prevention Act.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Places for selling tobacco products shall display warning graphics and texts as indicated in the attached diagram at prominent spots, in one of the two sizes specified, except for places selling exclusively tobacco and alcohol products or tobacco and alcohol selling places at airports or ports, which shall display warning signs at the entrance.
Such warnings and signs shall be clearly visible to consumers and may not be obstructed in any way. The attached graphics shall be displayed alongside tobacco products.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The display of tobacco products in the aforesaid places shall be limited to packaged tobacco products, containers, or grapchics no larger than the physical products.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Tobacco products shall be displayed in the following manner:
1.	At an elevation of more than 1.3 meters above the floor, and at a distance of more than 2 meters from the checkout counter, except for products displayed behind a staffed counter.
2.	The total display area for tobacco products within a place for selling tobacco products shall be no larger than 2 square meters.
3.	Each item shall be displayed only in the minimum packing unit or image sizes.
4.	No tobacco product may be displayed directly toward the exterior, except those displayed more than 2 meters away from the external area.
5.	Health warnings on tobacco product containers shall be clearly legible to consumers.
6.	The price of tobacco products shall be printed in black characters on a white background in a uniform font and size.
Places marked as exceptions in Paragraph 1 of Article 2 are not subject to sub-paragraphs 1, 2, 3, and 6 in the previous paragraph.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Tobacco products shall not be displayed alongside electronic screens, animations, moving backgrounds, audio playbacks, fragrant, lightning effects, or by other means to attract consumers' attention.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[A place for selling tobacco products, when operated by a single business, shall only have one area displaying tobacco products.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Regulations shall be enforced on June 22, 2023.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
