<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Regulations for Query on Kinship of Children of Assisted Reproduction</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>人工生殖子女親屬關係查詢辦法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawContent.aspx?PCODE=L0070025</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20180821</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件>
  <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/Law/law_getfile.ashx?FileId=0000004332</下載網址>
  <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/Law/law_getfile.ashx?FileId=0000004333</下載網址>
</附件>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated by Shu-Sho-Guo-Tzu Order No.0960400552 on June 23, 2007
2.Modified by Shu-Sho-Guo-Tzu Order No.0960401455 on January 11, 2008
3.Modified by Shu-Sho-Guo-Tzu Order No.1000401977 on October 20, 2011
4.Modified by Bu-Sho-Guo-Tzu Letter No.1020410297 on February 13, 2014.
5.Modified by Bu-Sho-Guo-Tzu Letter No.1030403104 on February 2, 2015.
6.A total of 7 articles was amended and promulgated according to the Order of Health and Welfare Department Wei-Shou-Guo-Zhi No. 1070402117 on August 21, 2018 and will be implemented from October 1, 2018.]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulations are prescribed pursuant to Article 29, Paragraph 2 of the Artificial Reproduction Act (herein referred to as this Act).
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Since 2008, children registered at the competent authority and conceived through the use of donated reproductive cells (hereinafter referred to as children conceived through assisted reproduction) or their statutory agents may apply for a Certificate of Birth through Artificial Reproduction from the competent authority if they satisfy one of the conditions specified in Article 29, Paragraph 1.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[If a person conceived through assisted reproduction plans to get married, adopt a child or be adopted, the person's marriage partner, adoptee or adoptive parent may submit the Certificate of Birth through Assisted Reproduction to the household registration office to apply for a Certificate for Degree of Kinship according to the Application and Management Regulations for Degree of Kinship.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[A child conceived through assisted reproduction or their statutory agents may submit the following documents according to Article 29, Paragraph 1 of the Act to apply to the competent authority for a query:
1. The applicant’s national ID card; foreigners should attach a document verifying his/ her ID card number or passport number.
2. Children of Assisted Reproduction Kinship Query Application Form (see attached forms 1 or 2).
3. Relevant documents for verification listed in the previous articles.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The competent authority shall notify the applicant the results of his/her query in writing within 30 days upon receiving the application; if necessary, the competent authority may notify the applicant to submit the correct documents within a prescribed period; failure to do so will result in a rejection of query.
The notification stated in the previous paragraph is limited to any of the conditions specified in Article 29, Paragraph 1.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The competent authority may assign the Health Promotion Administration of Ministry of Health and Welfare or relevant legal persons or groups to perform the query work provided in the regulations.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulations will be implemented from October 1, 2018.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
