<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Regulations Governing the Expenses Reduction, Exemption or Subsidy of Genetic Health Measures</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>優生保健措施減免或補助費用辦法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=L0070007</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20141103</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Table 1.pdf]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000005459</下載網址>
  </檔案>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Table 2.pdf]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000005460</下載網址>
  </檔案>
</附件>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1. Promulgated by Wei-Shu-Guo-Jian-Tzu Order No.0910016365 on December 10, 2002
2. Modified by Shu-Sho-Guo-Tzu Order No.0950400285 on April 19, 2006
3. Full text was amended and promulgated under the Ministry of Health and Welfare Order, Bu-Shou-Guo-Tzu No.10304024203 on November 3, 2014 and was taken effective on January 1, 2014.]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These regulations are formulated in accordance with the provisions stipulated in Paragraph 2, Article 16 of the Genetic Health Act.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The genetic health measures for the expenses reduction, exemption or subsidy of these regulations are as follows:
1. Examinations for genetic diseases:
(1)Neonatal screening for inborn errors of metabolism identified by the central competent authority.
(2)Confirmatory diagnosis for neonatal screening for inborn errors of metabolism positive cases identified by the central competent authority.
(3)Thalassemia gene analysis.
(4)Blood cytogenetic testing.
(5)Prenatal genetic diagnosis, including cytogenetic testing, genetic testing, biochemical genetics or other prenatal genetic testing.
(6)Confirmatory diagnosis for the abortive tissue or the stillbirth.
(7)Other genetic disease examinations identified by the central competent authority.
2. Psychiatric disease examinations.
3. Fertility regulation services: intrauterine contraceptive device.
4. Surgical sterilization.
5. Induced abortion.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Those who are eligible for the previous genetic health measures shall be exempted from their expenses.
For the exempted expenses specified in the preceding paragraph, institutions that handle the genetic health measures may apply for the subsidies from the competent authorities.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Regulations governing the items, eligible recipients and providers, amount of the expenses reduction or exemption, and the competent authorities for receiving the subsidy claims for the genetic health measures mentioned in
Article 2 are prescribed in Table 1.
The areas with limited medical resources for genetic health measures referred to in Table 1 of the preceding paragraph are prescribed in Table 2.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[To apply for the subsidies of expense exemption or reduction of genetic health measures, the institutions shall prepare the application forms, the case records and other relevant documents.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[For the genetic health measures expenses subsidized under the Regulations, the competent agencies of central and municipal governments shall designate annual budgets.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Regulations takes effect from the date of its promulgation.
Articles of the Regulations amended and promulgated on April 19, 2006 shall take effective on July1, 2006. Articles of the Regulations amended and promulgated on November 3, 2013 shall take effective on January 1, 2014.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
