<法規>
<法規性質>法律</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Organization Act of the Taiwan Biodiversity Research Institute, Ministry of Agriculture</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>農業部生物多樣性研究所組織法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=M0000064</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20230531</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated by Presidential Order Hua-Tzong (1) Yi No. 11200045611 on May 31, 2023]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[In order to handle matters related to biodiversity research, the Ministry of Agriculture hereby establishes the Taiwan Biodiversity Research Institute (hereafter TBRI).]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The TBRI shall be in charge of the following matters:
1. Research related to the genetic diversity of wildlife.
2. Research related to species diversity of wildlife.
3. Research related to ecosystem diversity.
4. Research related to agricultural biodiversity.
5. Research related to management of bioresources and sustainability of biodiversity.
6. Research related to extension services for popular science as well as international cooperation connected with biodiversity.
7. Other research matters related to biodiversity.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The TBRI shall have one director with the rank of senior civil servant Grade 12 to 13 and one deputy director, to hold the post in a concurrent capacity.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The TBRI shall have one chief secretary, to hold the post in a concurrent capacity.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[When necessary, the positions of researcher, associate researcher, and assistant researcher at the TBRI shall be filled in accordance with relevant provisions of the “Act Governing the Appointment of Educators.” Their retirement and pensions shall be handled in accordance with relevant provisions for teachers, and shall be reported to the Ministry of Agriculture for approval.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The number of personnel in the TBRI and their ranks and grades shall be stipulated in a separate staffing chart.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Executive Yuan shall determine the date this Act comes into effect.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
