<法規>
<法規性質>法律</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Organization Act of the Fisheries Research Institute, Ministry of Agriculture</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>農業部水產試驗所組織法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=M0000060</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20230531</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated by Presidential Order Hua-Tzong (1) Yi No. 11200045571 on May 31, 2023]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[In order to handle matters related to fisheries science and research, the Ministry of Agriculture hereby establishes the Fisheries Research Institute (hereafter FRI).]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The FRI shall be in charge of the following matters:
1. Research related to aquatic organisms, their ecosystems, and their restoration, as well as fishing ground environments and fisheries resources, technology, and management.
2. Research related to the genetics, breeding, biology, reproduction and rearing technologies, biotechnology, genetic resources, bioinformation, and disease prevention for aquatic organisms.
3. Research related to the nutritional requirements, feed, additives, live feed, and applied microbiology of aquatic organisms.
4. Research related to, and quality testing for, the processing, freshness preservation, functional ingredients, and resource circular reuse of aquatic organisms.
5. Protection, management, and cross-domain integrated application of the results of R&D in fisheries technologies.
6. Education about, and promotion of, fisheries technologies; manpower training; business incubation; and domestic and international technical exchanges and cooperation.
7. Operational planning and management of fisheries scientific vessels, scientific facilities for isolation of genetically modified aquatic organisms, germplasm banks for aquatic organisms, seafood testing centers, and affiliated aquariums.
8. Other science and research matters related to fisheries.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The FRI shall have one director with the rank of senior civil servant Grade 12 to 13 and one deputy director, to hold the post in a concurrent capacity.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The FRI shall have one chief secretary, to hold the post in a concurrent capacity.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[When necessary, the positions of researcher, associate researcher, and assistant researcher at the FRI shall be filled in accordance with relevant provisions of the “Act Governing the Appointment of Educators.” Their retirement and pensions shall be handled in accordance with relevant provisions for teachers, and shall be reported to the Ministry of Agriculture for approval.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The number of personnel in the FRI and their ranks and grades shall be stipulated in a separate staffing chart.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Executive Yuan shall determine the date this Act comes into effect.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
