<法規>
<法規性質>法律</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Organization Act of the Taiwan Forestry Research Institute, Ministry of Agriculture</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>農業部林業試驗所組織法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=M0000059</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20230531</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated by Presidential Order Hua-Tzong (1) Yi No. 11200045561 on May 31, 2023]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[In order to handle matters related to forestry science and research, the Ministry of Agriculture hereby establishes the Taiwan Forestry Research Institute (hereafter TFRI).]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The TFRI shall be in charge of the following matters:
1. Research related to forestry management on agricultural land, agroforestry, wood improvement, technology for economic afforestation, forestry biotechnology, cultivation of main products and by-products of forest, forest soil, and nutrient cycling.
2. Experiment and research related to management of public and private forests, development of forest industries, and quantification of forest carbon emissions reduction.
3. Experiment and research related to urban forestry and ecology, urban and rural green beautification, rural eco-environment, and forest therapy.
4. Technical research, development, and promotion related to tree protection, tree health management, and biological control of harmful organisms.
5. Operation and management of national botanical gardens, herbariums, forest germplasm banks, forest germplasm preservation gardens, and related facilities.
6. Experiment and research related to the basic properties of main products and by-products of forest, the processing and utilization of such products, the betterment  of wood and bamboo materials, and  products research as well as development.
7. Research related to the use of the chemical components of forest products, wood and bamboo product preservation, pulping and paper-making, biomass material, biomass energy, and the development and utilization of high value-added forest products.
8. Research related to the physiography, hydrology, meteorology, environmental impacts and logging, forest road maintenance within forest watersheds, and other related research matters.
9. Education and outreach using the results of forestry research, promotion of demonstration activities, information management, intellectual property rights management and application, forestry technology exchange and cooperation, and the operations and management of experimental forest.
10. Other experiment and research matters related to forestry.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The TFRI shall have one director with the rank of senior civil servant Grade 12 to 13 and one deputy director, to hold the post in a concurrent capacity.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The TFRI shall have one chief secretary, to hold the post in a concurrent capacity.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[When necessary, the positions of researcher, associate researcher, and assistant researcher at the TFRI shall be filled in accordance with relevant provisions of the “Act Governing the Appointment of Educators.” Their retirement and pensions shall be handled in accordance with relevant provisions for teachers, and shall be reported to the Ministry of Agriculture for approval.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The number of personnel in the TFRI and their ranks and grades shall be stipulated in a separate staffing chart.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Executive Yuan shall determine the date this Act comes into effect.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
