<法規>
<法規性質>法律</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Organization Act of the Agricultural Finance Agency, Ministry of Agriculture</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>農業部農業金融署組織法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=M0000056</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20230531</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated by Presidential Order Hua-Tzong (1) Yi No. 11200045531 on May 31, 2023]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[In order to handle matters related to agricultural finance and agricultural insurance, the Ministry of Agriculture hereby establishes the Agricultural Finance Agency  (hereafter AFNA).]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The AFNA shall be in charge of the following matters:
1. Planning, research, formulation, implementation, and supervision of policies, laws, and regulations for agricultural finance and agricultural insurance.
2. Planning and supervision of measures for monitoring, management, inspection, guidance, assessment, contact, coordination, and compliance of agricultural financial institutions.
3. Planning, supervision, guidance, and management of policy-oriented special agricultural loans and the interest differential subsidy policy.
4. Planning, supervision, and management of the agricultural credit guarantee system.
5. Planning, research, formulation, implementation, contact, and coordination of the agricultural insurance system.
6. Planning, stipulation, implementation, and monitoring of policies and programs for agricultural financial education and training.
7. Planning, promotion, coordination, and monitoring of the open data policy for agricultural financial information.
8. Other matters related to agricultural finance and agricultural insurance.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The AFNA shall have one director-general with the rank of senior civil servant Grade 13 and two deputy directors-general with the rank of senior civil servant Grade 12.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The AFNA shall have a chief secretary with the rank of senior civil servant Grade 11.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The number of personnel in the AFNA and their ranks and grades shall be stipulated in a separate staffing chart.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Executive Yuan shall determine the date this Act comes into effect.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
