<法規>
<法規性質>法律</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Organization Act of the Fisheries Agency, Ministry of Agriculture</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>農業部漁業署組織法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=M0000051</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20230531</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated by Presidential Order Hua-Tzong (1) Yi No. 11200045481 on May 31, 2023]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[In order to handle fisheries matters, the Ministry of Agriculture hereby establishes the Fisheries Agency (hereafter FA).]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The FA shall be in charge of the following matters:
1. Planning, research, formulation, promotion, and supervision of policies, laws, and regulations for fisheries.
2. Planning, implementation, and supervision of measures to manage marine resources conservation, as well as surveys, assessments, and scientific research related to fisheries.
3. Planning, coordination, promotion, and supervision of policies for management of fishing vessels and crew members.
4. Planning, coordination, and promotion of international fisheries affairs and fisheries matters involving foreign countries or foreign nationals.
5. Planning, coordination, promotion, and supervision of management and development of the aquaculture industry.
6. Planning, research, formulation, management, and guidance of policies, laws, and regulations for guidance of fishermen’s (fisheries industry) organizations.
7. Planning, coordination, promotion, and supervision of marketing, processing, and food safety of aquatic products.
8. Planning, promotion, and supervision of fishing harbors and other fisheries industry facilities.
9. Supervision, coordination, and promotion of fisheries radio broadcasting and fisheries information and communication organizations.
10. Other fisheries-related matters.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The FA shall have one director-general with the rank of senior civil servant Grade 13 and two deputy directors-general with the rank of senior civil servant Grade 12.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The FA shall have a chief secretary with the rank of senior civil servant Grade 11.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The FA may establish branch offices to meet operational needs.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[To meet operational needs, the FA may ask for approval from the Executive Yuan to dispatch personnel overseas to handle relevant matters; such assignments shall be handled on the basis of the “Organization Act of Diplomatic Missions of the Republic of China.”]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The number of personnel in the FA and their ranks and grades shall be stipulated in a separate staffing chart.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Executive Yuan shall determine the date this Act comes into effect.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
