<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>The Requirements and Facility Standards for the Qualification of Plant Seed Enterprises</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>種苗業者應具備條件及設備標準</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=M0030026</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20050629</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Full text of 9 articles enacted and promulgated on March 2, 1990 by Council of Agriculture, Executive Yuan Order 79 Nung-Liang-Tzu No. 9020046A
2.Article 7-1 added and promulgated on September 30, 2003 by Council of Agriculture, Executive Yuan Order 92 Nung-Liang-Tzu No. 0920021472
3.Full text of 8 articles amended and promulgated on June 29, 2005 by Council of Agriculture, Executive Yuan Order Nung-Shou-Liang-Tzu No. 0941057956; original name: "Plant Seed Enterprise Facility and Marking Regulations" revised as "The Requirements and Facility Standards for the Qualification of Plant Seed Enterprises"]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Standards are enacted in accordance with Article 44, Paragraph 2 of the Plant Variety and Plant Seed Act.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[A plant seed enterprise shall possess the following qualifications: 
1. It must be a natural person or juristic person.
2. It must have a fixed place of business.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[A plant seed enterprise shall state its type of business from among the following items when applying for registration: 
1. breeding;
2. propagation of seeds and nursery stock;
3. export of seeds and nursery stock;
4. import of seeds and nursery stock;
5. sale of seeds and nursery stock; and 
6. propagation, import/export, or sale of transgenic plant seed.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[A plant seed enterprise engaged in breeding or propagation shall possess the following equipments: 
1. Breeding enterprises:
(1) Low-temperature refrigeration equipment: Refrigerators or coolers for the storage of plant seed materials, tools, or chemicals, etc. 
(2) Disinfection or sterilization equipment: Equipment needed to prevent contamination from pathogens during operating processes. 
2. Propagation enterprises: 
(1) Seed propagation enterprises: 
a. Wind sorting machines or other separation equipment for seed.
b. Sealing machines or jar sealing machines.
c. Seed storage equipments such as low-temperature (below 15°C) dry storage chambers (greater than 1 cubic meter) and sealed seed barrels holding over 200 kg of seed.
d. Quality inspection equipments for checking seed cleanliness and germination percentage, etc. 
e. Weighing machines. 
(2) Nursery stock propagation enterprises: 
a. Nursery: Over 1,000 square meters. 
b. Refrigeration equipment: More than one low-temperature (below 15°C) constant temperature chamber or refrigerator. 
c. Disinfection equipment: High-temperature and high-pressure sterilizer or other disinfection equipments.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Plant seed enterprises engaging in the propagation, import/export, or sale of transgenic plant seed shall register their business items to the competent authorities of the regions where the transgenic plant seeds to be deliberately released. 
To avoid contamination with non-transgenic plants, the plant seed enterprise referred to in the preceding Paragraph shall possess dedicated management personnel and adopt relevant management measures.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[A plant seed enterprise referred to in the preceding Article shall use a unitary identification number for indexing, possess a registration book, and record the following information: 
1. names of transgenic plants; 
2. sources of transgenic plants; 
3. Propagators and their propagation records; 
4. whereabouts of sold transgenic plants; 
5. transgenic plant transaction dates and quantities; and
6. transgenic plant transaction receipts or proof.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The registration book referred to in the preceding Article shall be preserved for at least five years for inspection by the competent authority when necessary. 
The competent authority shall preserve the confidentiality of any information involving business secrets referred to in the preceding Paragraph.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Standards shall take effect on the day this Act is enforced.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
