<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Regulations Governing Receipts, Expenditures, Custody And Utilization Of The Forest Businesses Development Fund</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>林務發展基金收支保管及運用辦法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=M0040017</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20070910</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>廢</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated on December 22, 2000
2.Abolished on September 10, 2007]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[For the purpose of promoting the development of forest recreation business and public and/or private forestry businesses, a special forest businesses development fund is established (hereinafter "Fund") and these Regulations are enacted accordingly pursuant to the provisions of Article 21 of the Budget Act.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Except as otherwise provided by laws and regulations, the receipts, expenditures, custody and utilization of the Fund shall be governed by these Regulations.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Fund belongs to the special fund provided in subparagraph two of the first paragraph of Article 4 of the Budget Act and shall prepare budget for its subordinated units.　The Council of Agriculture, Executive Yuan is the competent authority of the Fund with the Taiwan Forestry Bureau, Council of Agriculture, Executive Yuan acting as the regulatory agency.　]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The sources of funding of the Fund are as follows:
1. Public fund allocated in accordance with government budgeting procedures;
2. Income from the operation of forest recreation and forest railway businesses;
3. Income from the operation of forest by-products;
4. Interest income of the Fund;
5. Other relevant sources of income.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Fund shall be used to
1. Cover expenditures arising from the operation of forest recreation and forest railway businesses;
2. Cover expenditures arising from the operation of forest by-products;
3. Provide general reforestation loans;
4. Loans to hsiang (town, city) administration offices for public reforestation;
5. Cover expenditures arising from advertising and promoting forest public welfare and forest recreation;
6. Cover administration and general affairs expenditures;
7. Cover other relevant expenditures.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The custody and utilization of the Fund shall lay stress on profitability and security.　Savings shall be governed by the National Treasury Law and the relevant laws and regulations.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Fund may be used to purchase government bonds, treasury bills, or other short-term bills to meet operation needs.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The drawing-up and execution of budgets, and the preparation of the financial statements of the Fund shall be in accordance with the Budget Act, the Accounting Act, the Financial Statement Act, the Audit Act and the relevant laws and regulations.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[An accounting system concerning the accounting of the Fund shall be established in accordance with the relevant regulations.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 10</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The surplus of the Fund (if any) as of the end of each year may be allocated to the Fund or treated as undistributed surplus in accordance with the budgeting procedures.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 11</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The accounting of the Fund shall be finalized upon termination of the Fund and the remaining rights and interests shall be submitted to the National Treasury.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 12</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulations shall come into force on the day of promulgation.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
