<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Regulations on the Reporting of Fishing Operations of Foreign Flag Fishing Vessels Invested by Nationals of the Republic of China</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>投資經營非我國籍漁船作業資料申報辦法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawContent.aspx?PCODE=M0050040</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20180301</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件>
  <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/Law/law_getfile.ashx?FileId=0000004115</下載網址>
  <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/Law/law_getfile.ashx?FileId=0000004116</下載網址>
</附件>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated by the Council of Agriculture, Executive Yuan on 16 October 2009 under Order No. Nung-Yu-Tzu 0981325550.
2.Article 3 amended and promulgated by the Council of Agriculture, Executive Yuan on 27 March 2017 under Order No. Nung-Yu-Tzu 1061333787.
3.Article 3 amended and promulgated by the Council of Agriculture, Executive Yuan on 1 March 2018 under Order No. Nung-Yu-Tzu 1071332734.]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulations are hereby established pursuant to Article 5, paragraph 2 of the Act to Govern Investment in the Operation of Foreign Flag Fishing Vessels.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Any national of the Republic of China that has been authorized to invest in or operate a foreign flag fishing vessel fishing in sea areas beyond national jurisdiction shall report, in electronic or written form, between 1 and 28 February every year its fishing operations of the preceding year to the competent authority.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[For vessels that catch fishes, the reporting of fishing operations as referred to in Article 2 shall include the following items, and the reporting format is as shown in Appendix 1:
(1)Fishing period;
(2)Fishery type;
(3)Target species;
(4)Catch amount;
(5)Time for the sale of catch, sale amount, and buying countries;
(6)Information on the employment of nationals of the Republic of China onboard.
For carrier vessels that transport catches or fisheries products, the reporting of fishing operations as referred to in Article 2 shall include the following items, and the reporting format is as shown in Appendix 2:
(1)Transshipment period;
(2)The name and nationality of any fishing vessel wherefrom catches were transshipped;
(3)Maine species transshipped;
(4)Amount of catches or fisheries products transshipped;
(5)Information on the employment of nationals of the Republic of China onboard.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulations shall become effective upon promulgation.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
