<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Regulations for Fishing Vessels Conducting Exploratory Squid Jigging Fishery in the Indian Ocean</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>漁船赴印度洋從事探勘魷釣漁撈作業管理辦法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=M0050067</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20191007</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.The full text of 14 articles promulgated on 7 October 2019 by the Council of Agriculture, Executive Yuan under Order No. Nung-yu-tzu 1081337457A.]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulations are hereby established pursuant to Article 31, paragraph 3 of the Act for Distant Water Fisheries (hereinafter referred to as “the Act”).]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The fishing area for fishing vessels proceeding to the Indian Ocean for exploratory squid jigging fishery to develop new fishing ground shall be limited to the Indian Ocean north of 20°N, and between 50°E to 68°E, but exclude the high risk area of piracy stipulated in subparagraph (1) of Article 4, paragraph 1 of the Regulations for Tuna Longline Fishing Vessels Proceeding to the Indian Ocean for Fishing Operation.
The maximum number of fishing vessels conducting exploratory squird jigging fishery (hereinafter referred to as “exploratory fishing vessels) shall be limited to ten.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Any exploratory fishing vessel shall meet the following requirements:
(1)A valid fishing license has been obtained with squid jigging registered as the main fishery.
(2)The distant water fisheries operator concerned shall be a member of the Taiwan Squid Fishery Association (hereinafter referred to as “the Squid Association”)]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Any distant water fisheries operator applying for conducting exploratory squid jigging fishery in the Indian Ocean shall submit an exploratory fishing plan together with a valid fishing license of directed fishery, and register to the Squid Association before 15 October 2019. The Squid Association shall compile and submit applications to the competent authority by October 20 of the current year.
The exploratory fishing plan as referred to in the preceding paragraph shall specify the following:
(1)The fishing area and depth.
(2)The fishing period.
(3)The fishing gear, type of squid jigging machine, numbers of lines and hooks, and type(s) of fishing lure.
(4)Species to be harvested.
(5)Method(s) for processing catch.
(6)Arrangement for unloading catch.
(7)Expected catch amount.
In the event that the number of applications as referred to in paragraph 1 exceeds the limit on vessel numbers as referred to in Article 2, paragraph 2, the Squid Association shall draw lots to decide the priority in an equitable and impartial manner.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[A permit of exploratory squid jigging fishery in the Indian Ocean will be issued after the application as referred to in Article 4 as well as the exploratory fishing plan have been approved by the competent authority.
The maximum validity period of the permit shall be one year and shall not exceed that of the fishing license.
The permit of exploratory squid jigging fishery in the Indian Ocean shall record, both in Chinese and English, the following:
(1)The serial number;
(2)The name, CT number, gross tonnage (GT), length overall (LOA) and fisheries type of the fishing vessel;
(3)Name of the distant water fisheries operator;
(4)The authorized fishing Ocean, fishing area(s), and fishing period;
(5)The International Radio Call Sign (IRCS); and
(6)The IMO ship identification number.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The distant water fisheries operator concerned shall implement the exploratory fishing plan approved by the competent authority.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Chapter III on fishing vessel markings and Chapter IV on management of vessel position reporting in the Regulations for Fishing Vessels Conducting Squid Jigging Fishery shall, mutatis mutandis, apply to exploratory fishing vessels.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[In the event that any exploratory fishing vessel leaves a port, its distant water fisheries operator or captain shall daily fill in and sign on the logbooks designated by the competent authority, and submit to the competent authority next day by facsimile.
The logbooks as referred to in the preceding paragraph shall filled in completely and accurately, and where the catch amount is zero, the logbooks shall still be filled in and submitted.
Article 20 to 24 regarding logbooks and catch reports in the Regulations for Fishing Vessels Conducting Squid Jigging Fishery shall, mutatis mutandis, apply to exploratory fishing vessels.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Any exploratory fishing vessel intending to land in a port shall land only in Chienchen Fishing Harbor and Siaogang Fishing Harbor in Kaohsiung City.
Any exploratory fishing vessel intending to land in a port of Mainland China shall do so only in the designated ports stipulated in the Regulations on Permission and the Management of Fishing Vessels Sailing to Mainland China.
Any carrier vessel of the Republic of China intending to transship catch from an exploratory fishing vessel shall obtain the distant water fisheries permit.
Any foreign carrier vessel intending to transship catch from an exploratory fishing vessel shall obtain the operation permit from the flag State concerned and be installed with the automatic location communicator (ALC) which meets the standards specified by the competent authority, and at least one vessel position shall be hourly sent to the commissioned professional institution.
Article 26, paragraph 1; Article 28 to 36; Article 37, paragraph 1 and 2 as well as Appendix 7; Article 38 and 39 regarding the permission and management of transshipment or landing in the Regulations for Fishing Vessels Conducting Squid Jigging Fishery shall, mutatis mutandis, apply to exploratory fishing vessels and carrier vessels.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 10</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Chapter VII on observation or inspection during fishing operations in the Regulations for Fishing Vessels Conducting Squid Jigging Fishery shall, mutatis mutandis, apply to exploratory fishing vessels.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 11</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Any exploratory fishing vessel shall not dispose any type of plastic trash or discharge any oil on the sea.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 12</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[In case of any of the following circumstances, the competent authority shall revoke the permit of exploratory squid jigging fishery in the Indian Ocean:
(1)Fishing operation is conducted with the fishing gear not specified in the exploratory fishing plan approved by the competent authority.
(2)Any of the serious infringement stipulated in Article 13, paragraph 1 of the Act is committed.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 13</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The distant water fisheries operator concerned shall, within 30 days after the permitted period of exploratory squid jigging fishery in the Indian Ocean has expired, submit a report to the competent authority in accordance with the approved exploratory fishing plan. The competent authority may grant 1 million New Taiwan Dollars to the exploratory fishing vessel as incentive.
The incentive shall not be granted in case of any of the following circumstances:
(1)The actual fishing period in the permitted fishing area of the exploratory fishing vessel is less than 30 days.
(2)Any circumstances stipulated in Article 12 is conducted or committed.
(3)The report as referred to in the preceding paragraph is not submitted or is submitted after the required timeframe.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 14</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulations shall become effective on the date of promulgation.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
