<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Regulations for Quarantine of Animal/Plant Carried by Passengers and Service Personnel on Vehicles</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>旅客及服務於車船航空器人員攜帶動植物檢疫物檢疫作業辦法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=M0130009</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20190703</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Annex：Regulated articles eligible for the Regulations.pdf]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000005461</下載網址>
  </檔案>
</附件>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1. Adopted and promulgated on January 30, 2003
2. Amendment to Articles 2, 3and promulgated on September 12, 2007
3. Amendment to Articles 4, 8 and promulgated on February 16, 2011
4. Amendment to Article 3 and promulgated on September 8, 2011
5. Amendment to the Annex of Article 2 and promulgated on April 8, 2015
6. Amended and promulgated on 3 July, 2019]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Regulations are pursuant to Paragraph 1, Article 39 of the Statute for Prevention and Control of Infectious Animal Disease and Article 21-1 of the Plant Protection and Quarantine Act.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These regulations are applicable to animal and plant regulated articles carried by passenger(s) or crew of vehicles, vessels, and aircrafts (inbound/outbound personnel hereinafter) as specified by the category and quantity of the Annex.
For regulated articles that do not conform to the provisions of the preceding paragraph, these are then subject to the application procedure for general goods for import/export quarantine.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Charges for quarantine inspection, attending service, overtime service, computer processing and quarantine labeling are exempted for regulated articles specified in Paragraph 1 of Article 2; other operational fees and costs are collected in accordance with relevant regulations.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Outbound personnel carrying regulated articles which quarantine inspection is required by the importing country shall complete the application form and apply for export quarantine inspection to the animal and plant quarantine authority with the presence of passport, ticket and other relevant documents.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Quarantine tags are issued by the animal and plant quarantine authority for outbound regulated articles after inspection with no evidence of infection with diseases/pests. Alternatively, animal health/phytosanitary certificates may be issued when importing country requires one or more of the following:
1.Animal health/Phytosanitary certificates,
2.Additional declarations, and/or
3.Statement of quarantine treatment.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Inbound personnel carrying regulated articles shall complete the application form and apply for import quarantine inspection to the animal and plant quarantine authority with the presence of passport, customs declaration form, original of animal health/ phytosanitary certificates and other relevant documents.
The inbound personnel or their agents shall be present during the inspection process.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[(Deleted)]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[(Deleted)]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The animal and plant quarantine authority shall issue animal health/ phytosanitary certificates for the inbound regulated articles that meet quarantine regulations.
When treatment, post-entry quarantine, bonding at the customs for reshipment or destruction is required, the animal and plant quarantine authority shall issue the "Notification of Non-Compliance of Imported Animals/Plants or Products."]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 10</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Personnel with diplomatic privilege carrying regulated articles (including those in their unaccompanied baggage) shall apply for inspection in accordance with the Regulation.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 11</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[(Deleted)]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 12</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Regulations should come into effect on the date of promulgation.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
