<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Remuneration Standards for the Board Members in Reviewing Cases Concerning Unfair Labor Practices</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>不當勞動行為裁決委員案件審理給付報酬標準</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=N0020020</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20230817</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Prescribed and promulgated a total nine articles by the Council of Labor Affairs, Executive Yuan Order No. 1000125932 on June 9, 2011, and become effective on May 1, 2011
2.Amended on December 27, 2012
3.Articles 2, 3, 6 and 9, as amended, were promulgated by the Order No. Lao-Dong-Guan-4-Zi-1070127094 dated June 20, 2018 from Ministry of Labor and shall become effective on Jan. 1, 2018
4.Articles 7 and 9, as amended, were promulgated by the Order No. Lao-Dong-Guan-4-Zi-1080125823 dated April 2, 2019 from Ministry of Labor and shall become effective on Jan. 1, 2019.
5.Articles 2 and 9, as amended, and Article 7-1, as added, were promulgated by Order No. Lao-Dong-Guan-4-Zi-1110139922 dated Nov. 10, 2022 from the Ministry of Labor shall become effective on the date of promulgation except for Article 7-1, which became effective on Oct. 1, 2021.
6.Total ten articles, as amended, were promulgated by the Order No. Lao-Dong-Guan-4-Zi-1120143700A dated August 17, 2023 from Ministry of Labor and shall become effective on Jan. 1, 2023.

]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Standards are prescribed in accordance with Paragraph 3 to Article 46 of the Act for Settlement of Labor-Management Disputes (here-in-after referred to as the Act).]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[When a member of the Board conducts preliminary review of case(s) based on Paragraph 2 of Article 14 of the Regulations for Decision on the Unfair Labor Practices (hereinafter referred to as the Regulations), he/she shall be paid NT$1,525.
When a member of the Board based on Paragraph 3 of Article 14 of the Regulations attends a meeting for preliminary review of case(s) where the parties concerned are present to provide explanation, he/she shall be paid NT$2,500 for each meeting.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[When a member of the Board conducts a fact-finding procedure, he/she shall be paid NT$2,500 per investigation meeting on the case and shall be paid no more than N.T.$ 10,000 for each case.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[When a member of the Board convenes a meeting in accordance with Articles 44 to 46 of the Act, he/she may be paid transportation fees and accommodation fees after verification by referring to the Directions on the Application and Payment of Travel Grants in Domestic Areas.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[A board member assigned to conduct a fact-finding shall in person write the fact-finding report and shall be paid, and the payment for the writing is calculated on the basis of NT$1,350 for one thousand Chinese characters.
A board member shall in person write the suggestions for a decision and shall be paid, and the payment for the writing is calculated on the basis of NT$2,300 for one thousand Chinese characters.The total payment for writing a fact-finding report and the suggestions for a decision of each case shall be no more than NT$35,000, and the borad member shall write the decision award in accordance with the decision of the Board.
The board may, if necessary, assign a member to write the decision award referred to in the preceding paragraph, and the payment for the writing is NT$2,000 each case.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[When a board member attends the Board meeting, he/she shall be paid NT$2,500 for each meeting.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Chair of the Board shall be paid NT$8,500 per month on a part-time basis for assigning cases and handling all related businesses.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[When a standing member of the Board reviews the comments, records of investigation, reports of investigation, and proposals for decisions and rulings of the preliminary review in accordance with Paragraph 2 of Article 14, Paragraph 3 of Article 22, and Paragraph 3 of Article 27 of the Regulations, he/she shall be paid NT$1,525 for each review.
The fees for the review of records of investigation stipulated in the preceding Paragraph shall not be paid more than four times for each case.
When a standing member of the Board attends the consultation meeting on the decision system for unfair labor practices, decision cases, or administrative remedies, he/she shall be paid NT$2,500 for each meeting.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The expenditures prescribed in the Standards shall be paid by the Central Competent Authority from its budget.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 10</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Standards shall become effective on Jan. 1, 2023.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
