<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Regulations for the Deliberation of Basic Wage</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>基本工資審議辦法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawContent.aspx?PCODE=N0030003</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20141210</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated on March 21, 1985
2.Promulgated by Council of Labor Affairs Under Executive Yuan January 1988 
3.Amended and promulgated by the Council of Labor Affairs, Executive Yuan on February 02, 2000 with Tai-89-Lao Don 2 Tze No. 0004169 Order
4.Amended and promulgated by the Council of Labor Affairs, Executive Yuan on January 23, 2002 with Lao Don 2 Tze No. 0910003593 Order
5.Amended and promulgated by the Council of Labor Affairs, Executive Yuan on November 6, 2002 with Lao Don 2 Tze No. 0910056581 Orde
6.Amended on August 31, 2010
7.Amended on December 10,2014]]></沿革內容>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Regulations are enacted according to Article 21 of the Labor Standards act.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[For the reviewing of basic wage, the Ministry of Labor (MOL) establishes the Basic Wage Commission, with the Minister of the MOL acting concurrently as the Chief Commissioner, and 21 members with a 2-year term consisting of the following representatives:
1.One representative from the Ministry of Labor.
2.One representative from the Ministry of Economic Affairs.
3.One representative from the National Development Council.
4.Seven representatives from laborers.
5.Seven representatives from employers.
6.Four individuals from academics and experts in this field.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Basic Wage Commission constitutes an Executive Secretary, who is concurrently the Director of the Labor Conditions Department Council, MOL, and shall be responsible for daily tasks under the direction of the Chief Commissioner. The Commission also constitutes several staff members to assist the work and who are concurrently the staff of relevant government agencies.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[(Data should be prepared for fixing of the basic wage)
For the fixing of basic wage, the Commission shall collect and study the following information:
1.Conditions of national economic development;
2.Wholesale price index;
3.Retail price index;
4.National income and average individual income;
5.Labour productivity of different industries & employment situation;
6.Workers' wages in different industries;
7.Survey & statistical figures on household income & expenditure.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Basic Wage Commission will convene the annual wage review in the third quarter each year.
When the Basic Wage Commission determines an adjustment to the basic wage, the new basic wage set by the Basic Wage Commission shall be submitted by the MOL to the Executive Yuan for approval, promulgation, and enforcement.
The Basic Wage Commission may assemble a work group to deliberate on basic wage related matters.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Members and Staff of the Basic Wage Commission shall serve without pay.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Regulations shall take effect on the day of promulgation.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
