<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Regulations for Ordering the Insured Unit to Contribute Within a Time Limit After Issuance of Labor Occupational Accident Insurance Benefits</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>勞工職業災害保險給付後限期投保單位繳納辦法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=N0050036</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20220309</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated on March 9, 2022]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulations are enacted in accordance with Paragraph 3 of Article 36 of the Labor Occupational Accident Insurance and Protection Act (hereinafter referred to as the “Act”).]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The scope of ordering the insured unit to contribute within a time limit after the insurer’s issuance of insurance benefits referred to herein covers the injury or sickness benefits, disability benefits, death benefits and disappearance benefits.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The amount to be contributed by the insured unit referred to in Paragraph 1 of Article 36 herein shall be calculated based on the average monthly insured salary set forth in Article 28 herein and in accordance with the following requirements:
I. Injury or sickness benefits, lump sum payment for disability, survivors’ allowance, lump sum payment for survivors’ pension, and disappearance benefits: Subject to the benefit criteria set forth herein.
II. Disability pension: The benefit criteria for the lump sum payment for disability with respect to the same disability set forth herein.
III. Survivors’ pension: The benefit criteria for the lump sum payment for survivors’ pension set forth herein.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The amount payable referred to in the preceding article shall be paid by the insured unit within 15 days as of the date following service of the insurer’s written administrative decision.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[If the insured unit fails to pay the amount within the time limit set forth in the preceding article and still fails to do so within 30 days upon receipt of the insurer’s written reminder, the insured unit shall be subject to the administrative execution pursuant to laws.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[If it is impossible for the insured unit to pay the amount set forth in Article 3 herein in full, the insured unit may apply for payment in installment with the insurer before the insurer has it subject to the administrative execution referred to in the preceding article.
If the insurer approves the payment in installment but the insured unit fails to make any installment payment timely, the payment shall be deemed matured in whole and the insurer may have the insured unit subject to administrative execution pursuant to laws.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulations shall be enforced as of May 1, 2022.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
