<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Regulations for Deduction of Unreturned Insurance Benefits for Those with Labor Occupational Accident Insurance</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>勞工職業災害保險未繳還之保險給付扣減辦法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=N0050032</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20220302</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated on Mar. 2, 2022.]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulations are enacted in accordance with Paragraph 2 of Article 34 of the Labor Occupational Accident Insurance and Protection Act (hereinafter referred to as the “Act”).]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The term "unreturned insurance benefits" used in these Regulations refers to insurance benefits that have been claimed by insured persons but then revoked or abolished by the insurer, and have not yet paid back by the insured persons.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[When an insured person fails to return insurance benefits, the insurer may make deductions from the following insurance benefits claimable by the insured person or his or her beneficiary until the full amount is paid up:
I. Injury and sickness benefits;
II. Disability benefits;
III. Death benefits;
IV. Missing person benefits.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The insurer may make the deductions referred to in the preceding article in the following manners:
I. With benefits to be paid in one lump sum: deductions in full.
II. With pension benefits: deduction of the pension benefits claimable for each time until the full amount is paid up.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[When the insurer makes the deduction from insurance benefits claimable by the insured persons or their beneficiaries, the insurer shall issue a written notice along with the insurance benefit payment.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulations shall be enforced as of May 1, 2022.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
