<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Enforcement Rules of the Vocational Training Act</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>職業訓練法施行細則</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=N0080002</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20120530</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Enacted and promulgated a total forty-four Articles of the Rules by the Order of Executive Yuan  No. 5496 on March 21, 1986
2.Amended and promulgated Articles 2, 8 and 9 of the Rules by Executive Yuan  No. 36308 on December 30, 2000
3.Amended Article 4, added article 2-1 and deleted Articles 8 and 9 of the Rules by the Order of Council of Labor Affairs , Executive Yuan  No.1010510535 on May 30, 2012]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Rules are prescribed in accordance with Article 43 of the Vocational Training Act (hereinafter referred to as the Act).]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The implementation of vocational training in association with employment services as set forth in Article 4 of the Act shall be conducted according to the following regulations:
1.Vocational training institutions shall plan and conduct vocational training in accordance with labor market demands.
2.Vocational training institutions shall provide lists of trainees who have completed their training but remained unemployed for job placement through public employment agencies.
3.Vocational training institutions shall accept the delegation of public employment agencies to conduct vocational training.
4.Vocational training institutions may accept the delegation of other organizations to conduct vocational training.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2-1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[To fulfill the functions set forth in Article 4-1 of the Act, the central competent authority shall establish the timeframes and approaches of the provision of various services.
The central competent authorities of various industries shall conduct their corresponding duties according to the preceding paragraph.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Vocational training institutions intending to conduct rudimentary training for occupations for which the government has not yet established training programs are required to draw up the training plans and submit them to the central competent authority for reference.
The training plans as described in the preceding paragraph shall include the following information:
1.Target occupation and class title
2.Training objectives
3.Trainee qualifications
4.Duration of program
5.Training curriculum
6.Time allotment and schedule
7.Training venue
8.Training equipment
9.Training methods
10.Budget overview]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Rudimentary training certificate shall carry the following information:
1. Name, National ID No., and date of birth of the trainees
2. Class attended
3. Dates of beginning and end of training
4. Courses taken and total hours of each course
5. Title of training unit
6. Certificate number
In addition to the items listed in the preceding paragraph, the training certificate from training units delegated to conduct rudimentary training in accordance with Paragraph 3, Article 3 of the Act shall also carry the title of the delegating agency.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The instruction and counseling work in apprentice training organization by business entities shall be conducted by skillful technicians with either of the two following qualifications:
1.Having acquired a Class B or higher technician certificate for occupations for which skills certification is available.
2.Having at least five years of experience in related fields for occupations for which skills certification is not yet available.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[To operate apprentice training, business entities shall draw up training plans in accordance with Article 12 of the Act. The program shall be conducted according to Paragraph 2, Article 3 and the training plan shall include the following information:
1. Title of business entity
2. Names and qualifications of trainers and counseling personnel
3. Collaborating training units]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The information to be included on a training certificate shall be the same as specified in Article 4.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[（Deleted）]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[（Deleted）]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 10</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The term “year” referred to in the Act may be calendar year or fiscal year that each vocational training institution sees fit to apply.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 11</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Vocational training institutions are required to issue receipts when receiving donations in the form of cash, securities or other personal property from individuals, organizations or business entities, and register the ownership transfer in the company of the donor when receiving donations in the form of real property. Both types of donations shall be recorded.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 12</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Rules shall become effective on the date of promulgation.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
