<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Fee-charging Standards for Technical Skills Certification</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>技術士技能檢定規費收費標準</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=N0080020</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20240416</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[ANNEX Fees for Field Tests-0703.ODT]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000008482</下載網址>
  </檔案>
</附件>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Issued according to Order Lao-Jhong-Yi-Tzu No. 0950100133 by the Council of Labor Affairs(CLA), Executive Yuan on March 30,2006
2.Annex of Article 6 amended & promulgated by CLA with Lao-Chung- ER-Tzu No. 0960200028 on January 10th 2007 
3.Annex of Article 6 amended & promulgated by CLA with Lao-Chung- ER-Tzu No. 0960201218 on August 23th 2007 
4.Annex of Article 6 amended & promulgated by CLA with Lao-Chung- Yi -Tzu No. 0970100211on June 17th 2008 
5.Annex of Article 6 amended & promulgated by CLA with Lao-Chung- ER -Tzu No. 0980201685 on May 7th 2009 
6.Annex of Article 6 amended & promulgated by CLA with Lao-Chung- ER -Tzu No. 0980202569 on August 27th 2009 
7.Annex of Article 6 amended & promulgated by CLA with Lao-Chung- ER -Tzu No. 0990201332 on May 24th 2010
8.Annex of Article 6 amended & promulgated by CLA with Lao-Chung- ER -Tzu No. 09902025142 on August 5th 2010
9.Annex of Article 6 amended & promulgated by CLA with Lao-Chung- ER -Tzu No. 0990202545 on September 24th 2010
10.Article 3 and Annex of Article 6 amended & promulgated by CLA with Lao-Chung- Yi -Tzu No. 0990100484 on December 6th 2010
11.Annex of Article 6 amended & promulgated by CLA with Lao-Chung- ER -Tzu No. 1000202412 on July 26th 2011
12.Annex of Article 6 amended & promulgated by CLA with Lao-Chung- ER -Tzu No. 1000204045 on December 7th 2011
13.Annex of Article 6 amended & promulgated by CLA with Lao-Chung- ER -Tzu No. 1010200857 on April 7th 2012
14.Annex of Article 6 amended & promulgated by CLA with Lao-Chung- ER -Tzu No. 101010202083 on August 3th 2012
15.Annex of Article 6 amended & promulgated by CLA with Lao-Chung- ER -Tzu No. 101010202083 on August 2th 2013
16.Annex of Article 6 amended & promulgated by CLA with Lao-Chung- ER -Tzu No. 101010204160 on December 11th 2013
17.Annex of Article 6 amended & promulgated by MOL with Lao-Dong-Fa-Neng -Tzu No. 1031809545 on July 24th 2014
18.Annex of Article 6 amended & promulgated  by  MOL  with Lao-Dong-Fa-Neng -Tzu No. 1031809852 on August 11th 2014
19.Annex of Article 6 amended & promulgated by MOL with Lao-Dong-Fa-Neng -Tzu No. 1039800219 on December 26th 2014
20.Annex of Article 6 amended & promulgated by MOL with Lao-Dong-Fa-Neng -Tzu No. 1040503832 on April 7th 2015
21.Annex of Article 6 amended & promulgated by MOL with Lao-Dong-Fa-Neng-Tzu No.1040504511 on May 7th 2015
22.Annex of Article 6 amended & promulgated by MOL with Lao-Dong-Fa-Neng -Tzu No. 1050504673 on May 9th 2016
23.Annex of Article 6 amended & promulgated by MOL with Lao-Dong-Fa-Neng -Tzu No. 10705056631 on May 10th 2018
24.Annex of Article 6 amended & promulgated by MOL with Lao-Dong-Fa-Neng –Tzu No. 1070511382 on August 13th 2018
25.Article 5、 Article 9 and Annex of Article 6 amended & promulgated by MOL with Lao-Dong-Fa-Neng –Tzu No. 1070517560 on August 10th 2018
26.Annex of Article 6 amended & promulgated by MOL with Lao-Dong-Fa-Neng –Tzu No. 1080511426 on August 26th 2019
27.Annex of Article 6 amended & promulgated by MOL with Lao-Dong-Fa-Neng –Tzu No. 1090503562 on Mar 20th 2020
28.Annex of Article 6 amended & promulgated by MOL with Lao-Dong-Fa-Neng –Tzu No. 1090512666 on August 5th 2020
29.Annex of Article 6 amended & promulgated by MOL with Lao-Dong-Fa-Neng –Tzu No. 1090520190 on December 10th 2020
30.Annex of Article 6 amended & promulgated by MOL with Lao-Dong-Fa-Neng –Tzu No. 1100521475 on December 30th 2021
31.Annex of Article 6 amended & promulgated by MOL with Lao-Dong-Fa-Neng –Tzu No. 1130505011 on April 16th 2024]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This Standard is formulated in accordance with Paragraph 1, Article 10 of the Charges and Fees Act.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Charges and fees for Technical Skills Certification referred to herein includes the items as follows:
1. Enrollment introduction and application form fee.
2. Enrollment qualification review fee.
3. Written test fee.
4. Field test fee.
5. Technical license fee
6. Technical Certificate fee]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The enrollment introduction and application form fee is NT$50. However, online enrolled applicants are free from the charge of enrollment introduction and the fee of application form.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The enrollment qualification review fee is NT$150 per person each time.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The field test fee is NT$190 per person each time]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Charges for field tests are shown in the annex.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The charge for the technical license is NT$160. The same is applied for reissuing.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The charge for the technical certificate is NT$400. The same is applied for reissuing.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This Standard is effective as of the date of promulgation.
The Article(s) amended on Dec 10, 2018 shall become effective on Jan. 1, 2019.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
