<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Fee-charging Standards for Application  Case Review and License under the Employment Services Act</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>就業服務法申請案件審查費及證照費收費標準</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=N0090030</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20140328</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated by the Council of Labor Affairs, Executive Yuan on Jan. 13, 2004
2.Amendment to Article 2 by the Ministry of Labor on 28 March 2014 under Lao Dong FaDecree No. 1031811916]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Standards are drawn upon in accordance with Article 81 of the Employment 
Services Act (hereinafter referred to as the Act).]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The employer when applying for permissions relating to foreign person employment shall pay review fees in accordance with the following standards:
1.Five hundred New Taiwan dollars for each employment permission or extension of employment permission of work prescribed in Subparagraph 1 to Subparagraph 6 of Paragraph 1 of Article 46 and work permission prescribed in Paragraph 3 of Article 51 of the Act.
2.Two hundred New Taiwan dollars for each recruitment permission or transfer of employer (or job) permission of work prescribed in Subparagraph 8 to Subparagraph 11 of Paragraph 1 of Article 46 of the Act.
3.One hundred New Taiwan dollars for each entry visa permission, employment permission, extension of employment permission, replacement permission, extended recruiting period of recruitment permission, change of work place, change of care recipient, or change / increase of care recipient(s) of work prescribed in Subparagraph 8 to Subparagraph 11of Paragraph 1 of Article 46 of the Act.
4.One hundred New Taiwan dollars for each employment permission application of foreign person prescribed in Paragraph 1 of Article 50 of the Act.
5.One hundred New Taiwan dollars for each employment permission or extension of employment permission of work prescribed in Subparagraph 1 to Subparagraph 4 of Paragraph 1 of Article 51 of the Act.
The person when applying for reissuing any one of above mentioned permissions shall pay one hundred New Taiwan dollars for eachapplication as the review fee.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The private employment services institution or the person with employment services 
specialty when applying for permission or issuance of license shall pay review fee or 
license fee in accordance with the following standards:
1. Five hundred New Taiwan dollars for each establishment permission application of 
a private employment services institution or its branch.
2. Two hundred New Taiwan dollars for each alteration permission application of a 
private employment services institution or its branch.
3. Two thousand New Taiwan dollars for each issuance of license application of a 
private employment services institution or its branch.
4. One thousand New Taiwan dollars for each case of changing or supplementing 
license prescribed in previous Subparagraph.
5. Four hundred New Taiwan dollars for each case of issuing, changing or 
supplementing certificate of person with employment services specialty.
6. Two thousand New Taiwan dollars for each approval application of foreign 
employment company.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[A foreign person shall pay review fee of one hundred New Taiwan dollars for each 
work permit application.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[An applicant shall pay in accordance with these Standards review fee or license fee to 
the competent authorities or the institution entrusted by the competent authorities.
The competent authorities shall publicly announce the institution(s) prescribed in 
previous Paragraph.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Standards shall be put into practice on the date of promulgation.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
