<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>The Ministry of Labor’s Fee-charging Standards for Approving Applications for Case Review under the Act for the Recruitment and Employment of Foreign Professionals</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>勞動部受理外國專業人才延攬及僱用法申請案件收費標準</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=N0090052</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20211025</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated on February 06, 2018
2.Amended on October 25, 2021]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Standard is enacted according to the requirements of Articles 7 and 10 of the Charges and Fees Act.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Applications made to the Ministry of Labor for the following permits according to the Act for the Recruitment and Employment of Foreign Professionals (hereinafter “the Act”) are subject to a fee of review:
1.Employment permit or its extension set out in Article 5 of the Act.
2.The artistic work permit or its extension set out in Article 10 of the Act.
3.Work permit set out in Article 15 of the Act.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Applications for an employment permit or its extension for employment of foreign teachers with specialized knowledge, skill or foreign languages at short-term cram school as set out in Article 6 of the Act are subject to a fee of NT$500 per case.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Application for work permit or its extension for foreign professionals engaging in artistic work as set out in Article 10 of the Act is subject to a fee of NT$500 per case.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Application for a work permit for children who have reached the age of majority or above of foreign professionals, foreign s pecial ist professional or foreign senior professional as set out in Article 15 of the Act is subject to a fee of NT$100 per case.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Application for the reissue of permits set out in the three Articles above is subject to a fee of NT$100 per case.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[For applications for permits for residents of Hong Kong or Macau engaging in undertakings as stated in paragraph 1, Article 5 and Article 10 of the Act, the requirements under s ubparagraph 1 and s ubparagraph 2 of Article 2, Article 3, Article 4 and the previous Article are applicable.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These standards go into effect on October 25, 2021.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
