<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Standards for the Composition of Automobile Gasoline and Diesel Fuels</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>車用汽柴油成分管制標準</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=O0020034</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20090729</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Full text in 11 articles promulgated by Environmental Protection Administration Order (88) Huan-Shu-Kong-Tzu No. 0080295 on December 15, 1999.
2.Revision to Articles 5, 6, and 7 promulgated by Environmental Protection Administration Order (89) Huan-Shu-Kong-Tzu No. 0037890 on July 19, 2000.
3.Revision to full text in 11 articles promulgated by Environmental Protection Administration Order (90) Huan-Shu-Kong-Tzu No. 0081378 on December 26, 2001.
4.Revision to Articles 1 through 4, 9, and 11 promulgated by Environmental Protection Administration Order Huan-Shu-Kong-Tzu No. 0910075537 on November 6, 2002.
5.Revision to full text in 5 articles promulgated by Environmental Protection Administration Order Huan-Shu-Kong-Tzu No. 0920055396 on August 6, 2003.
6.Revision to Article 4 promulgated by Environmental Protection Administration Order Huan-Shu-Kong-Tzu No. 0930089773 on December 15, 2004.
7.Revision to full text in 5 articles promulgated by Order Huan-Shu-Kong-Tzu No. 0980065735 on July 29, 2009, and name revised; the original name was "Standards for the Composition and Properties of Automobile Gasoline and Diesel Fuels."]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Standards are determined pursuant to Article 36, Paragraph 3 of the Air Pollution Control Act.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The terms used in these Standards are defined as follows.
I. "Gasoline characteristics" mean the physical and chemical characteristics of gasoline insofar as they are able to influence the pollution emissions of gasoline engine vehicles, and includes benzene content, aromatics content, olefins content, sulfur content, oxygen content, Reid vapor pressure (RVP), and evaporation volume percentage.
II. "Diesel characteristics" means the physical and chemical characteristics of diesel fuel insofar as they are able to influence the pollution emissions of diesel engine vehicles, and includes sulfur content, aromatics and polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons content.
III. "Benzene content" means the total amount of benzene contained in the gasoline.
IV. "Sulfur content" means the total amount of sulfur and its compounds in gasoline or diesel fuel.
V. "Reid vapor pressure" is a method of expressing gasoline volatility, and means the vapor pressure of gasoline at 37.8°C (100°F) when the volume ratio of vapor to liquid gasoline is four to one.
VI. "Oxygen content" refers to the total oxygen weight percentage of oxygenates which have been added to gasoline. The most commonly used oxygenates are methyl tertiary-butyl ether (MTBE), ethyl tertiary-butyl ether (ETBE), tertiary-amyl methyl ether (TAME), diisopropyl ether (DIPE), ethanol, and methanol.
VII. "Aromatics content" means the total amount of benzene, methylbenzene and aromatic hydrocarbon compounds above C9 in gasoline or diesel fuel.
VIII. "Olefins content" means total amount of olefins in gasoline.
IX. "Cetane index" is a method of expressing the ignition performance of diesel fuel, and is calculated based on the density and 50% distillation temperature in accordance with the Chinese National Standard 12016 (CNS 12016).
X. "Polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons (PAH) content" means the total amount of aromatic hydrocarbons contained in gasoline excluding monocyclic aromatics.
XI. "Gasohol" means fossil gasoline blended with fuel ethanol, or denatured fuel ethanol not blended with fossil gasoline and used directly as a fuel.
XII. "Biodiesel" means fossil diesel fuel blended with fatty acid methyl ester, or fatty acid methyl ester not blended with fossil diesel fuel and used directly as a fuel.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Gasoline characteristics standards are as shown below:
The following table contains gasoline characteristics standards effective as of January 1, 2007:
┌──────────────────┬───────────┐
│Item                                │Standard value        │
├──────────────────┼───────────┤
│Benzene                             │1.0 vol%, max         │
├──────────────────┼───────────┤
│Sulfur                              │50 ppmw, max          │
├──────────────────┼───────────┤
│Reid vapor pressure                 │8.7 psi, max          │
├──────────────────┼───────────┤
│Oxygen                              │2.7 wt%, max          │
├──────────────────┼───────────┤
│Aromatics                           │36 vol%, max          │
├──────────────────┼───────────┤
│Olefins                             │18 vol%, max          │
├──────────────────┴───────────┤
│Remark:                                                     │
│1. Until E3 gasohol is applied nationwide, the standard     │
│   value of Reid vapor pressure will be 66.9 kPa, the       │
│   standard value of oxygen content will be 3.24% (m/m), and│
│   the standard values for remaining regulated items will be│
│   the same as in the table for E3 gasohol.                 │
│2. 2. 1psi = 6.895 kPa                                      │
└──────────────────────────────┘
The following table contains gasoline characteristics standards effective as of July 1, 2011:
┌───────────────┬──────────────┐
│Item                          │Standard value              │
├───────────────┼──────────────┤
│Benzene                       │1.0 %(v/v), max             │
├───────────────┼──────────────┤
│Sulfur                        │50 mg/kg, max               │
├───────────────┼──────────────┤
│Reid vapor pressure           │60 kPa, max                 │
├───────────────┼──────────────┤
│Oxygen                        │2.7 %(m/m), max             │
├───────────────┼──────────────┤
│Aromatics                     │35 %(v/v), max              │
├───────────────┼──────────────┤
│Olefins                       │18 %(v/v), max              │
├───────────────┴──────────────┤
│Remark:                                                     │
│1. Until E3 gasohol is applied nationwide, the standard     │
│   value of Reid vapor pressure will be 66.9 kPa, the       │
│   standard value of oxygen content will be 3.24% (m/m), and│
│   the standard values for remaining regulated items will be│
│   the same as in the table for E3 gasohol.                 │
│2. 1psi = 6.895 kPa                                         │
└──────────────────────────────┘
The following table contains gasoline characteristics standards effective as of January 1, 2012:
┌──────────────────┬───────────┐
│Item                                │Standard value        │
├──────────────────┼───────────┤
│Benzene                             │1.0 %(v/v), max       │
├──────────────────┼───────────┤
│Sulfur                              │Sulfur 10 mg/kg, max  │
├──────────────────┼───────────┤
│Reid vapor pressure                 │60 kPa, max           │
├──────────────────┼───────────┤
│Oxygen                              │2.7 %(m/m), max       │
├──────────────────┼───────────┤
│Aromatics                           │35 %(v/v), max        │
├──────────────────┼───────────┤
│Olefins                             │18 %(v/v), max        │
├──────────────────┴───────────┤
│Remark:                                                     │
│1. Until E3 gasohol is applied nationwide, the standard     │
│   value of Reid vapor pressure will be 66.9 kPa, the       │
│   standard value of oxygen content will be 3.24% (m/m), and│
│   the standard values for remaining regulated items will be│
│   the same as in the table for E3 gasohol.                 │
│2. 1psi = 6.895 kPa                                         │
│3. Gasoline shipped from refineries shall comply with these │
│   standards starting from January 1, 2012. Fuel depots and │
│   filling stations shall complete stock replacement tasks  │
│   by July 1, 2012 in order to achieve compliance with these│
│   standards.                                               │
│4. Imported gasoline products shall comply with these       │
│   standards starting from January 1, 2012.                 │
└──────────────────────────────┘
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Diesel (including biodiesel) characteristics standards are as shown below:
The following table contains diesel characteristics standards effective as of January 1, 2005:
┌──────────────────┬─────────┐
│Item                                │Standard value    │
├──────────────────┼─────────┤
│Sulfur                              │50 ppmw, max      │
├──────────────────┼─────────┤
│Aromatics                           │35 wt%, max       │
├──────────────────┴─────────┤
│Remark:                                                 │
│Biodiesel shall comply with these standards.            │
└────────────────────────────┘
The following table contains diesel fuel characteristics standards effective as of July 1, 2011:
┌──────────────────┬───────────┐
│Item                                │Standard value        │
├──────────────────┼───────────┤
│Sulfur                              │10 mg/kg, max         │
├──────────────────┼───────────┤
│Cetane index                        │48 min                │
├──────────────────┼───────────┤
│Polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons    │11 %(m/m), max        │
├──────────────────┴───────────┤
│Remark:                                                     │
│1. Diesel shipped from refineries shall comply with these   │
│   standards starting from July 1, 2011. Fuel depots and    │
│   filling stations shall complete stock replacement tasks  │
│   by January 1, 2012 in order to achieve compliance with   │
│   these standards.                                         │
│2. Imported diesel products shall comply with these         │
│   standards starting from July 1, 2011.                    │
│3. Biodiesel shall comply with these standards.             │
└──────────────────────────────┘
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Unless an enforcement date is separately designated, these standards shall take effect on the date of promulgation.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
