<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Regulations on Marine Environment Monitoring and Monitoring Station Installation</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>海域環境監測及監測站設置辦法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=O0040034</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20240426</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1，Promulgated on November 13, 2002
2，Amended and promulgated by Ocean Affairs Council Order Hai-Bao-Tzu No. 1130004214 on April 26, 2024.
]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulations are determined pursuant to Article 9 Paragraph 5 of the Marine Pollution Control Act. (herein referred to as this Act).]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Marine environment water quality monitoring stations shall be installed at the following locations:
1. The mouths of primary and secondary rivers.
2. Harbors, lagoons.
3. The areas designated in Paragraph 1, Article 18 of this Act.
4. The marine environment which may be affected by the behaviors stipulated in Paragraph 1, Article 19 of this Act.
5. Marine water quality background monitoring points.
6. Other locations as designated by the central competent authority.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The competent authorities should conduct the marine environment water quality monitoring task for the following items according to the characteristics of different marine environments:
1. Monitoring Items (required):
(1) Marine hydrology, water temperature,
(2) Marine water quality, including salinity, hydrogen ion concentration index (pH value), dissolved oxygen (DO),
(3) Other items designated by the central competent authority.
2. Monitoring Items (optional):
(1) Marine hydrology, including flow velocity, flow direction, wave height, wave direction, and wave period.
(2) Marine water quality, including suspended solids (SS), light intensity in water, chlorophyll a, coliform group, heavy metals, nutrient salts (nitrate nitrogen, nitrite nitrogen, ammonia nitrogen, phosphate, silicate, and total phosphorus), biochemical oxygen demand, mineral oil, cyanide, phenols, volatile organic compounds, pesticides.
(3) Marine organisms, including plankton(zooplankton and phytoplankton) and benthic organisms.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Port management authorities and enterprises should conduct the water quality and sediment testing tasks in port areas according to the characteristics of different port areas:
The testing items for port area water quality are the same as the ones stipulated in the preceding article; the testing items for port area sediment are as follows:
1. Testing Items (required):
(1) Heavy metals.
(2) Organic compounds (volatile organic compounds, semi-volatile organic compounds and plasticizers.
2. Testing Items (optional):
(1) Pesticides.
(2) Dioxins.
(3) Polychlorinated biphenyls.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The frequency of water quality monitoring (testing) of marine environment and in port areas shall be once every quarter, and the frequency of sediment testing in port areas shall be once every year. However, in the event of a marine pollution emergency, competent authorities shall conduct monitoring (testing) in accordance with the contingency plan stipulated in Paragraph 2, Article 10 of this Act.
If the water quality in a port area meets the marine environmental quality standards for the protection of the living environment in Classification A waters for three consecutive years, the frequency of sediment testing in the port area may be adjusted to at least once every five years.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The methods of sampling, sample preservation, and examination and analysis for marine environment water quality, organisms, water quality and sediment in the port areas shall be in compliance with those officially announced by the central competent authority.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulations shall take effect on the date of promulgation.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
