<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Marine Discharge Pipe Effluent Standards</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>海洋放流管線放流水標準</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=O0040013</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20171020</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件>
  <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000003878</下載網址>
  <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000003879</下載網址>
</附件>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Original 66 articles promulgated by Environmental Protection Administration order (83) Huan-Shu-Shui-Tzu No. 31073 on July 13, 1994.
2.Revised Article 4 promulgated by Environmental Protection Administration order Huan-Shu-Shui-Tzu No. 0920041930E on June 18, 2003.
3.Revised full text in 6 articles promulgated by Environmental Protection Administration order Huan-Shu-Shui-Tzu No. 0920089957 on November 17, 2003.
4.Revised full text in 5 articles promulgated by Environmental Protection Administration order Huan-Shu-Shui-Tzu No. 1000103917 on December 1, 2011; name revised from original name of "Marine Effluent Standards".
5.Revised attached Table 1 and Table 2 in Article 4 promulgated by Environmental Protection Administration order Huan-Shu-Shui-Tzu No. 1060081235 on October 20, 2017.]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Standards are determined pursuant to Article 7, Paragraph 2 of the Water Pollution Control Act.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Standards are applicable to enterprises or sewage systems discharging wastewater or sewage into the sea via marine discharge pipes.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Enterprises or sewage systems employing marine discharge pipes to discharge wastewater or sewage into the sea must comply with the limits specified in attached Table 1 and 2.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Concerning the limits in the foregoing paragraph, apart from the pH, which is defined as a range and not in units, the rest are defined as the maximum allowed value using the following units of measure:
I. E. Coli: colony count on filter membrane per 100 mL water sample (CFU/100mL).
II. Water temperature: Celsius (℃).
III. Other items: milligrams per liter (mg/L)
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Unless an enforcement date is separately designated, these standards shall take effect on the date of promulgation.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
