<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Regulations Governing the Discharge of Oil, Wastewater or Sewage Into the Sea From Maritime Projects</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>海域工程排放油廢（污）水許可辦法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=O0050066</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20240301</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated on December 11, 2002
2.Amended and promulgated by Ocean Affairs Council Order Hai-Bao-Tzu No. 1130001352 on March 1, 2024.
]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulations are determined pursuant to Article 21 Paragraph 3 of the Marine Pollution Control Act (herein referred to as this Act).]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Those who engage in maritime projects shall not discharge oil or waste water or sewage into the sea. However, if the discharge of oil or waste water or sewage meets the standards for discharge of water via the sea discharge pipeline and does not pose a risk of lowering the marine environment categories, and if an application has been made to the central competent authority to obtain the permission for the discharge, then the discharge shall be exempted from this restriction; If a discharge is permitted, it shall be made in accordance with the contents of the permit.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The application for an oil or waste water or sewage discharge permit in accordance with the provisions of the preceding Article shall be subject to a review fee, and the following documents shall be submitted:
1. An application form.
2. The identification documents which can prove that the establishment and registration of the applicants has been approved by a government agency.
3. The identification documents, residential address and contact telephone number of the person in charge of the applicants.
4. The identification documents which can prove that the maritime project has been approved by a governmental agency to be carried out.
5. The identification documents, residential address and contact telephone number of the person in charge of the maritime project.
6. A marine pollution control plans prepared in accordance with Article 17 of the Enforcement Rules of this Act.
7. Other documents designated by the central competent authority.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[When the central competent authority receives an application for an oil and wastewater or sewage discharge, it shall complete its documentary review within two months; when necessary, may be extended for another two months, and only once.
The application documents in the  forgoing paragraph demonstrates failure to comply with these regulations or incomplete content, the central competent authority shall notify the applicant to make corrections within a limited time period. the number of days for making corrections shall not be calculated within the review period, any applications that have not been corrected by the deadline shall be rejected.
The central competent authority may, when necessary, consult with the relevant industry competent.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The discharge permits document shall record the following items:
I. Basic information
A. The name and address of the applicants
B. The name, identification document number of the statutory and address, of responsible person of the applicants.
C. The name and GPS coordinates of the marine project.
D. The name, national ID card number and address of the person in charge of the marine project.
II. Content of the discharge permit:
A. The name of marine pollution control equipment, treatment capacity and treatment efficiency.
B. The location of discharge facilities and discharge outlets.
C. The types of pollutants to be discharged, maximum permitted concentration and upper limit of discharge.
D. Other matters as stipulated by the central competent authority.
III. The validity period of the discharge permit and the permit number.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[When there are changes to the information recorded on a discharge permits document of the foregoing article, the applicant shall register the changes with the central competent authority within thirty days after the occurrence of the change. When the changes involve the content of the permit, however, the applicant shall re-apply to the central competent authority for a permit.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[If a discharge permit is damaged or lost during the validity period, the applicants shall provide a written explanation of the reason and apply to the central competent authority for a replacement by attaching the documents listed in Article 3 Paragraphs 2 to 5 within 30 days after the occurrence of the fact.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[In case the oil or waste water or sewage discharge facility of a maritime project for which a discharge permit has been issued is cancelled or in suspension of use, the applicants shall report to the central competent authority for record within 30 days from the date of cancellation or in suspension of use.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The central competent authority shall revoke or cancel the permit for the discharge of oil or waste water or sewage from a maritime project which has obtained a discharge permit under any of the following circumstances:
1. The application documents are false or untrue.
2. There are two times of violation of one of Item 2 to 4 in Article 5 Subparagraph 2 within six months.
3. There is a change in the content of the oil or waste water or sewage discharge permit without re-applying in accordance with the provisions of Article 6.
4. The applicants fail to comply with the provisions of the preceding Article.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 10</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The applicants shall, following notification of review and approval by the central competent authority, pay certificate fees before claiming a discharge permit document.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 11</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Those that violate either Articles 6, or 8,  shall be punished pursuant to Article 55 Subparagraph 6 of this Act.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 12</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulations shall take effect on the date of promulgation.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
