<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Toxic Chemical Substances Transportation Management Regulations</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>毒性化學物質運送管理辦法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=O0060015</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20181218</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件>
  <下載網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000005153</下載網址>
  <下載網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000005154</下載網址>
  <下載網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000005155</下載網址>
  <下載網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000005156</下載網址>
  <下載網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000005157</下載網址>
  <下載網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000005158</下載網址>
</附件>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated on February 8, 1991
2.Amended on March 28, 1994
3.Amended on November 15, 1995
4.Amended on August 19, 1998
5.Amended on September 29, 1999
6.Amended on January 25, 2008
7.Amended on September 28, 2009
8.Latest Revision Effective on December 18, 2018]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulations are promulgated in accordance with Paragraph 3, Article 22 of the Toxic Chemical Substances Control Act (hereinafter “this Act”).]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The term “transport manifest” as described in the Regulations refers to the ordinary transport manifest or the simplified transport manifest.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[For the following transportation conditions, owners of toxic chemical substances shall declare on the ordinary transport manifest:
1. The net weight of toxic chemical substances transported domestically by sea or land if they exceed the following amounts:
(1) Gas: Fifty kilograms;
(2) Liquid: One hundred kilograms;
(3) Solid: Two hundred kilograms.
2. Toxic chemical substances transported domestically by air.
3. Imported and exported toxic chemical substances.
The terms “gas”, “liquid” or “solid” as described in Subparagraph 1 of the preceding paragraph refers to substances in the gas, liquid or solid state at room temperature and under normal atmospheric pressure.
Where the net weight of toxic chemical substances transported domestically by sea or land does not exceed the amounts stated in Subparagraph 1 of Paragraph 1, owners of toxic chemical substances shall declare using the simplified transport manifest.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Owners of toxic chemical substances shall submit a transport manifest to the municipality or county (city) competent authority where the transportation commences.
The transport manifest shall be made according to the format prescribed by the central competent authority and be declared online. However, this shall not apply to those who have received consent from the municipality or county (city) competent authority for a declaration in writing.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The transport manifest shall be submitted with the following documents for declaration:
1. For toxic chemical substances transported by motor vehicle, a transportation plan prescribed in Article 84 of the Regulations Governing Road Traffic Safety shall be attached.
2. Transportation accident prevention and response documents.
Those whose declaration is made in writing shall not only abide by rules of the preceding paragraph, but also submit the transport manifest and a photocopy of the permit, proof of registration and other approvals issued to the owner of toxic chemical substances. The transport manifest submitted for declaration shall be preserved for three years.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[After approving and placing the stamp on the transport manifest, the municipality or county (city) competent authority shall reply to owners of toxic chemical substances online and notify the municipality or county (city) competent authority of where the transportation is destined.
Owners of toxic chemical substances shall distribute, receive and preserve approved and stamped transport manifests according to the following rules:
1. Submitted to transportation relevant organizations(agencies);
2. Preserved by owners of toxic chemical substances for future reference;
3. Given to the shipper of toxic chemical substances before the delivery;
4. Given to the consignee of toxic chemical substances before the delivery.
Where the transport manifest is declared in writing, owners of toxic chemical substances shall be liable to give the approved transport manifest to the municipality or county (city) competent authority where the transportation is destined.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The descriptions on transport manifests shall be truthful. Any amendment thereto shall be declared before transportation and shall be handled according to the preceding article.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[When transporting toxic chemical substances, owners of toxic chemical substances shall apply to the motor vehicle administration or a railway station for a transportation pass or permit according to the respective transportation methods and relevant transportation regulations.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The shipper of toxic chemical substances shall ensure the legal compliance of labels on the transportation vehicle and packages in transport.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 10</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[When transporting toxic chemical substances, the shipper shall carry the transport manifest for toxic chemical substances; corresponding material safety data sheets; transportation accident prevention and response documents; and safety equipment.
In regard to the safety equipment described in the preceding paragraph, the handler shall, according to the material safety data sheets and hazard characteristics of the substance, prepare appropriate emergency response tools, equipment and personal protection equipment (PPE).]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 11</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Shippers who transport toxic chemical substances by motor vehicle shall carry a  temporary pass; the driver or escorting personnel shall have taken professional trainings and carry certificates therefor.
The container of the transported substances as described in the preceding article shall be equipped and transported in accordance with Subparagraph 10 and Subparagraph 11 of Paragraph 1 of Article 84 of Regulations Governing Road Traffic Safety.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 12</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The shipper: shall install a real-time tracking system on the vehicle transporting toxic chemical substances as described in the preceding article; shall have the said installation approved; and shall ensure that the system functions normally. Please refer to Annexes 1, 2 and 3 for the specifications thereof.
Vehicles with the specifications of Annex 1 shall have a real-time tracking system installed according to the specifications of Annex 3 before the 1st of July, 2019; vehicles with the specifications of Annex 2 shall have a real-time tracking system installed according to the specifications of Annex 3 before the 1st of January, 2020.
Vehicles that have a real-time tracking system installed according to the specifications of Annex 1 and 2 before aforesaid deadline shall have the real-time tracking system re-installed according to the specifications of Annex 3 in any of the following circumstances:
1. The tracking system is damaged and cannot be repaired.
2. The handler of toxic chemical substances violates Article 23 of the Act.
A shipper whose declaration is made with a simplified transport manifest shall report the starting point, ending point and tracking data of the vehicle using the mobile device software prescribed by the central competent authority; and shall ensure that the said software functions normally.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 13</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Application for transporting toxic chemical substances by railway shall be handled in accordance with regulations of the Ministry of Transportation and Communications and railway agencies.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 14</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Where the name, material content or quantity of received toxic chemical substances are different with the transport manifest information, the consignee shall, within three days upon receipt of the goods, report it to the municipality or county (city) competent authority where the transportation is destined.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 15</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[An error within ± 5% of the total amount is allowed for the declaration of toxic chemical substances transported in bulk. However, within three working days the actual transportation amount must be declared to the municipality or county (city) competent authority where the transportation is destined.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 16</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Where the declaration cannot be amended due to natural disasters or other force majeure, an amendment must be applied for within three working days after the said cause is eliminated.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 17</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Regarding transportation regulations governing hazard prevention and response documents, safety equipment in Article 5 Paragraph 1, Article 8, Article 9, and Article 10 Paragraph 1 and the regulations in Article 11 Paragraph 1: if toxic chemical substances are declared using a simplified transport manifest, or if the net weight of imported/exported toxic chemical substances does not exceed the amounts stated in Article 3 Paragraph 1 Sub-paragraph 1, then the regulations stipulated shall not be applicable.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 18</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Where the toxic chemical substances are transported by motor vehicles, the municipality or county (city) competent authority may request the motor vehicle administration and police agency to conduct on-site inspection.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 19</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Apart from Paragraph 3 of Article 3 and Paragraph 2 of Article 4, which shall take effect one year after the date of promulgation; and Paragraph 4 of Article 12, which shall take effect on the 1st of July in 2020, other provisions of the Regulations shall take effect on the date of promulgation.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
