<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Standards for Determining Specific Items and Scope of Environmental Impact Assessments for Development Activities</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>開發行為應實施環境影響評估細目及範圍認定標準</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawContent.aspx?PCODE=O0090012</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20130912</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件>
  <下載網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/Law/law_getfile.ashx?FileId=0000002261</下載網址>
  <下載網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/Law/law_getfile.ashx?FileId=0000002262</下載網址>
  <下載網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/Law/law_getfile.ashx?FileId=0000002263</下載網址>
  <下載網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/Law/law_getfile.ashx?FileId=0000002264</下載網址>
  <下載網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/Law/law_getfile.ashx?FileId=0000002265</下載網址>
  <下載網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/Law/law_getfile.ashx?FileId=0000002266</下載網址>
  <下載網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/Law/law_getfile.ashx?FileId=0000002267</下載網址>
  <下載網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/Law/law_getfile.ashx?FileId=0000002268</下載網址>
</附件>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1. Promulgated by Environmental Protection Administration order (84) Huan-Shu-Tsung-Tzu No. 5406 on October 18, 1995.
2. Revisions promulgated by Environmental Protection Administration order (86) Huan-Shu-Tsung-Tzu No. 50186 on August 13, 1997.
3. Revisions promulgated by Environmental Protection Administration order (87) Huan-Shu-Tsung-Tzu No. 0042249 on July 8, 1998.
4. Some articles revised and promulgated by Environmental Protection Administration order Huan-Shu Tsung-Tzu No. 0063289 on November 1, 2000.
5. Revisions to Articles 3, 10, 14, 15, and 28, and addition of Article 31-1 promulgated by Environmental Protection Administration order (90) Huan-Shu-Tsung-Tzu No. 0061785 on October 3, 2001.
6. Revisions to Articles 4, 5, 7, 8, 10, 11, 15, 28-31, and 31-1 promulgated by Environmental Protection Administration order Huan- Shu-Tsung-Tzu No. 0910091684 on December 31, 2002.
7. Revisions to Articles 8, 10, 27, and 28 articles promulgated by Environmental Protection Administration order Huan-Shu- Tsung-Tzu No. 0930095517 on December 29, 2004.
8. Revisions to Articles 14, 19, 20, 28, 29, and 31 promulgated by Environmental Protection Administration order Huan-Shu- Tsung-Tzu No. 0950013200 on February 20, 2006.
9. Revisions to Articles 3, 10, 16, 28, 29, and 31 promulgated by Environmental Protection Administration order Huan-Shu-Tsung- Tzu No. 0960099874 on December 28, 2007.
10. Revised full text in 41 articles promulgated by Environmental Protection Administration order Huan-Shu-Tsung-Tzu No. 0980108239 on December 2, 2009.
11. Some articles revised and promulgated by EPA Order Huan-Shu-Tzong-Tzu No. 1010006607 on January 1, 2012.
12. Some articles revised and promulgated by EPA Order Huan-Shu-Tzong-Tzu No. 1020078054 on September 12, 2013.]]></沿革內容>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Standards are determined pursuant to Article 5, Paragraph 2 of the Environmental Impact Assessment Act (herein referred to as "this Act").
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The specific items and scope of environmental impact assessments to be conducted with respect to development activities prohibited under relevant laws and regulations are to be determined according to these Standards.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Where one of the following circumstances applies with respect to the establishment of a factory, an environmental impact assessment shall be required:
I. There is a newly-established or added production line in one of the industry types in Attached Table 1.
II. There is a production capacity increase in one of the industry types in Attached Table 1 meeting one of the following conditions:
A. The site is located in a national park.
B. The site is located in a wildlife preserve or an important wildlife habitat environment.
C. The site is located in an important national wetland.
D. The site is located in a nature preserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan.
E. The site is located in the water catchment area of a dam or reservoir.
F. The site is located within a water quality and quantity protection area.
G. The site is located at an elevation of over 1,500 meters.
H. The site is located in a mountain slope area, national scenic area, or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, and the application involves an area or the aggregate area to be developed greater than one hectare.
I. The site is located in farmland in a special agricultural district where farmland readjustment has been completed, the agricultural competent authority has agreed to the use change, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than one hectare.
J. The increase in production capacity exceeds ten percent. However, this restriction shall not apply when the proposed expansion does not cause any increase in the overall volume of air pollution, water pollution, or waste, and verifying documentation has been submitted to the competent authority and industry competent authority, which have granted their consent.
III. There is a newly-established or expanded production capacity in one of the industry types in one of the industry types in Attached Table 2 meeting one of the following conditions:
A. The site is located in a national park.
B. The site is located in a wildlife preserve or an important wildlife habitat environment.
C. The site is located in an important national wetland.
D. The site is located in a nature preserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan.
E. The site is located in the water catchment area of a dam or reservoir.
F. Located within a water quality and quantity protection area;This requirement does not apply, however, with respect to factories constructed in industrial zones prior to the promulgation and entry into effect of this Act, and of which the effluent drains conduct waste outside a tap-water quality and volume protection area, insofar as the increase in production capacity does not exceed 20% and an intake certificate has been duly obtained from the waste-water treatment plant of the said industrial zone.
G. The site is located at an elevation of over 1,500 meters.
H. The site is located in a mountain slope area, national scenic area, or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than one hectare.
I. The site is located in farmland in a special agricultural district where farmland readjustment has been completed, the agricultural competent authority has agreed to the use change, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than one hectare.
J. The site is located on urban land, and the application involves an area or aggregate area of land to be developed greater than 5 hectares.
K. The site is located on non-urban land, and the application involves an area or aggregate area of land to be developed greater than 10 hectares.
IV. The new establishment of, or expansion of the production capacity of, any other factory, and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The site is located in a national park. However, this restriction shall not apply when the area involved is less than 500 square meters or the aggregate area to be developed is less than 2,500 square meters, and the national park competent authority and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
B. The site is located in a wildlife preserve or an important wildlife habitat environment. However, this restriction shall not apply when the site is located in an important wildlife habitat environment, the area involved is less than 500 square meters or the aggregate area to be developed is less than 2,500 square meters, and the competent authority for important wildlife habitat environments and the industry competent authority have granted their consent.
C. The site is located in an important national wetland.
D. The site is located in a nature preserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan.
E. The site is located in the water catchment area of a dam or reservoir, and one of the following conditions applies:
1. Belongs to industry types listed on Attached Table 2-1, but is located in water catchment area of a second-class dam or reservoir. However, this restriction shall not apply when the applied-for area is less than 500 square meters or the aggregate developed area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the reservoir competent authority and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
2. Does not belong to any industry type listed on Attached Table 2-1 and is located in the water catchment area of a first-class dam or reservoir. However, this restriction shall not apply when the applied-for area is less than 500 square meters or the aggregate developed area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the reservoir competent authority and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
F. The site is located at an elevation of over 1,500 meters.
G. The site is located in a mountain slope area or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than one hectare.
H. The site is located in farmland in a special agricultural district where farmland readjustment has been completed, the agricultural competent authority has agreed to the use change, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than one hectare.
Where the provisions of Subparagraph 3, Items (h) through (k) and Subparagraph 4, Items (h) or (i) of the foregoing paragraph apply, the development or cumulative development area allowances are doubled in applications for sites located in industrial zones, export processing zones, science parks, environmental technology parks, biotechnology parks, or other parks wherein firms may locate and engage in production, manufacturing, technical services, or other services (herein referred to as "parks") for which an environmental impact assessment has already been completed.
When the case in Paragraph 1 consists of a replacement or renovation project, the production capacity and pollution output do not increase, and unit energy consumption is lower, exemption from an environmental impact assessment may be granted with the approval of the industry competent authority.
When an application for establishment of a factory within a park that has completed site preparation and development of public facilities is made, the case shall be exempt from implementation of an environmental impact assessment pursuant to regulations concerning locations in mountain slope areas in Paragraph 1, Subparagraph 2, Item (h); Subparagraph 3, Item (h); or Subparagraph 4, Item (g).
For the brewing business of fermentation industry stated in Attached Table 2 (Paragraph 1, Subparagraph 3) and plants of industries not stated in Attached Table 2-1 (Paragraph1, Subparagraph 4), if they are established outside the main island and located within the parks, and have drains to dispose and conduct the sewage outside the water catchment area of a dam or reservoir,  they shall be exempt from the environmental impact assessment stated in Paragraph 1, Subparagraph 3, Item (e); or Subparagraph 4, Item (e) 2  once received approval from local  competent authority.
For other plants stated in Paragraph 1, Subparagraph 4, whose industry types are not stated in Attached Table 1 and 2; plants with industry types stated in Subparagraph 4, Item (e) 1, Attached Table 2-1; and plants with industry types stated in Attached Table 1 or 2 – all of them shall comply with provisions stated in Paragraph 1, Subparagraph 1 through 3.
Subparagraph 4 of Paragraph 1 refers to plants dealing with gravel crushing and extracting that must comply with provisions stated in Article 10, Paragraph 1, Subparagraph 2.
When an application for establishment of a factory is made, it shall be determined in the following manner whether an environmental impact assessment shall be carried out:
I. Where factories are required to obtain a factory establishment permit prior to factory establishment, at the time of application.
II. In the following manner where factories are not required to obtain a factory establishment permit prior to factory establishment:
A. Where the factory industry type has been confirmed when applying for a factory building construction permit, it will be determined at the time of application for a construction permit.
B. Where the factory industry type was not determined when applying for a factory building construction permit, or where the scope of the factory registration application exceeds the industry type or scale stated in the construction permit application, or where the developers applying for the factory construction permit and the factory registration are not the same, it will be determined at the time of application for factory registration.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Where one of the following circumstances applies with respect to the construction of an industrial park, an environmental impact assessment shall be required:
I. The site is located in a national park.
II. The site is located in a wildlife preserve or an important wildlife habitat environment.
III. The site is located in an important national wetland.
IV. The site is located in a nature preserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan.
V. The site is located in the water catchment area of a dam or reservoir.
VI. The site is located within a water quality and quantity protection area.
VII. The site is located in an aboriginal reserve.
VIII. The site is located at an elevation of over 1,500 meters.
IX. The site is located in a mountain slope area, national scenic area, or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than one hectare.
X. The site is located in farmland in a special agricultural district where farmland readjustment has been completed, the agricultural competent authority has agreed to the use change, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than one hectare.
XI. The site is located on urban land, and the application involves an area or aggregate area of land to be developed greater than 5 hectares.
XII. The site is located on non-urban land, and the application involves an area or aggregate area of land to be developed greater than 10 hectares.
Free trade zones established within the scope of restricted areas of international airports and international ports before March 2, 2010, shall not be subject to the restrictions in the foregoing paragraph.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Where one of the following circumstances applies with respect to the construction of a road, an environmental impact assessment shall be required:
I. The construction is of a freeway or expressway.
II. A road construction or extension project, freeway or expressway extension project, or connecting road or interchange construction project, and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The site is located in a national park.
B. The site is located in a wildlife preserve or an important wildlife habitat environment.
C. The site is located in an important national wetland.
D. The site is located in a nature preserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan.
E. The site is located in the water catchment area of a dam or reservoir.
F. The site is located at an elevation of over 1,500 meters.
G. The site is located in a mountain slope area or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, and the length is 2.5 kilometers or more or the construction involves displacement of earth in excess of 100,000 cubic meters; for a site also located in a water quality and quantity protection area, a length of 1.5 kilometers or more or the construction involves displacement of earth in excess of 25,000 cubic meters.
H. The site is located in farmland in a special agricultural district where farmland readjustment has been completed, the agricultural competent authority has agreed to the use change, and the length is 2.5 kilometers or more or the construction involves displacement of earth in excess of 100,000 cubic meters, or the total length of an associated tunnel or underground roadway project is one kilometer or more.
I. The site is located in a mountain slope area, a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, urban land or non-urban land and the total length of an associated tunnel or underground roadway project is one kilometer or more.
J. The site is located on urban land or non-urban land, and the total length of an associated road viaduct, bridge, or elevated intersection project is five kilometers or more.
K. The site is located on non-urban land and exceeds 10 kilometers in length.
III. A roadway, freeway or expressway is being widened, and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The road is to be located in a national park and is 2.5 kilometers or longer, or involves the displacement of 50 thousand cubic meters or more of earth.。
B. The road is to be located in a wildlife preserve or an important wildlife habitat environment and is 1.0 kilometer or more in length.
C. The site is located in an important national wetland and exceeds one kilometer in length.
D. The site is located in a nature preserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan and exceeds one kilometer in length.
E. The site is located in the water catchment area of a dam or reservoir and exceeds one kilometer in length.
F. The site is located at an elevation of over 1,500 meters.
G. The site is located in a mountain slope area or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, widening will increase the width of the roadway by one or more vehicle lanes, or the construction involves displacement of earth in excess of 50,000 cubic meters.
H. The site is located in farmland in a special agricultural district where farmland readjustment has been completed, the agricultural competent authority has agreed to the use change, widening will increase the width of the roadway by one or more vehicle lanes, or the construction involves displacement of earth in excess of 50,000 cubic meters.
I. The road is located on non-urban land and is to be widened by the addition of one or more vehicle lanes for a distance of 10 kilometers or more.
IV. The project consists of the reconstruction, expansion, or widening of an existing viaduct, bridge, or elevated intersection, or connection with an existing road, and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The site is located in a national park and the project exceeds 2.5 kilometers in length.
B. The site is located in a wildlife refuge, important wildlife habitat environment, important national wetland, or a nature preserve or reservoir watershed area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, and the length exceeds 500 meters.
C. The site is located at an elevation of over 1,500 meters.
D. The road is 5 kilometers or more in length.
The roads in the foregoing paragraph refer to roads used for the travel of motor vehicles, and include national freeways, provincial highways, county roads, township roads, urban roads, special-use roads, and industry roads, and facilities within their site scope.
In Paragraph 1, Subparagraph 2 and Subparagraph 3, the length shall be calculated as the combined length of viaducts, bridges, elevated intersections, tunnels, underground roadways, ramps, and approach roads.
In Paragraph 1, Subparagraph 4, when the ramps or approach roads of the viaducts, bridges, or elevated intersections are elevated structures, the length of the ramps or approach roads shall be combined with that of the viaducts, bridges, or elevated intersections in length calculations.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Where one of the following circumstances applies with respect to the construction of a railway, an environmental impact assessment shall be required:
I. The construction is a widening or extension of a high-speed railway.
II. The construction is a new construction or extension of a railway other than a high-speed railway, and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The site is located in a national park.
B. The site is located in a wildlife preserve or an important wildlife habitat environment.
C. The site is located in an important national wetland.
D. The site is located in a nature preserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan.
E. The site is located in the water catchment area of a dam or reservoir.
F. The site is located at an elevation of over 1,500 meters.
G. The site is located in a mountain slope area, a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, urban land or non-urban land and the total length of an associated tunnel or underground roadway project is one kilometer or more.
H. The road is 5 kilometers or more in length.
III. Widening of a railway that is not a high-speed railway, and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The road is to be located in a national park and is 2.5 kilometers or more in length, or involves displacement of 50 thousand cubic meters or more of earth.
B. The road is to be located in a wildlife preserve or an important wildlife habitat environment and is 1.0 kilometer or more in length.>
C. The site is located in an important national wetland and exceeds one kilometer in length.
D. The site is located in a nature preserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan and exceeds one kilometer in length.
E. The site is located in the water catchment area of a dam or reservoir and exceeds one kilometer in length.
F. The site is located at an elevation of over 1,500 meters.
G. The site is located in a mountain slope area, a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, urban land or non-urban land and the total length of an associated tunnel or underground roadway project is one kilometer or more.
H. The road is 5 kilometers or more in length.
IV. The project consists of the reconstruction or expansion of an existing railway viaduct, bridge, or elevated intersection, connects with an existing railway, and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The site is located in a national park and the project exceeds 2.5 kilometers in length.
B. The site is located in a wildlife refuge, important wildlife habitat environment, important national wetland, or a nature preserve or reservoir watershed area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, and the length exceeds 500 meters.
C. The site is located at an elevation of over 1,500 meters.
D. The road is 5 kilometers or more in length.
V. A railway depot or switching yard construction or expansion project, and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The site is located in a national park. However, this restriction shall not apply when the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the national park competent authority and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
B. The site is located in a wildlife preserve or an important wildlife habitat environment. However, this restriction shall not apply when the site is located in an important wildlife habitat environment, the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the competent authority for important wildlife habitat environments and the industry competent authority have granted their consent.
C. The site is located in an important national wetland.
D. The site is located in a nature preserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan.
E. The site is located in the water catchment area of a dam or reservoir.However, this restriction shall not apply when the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the reservoir competent authority and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
F. The site is located within a water quality and quantity protection area.However, this restriction shall not apply when the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the water quality and quantity protection area competent authority and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
G. The site is located at an elevation of over 1,500 meters.
H. The site is located in a mountain slope area or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than one hectare.
I. The site is located in farmland in a special agricultural district where farmland readjustment has been completed, the agricultural competent authority has agreed to the use change, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than one hectare.
J. The site is located on urban land, and the application involves an area or aggregate area of land to be developed greater than 5 hectares.
K. The site is located on non-urban land, and the application involves an area or aggregate area of land to be developed greater than 10 hectares.
In Subparagraph 2 or 3 of the foregoing paragraph, the length shall be calculated including the combined length of viaducts, bridges, elevated intersections, tunnels, underground roadways, and approach roads.
In Paragraph 1, Subparagraph 4, when the viaducts, bridges, or elevated intersections are elevated structures, the length of the approach roads shall be combined with that of the viaducts, bridges, or elevated intersections in length calculations.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Where one of the following circumstances applies with respect to the construction of a mass rapid transit system, an environmental impact assessment shall be required:
I. The construction of a mass rapid transit system.
II. The surface, elevated, or underground length of a mass rapid transit system expansion project is one kilometer or more.
III. A depot or switch yard construction or expansion project, and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The site is located in a national park. However, this restriction shall not apply when the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the national park competent authority and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
B. The site is located in a wildlife preserve or an important wildlife habitat environment. However, this restriction shall not apply when the site is located in an important wildlife habitat environment, the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the competent authority for important wildlife habitat environments and the industry competent authority have granted their consent.
C. The site is located in an important national wetland.
D. The site is located in a nature preserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan.
E. The site is located in the water catchment area of a dam or reservoir.However, this restriction shall not apply when the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the reservoir competent authority and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
F. The site is located within a water quality and quantity protection area.However, this restriction shall not apply when the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the water quality and quantity protection area competent authority and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
G. The site is located at an elevation of over 1,500 meters.
H. The site is located in a mountain slope area or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than one hectare.
I. The site is located in farmland in a special agricultural district where farmland readjustment has been completed, the agricultural competent authority has agreed to the use change, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than one hectare.
J. The site is located on urban land, and the application involves an area or aggregate area of land to be developed greater than 5 hectares.
K. The site is located on non-urban land, and the application involves an area or aggregate area of land to be developed greater than 10 hectares.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Where one of the following circumstances applies with respect to the construction of a harbor, an environmental impact assessment shall be required:
I. The construction is of a commercial, military, fishing or industrial harbor.
II. The construction or expansion of a yacht marina, and one of the following conditions applies. When the site is:
A. The site is located in a national park. However, this restriction shall not apply when the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the national park competent authority and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
B. The site is located in a wildlife preserve or an important wildlife habitat environment. However, this restriction shall not apply when the site is located in an important wildlife habitat environment, the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the competent authority for important wildlife habitat environments and the industry competent authority have granted their consent.
C. The site is located in an important national wetland.
D. The site is located in a nature preserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan.
E. The site is located in the water catchment area of a dam or reservoir.However, this restriction shall not apply when the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the reservoir competent authority and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
F. The site is located within a water quality and quantity protection area.However, this restriction shall not apply when the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the water quality and quantity protection area competent authority and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
G. The site is located in an aboriginal reserve.However, this restriction shall not apply when the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the aboriginal reserve authority and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
H. The site is located in a mountain slope area or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than one hectare.
I. The site is located in farmland in a special agricultural district where farmland readjustment has been completed, the agricultural competent authority has agreed to the use change, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than one hectare.
J. Designed to accommodate the moorage of one hundred or more vessels, or where the aggregate total of moorage places in separate development projects for a single location exceeds two hundred vessels.
III. The expansion of a commercial, military, fishing or industrial harbor (excluding expansion projects within the existing harbor scope), or the construction or expansion of cargo loading and unloading facilities or other special facilities located outside a commercial port area, and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The site is subject to the provisions of items (a) to (c) of the foregoing subparagraph.
B. A dock or breakwater where the length covered by the application or the aggregate developed length exceeds 500 meters in length.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Where one of the following circumstances applies with respect to the construction of an airport, an environmental impact assessment shall be conducted:
I. The construction is of an airport.
II. Construction of an airport runway, extension of a runway by 500 meters or more, or the relocation of a runway center line.
III. Expansion of an airport passenger terminal, freight terminal, parking facility, or airport roads, and the applied-for area or the aggregate developed area is five hectares or more.
IV. Construction or expansion of a civil airport such as a heliport (excluding heliports exclusively used for emergency medical care by general hospitals), and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The site is located in a national park. However, this restriction shall not apply when the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the national park competent authority and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
B. The site is located in a wildlife preserve or an important wildlife habitat environment. However, this restriction shall not apply when the site is located in an important wildlife habitat environment, the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the competent authority for important wildlife habitat environments and the industry competent authority have granted their consent.
C. The site is located in an important national wetland.
D. The site is located in a nature preserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan.
E. The site is located in an aboriginal reserve. However, this restriction shall not apply when the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the aboriginal reserve authority and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
F. The site is located within a water quality and quantity protection area.However, this restriction shall not apply when the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the water quality and quantity protection area competent authority and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
G. The site is located at an elevation of over 1,500 meters.
H. The application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed that exceeds one hectare or that handles more than twenty flights per day.
V. Construction or expansion of aircraft maintenance hangars (excluding those located within the scope of a fully-developed airport), and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The site is located in a national park. However, this restriction shall not apply when the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the national park competent authority and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
B. The site is located in a wildlife preserve or an important wildlife habitat environment. However, this restriction shall not apply when the site is located in an important wildlife habitat environment, the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the competent authority for important wildlife habitat environments and the industry competent authority have granted their consent.
C. The site is located in an important national wetland.
D. The site is located in a nature preserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan.
E. The site is located in an aboriginal reserve. However, this restriction shall not apply when the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the aboriginal reserve authority and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
F. The site is located at an elevation of over 1,500 meters.
G. The site is located in a mountain slope area or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than one hectare.
H. The application involves an area or aggregate area of land to be developed that is greater than 5 hectares.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 10</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Where one of the following circumstances applies with respect to the extraction of earth and gravel, an environmental impact assessment shall be conducted:
I. Extraction of earth and gravel (excluding the extraction of clay by brick and tile enterprises) and related expansion projects, and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The site is located in a national park.
B. The site is located in a wildlife preserve or an important wildlife habitat environment.
C. The site is located in an important national wetland.
D. The site is located in a nature preserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan.
E. The site is located in an aboriginal reserve.
F. The site is located in the water catchment area of a dam or reservoir.
G. The site is located at an elevation of over 1,500 meters.
H. The extraction site is located in a marine area. However, maintenance dredging within the scope of an existing harbor shall not be subject to this restriction.
I. The site is located in a mountain slope area, national scenic area, or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, and the applied-for area or the aggregate developed area is five hectares or more (including the surface area of any access roadways that must be built), or is in a riverbed and the application involves an extraction zone or aggregate extraction zone that extends for 500 meters or more along the river, or involves extraction of more than 800,000 cubic meters of earth and gravel.
J. The site is located in a mountain slope area, national scenic area, or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, and is also located in a water quality and quantity protection area, the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed that is 2.5 hectares or more (including the surface area of any access roadways that must be built), or that is in a riverbed, or that involves an extraction zone or aggregate extraction zone that extends for 250 meters or more along the river, or that involves extraction of more than 400,000 cubic meters of earth and gravel.
K. The site is located in farmland in a special agricultural district where farmland readjustment has been completed, the agricultural competent authority has agreed to the use change, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed that is five hectares or more (including the surface area of any access roadways that must be built), or that involves extraction of more than 800,000 cubic meters of earth and gravel.
L. The application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed that exceeds ten hectares or is in a riverbed, or that involves an extraction zone or aggregate extraction zone that extends for 1,000 meters or more along the river, or that involves the extraction of more than 400,000 cubic meters of earth and gravel.
M. Extraction zones are located in a mountain slope area, and one of the following conditions is present, the respective surface areas of the various extraction sites shall be added together, and when this aggregate figure falls within the scope set out in items (i) or (j) above, these sites shall be grouped under one application:
1. The extraction sites are within one lot under the same land number.
2. The extraction site land numbers are adjacent to or connected to one another.
3. The horizontal distance between the boundaries of extraction sites is within a range of 500 meters.
N. When the extraction zone is not located in a mountain-slope area but is located within a water quality and quantity protection area and one of the following conditions is present then the area to be developed in the application shall be added together and must reach a size specified in Items (j) through (l):
1. The extraction sites are within one lot under the same land number.
2. The extraction site land numbers are adjacent to or connected to one another.
3. The horizontal distance between the boundaries of extraction sites is within a range of 500 meters.
II. The construction or expansion of the sizing and washing plant of an earth or gravel extraction operation, and one of the following conditions applies. When the site:
A. The site is subject to the provisions of Items (a) to (e), and Item (g) of the foregoing subparagraph.
B. Located in the water catchment area of a dam or reservoir. However, if the case belongs to a weir catchment area that only crushes and extracts earth and gravels from the river; has less than one hectare of applied or aggregate development area; already installed waste water or sewage treatment facilities; has an outfall that is at least 1 kilomeer away from the boarder of the reservoir storage area as confirmed by the reservoir management agency (entity), it is not limited by this regulation as long as it receives consent from the local  competent authority..
C. The site is located in a mountain slope area, national scenic area, or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than one hectare.
D. The site is located in farmland in a special agricultural district where farmland readjustment has been completed, the agricultural competent authority has agreed to the use change, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than one hectare.
E. The application of this site involves an area or aggregate area of land to be developed greater than 10 hectares.
III. A brick and tile enterprise applies for or expands its extraction of clay, and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The site is located in a national park.
B. The site is located in a wildlife preserve or an important wildlife habitat environment.
C. The site is located in an important national wetland.
D. The site is located in a nature preserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan.
E. The site is located in an aboriginal reserve.
F. The site is located in the water catchment area of a dam or reservoir.
G. The site is located at an elevation of over 1,500 meters.
H. The site is located in a mountain slope area, national scenic area, or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed that is five hectares or more (including the surface area of any access roadways that must be built), or the application is for extraction of more than 800,000 cubic meters of earth and gravel.
I. The site is located in a mountain slope area, national scenic area, or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, and is also located in a water quality and quantity protection area, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed that is 2.5 hectares or more (including the surface area of any access roadways that must be built) or the the extraction of more than 400,000 cubic meters of earth and gravel.
J. The site is located in farmland in a special agricultural district where farmland readjustment has been completed, the agricultural competent authority has agreed to the use change, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed that is five hectares or more (including the surface area of any access roadways that must be built), or that involves extraction of more than 800,000 cubic meters of earth and gravel.
K. The application involves an area or aggregate area of land to be developed that is 5 hectares.
Any government-approved dredging projects that fall under subparagraph 1 of the foregoing paragraph shall be conducted in accordance with the provisions of Article 14, subparagraph 2.
When two or more applications for earth and gravel extraction zones are made at the same time (excluding the extraction of clay by brick and tile producers), and any of the conditions described in Paragraph 1, Subparagraph 1, Items (m) or (n) are present due to subsequent applications, and in addition the combined area covered by the applications or aggregate developed area falls within one of the scopes specified in Paragraph 1, Subparagraph 1, Items (i) through (l), then an environmental impact assessment shall be conducted for each such subsequent extraction zone application when the industry competent authority does not grant its consent.
The combined calculation of extraction zone areas as prescribed in Paragraph 1 Subparagraph 1, Items (m) or (n) shall include the following situations:
I. Development permission has been received.
II. The application has not yet received permission for development from the industry competent authority.
III. The industry competent authoritys approval has been annulled for less than one year.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 11</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Where one of the following circumstances applies with respect to a mining exploration or extraction operation, an environmental impact assessment shall be conducted:
I. There is development or expansion of mining exploration or extraction operations, and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The site is located in a national park.
B. The site is located in a wildlife preserve or an important wildlife habitat environment.
C. The site is located in an important national wetland.
D. The site is located in a nature preserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan.
E. The site is located in an aboriginal reserve.
F. The site is located in the water catchment area of a dam or reservoir.
G. The site is located at an elevation of over 1,500 meters.
H. The extraction site is located in a marine area. However, sites that do not involve drilling or excavation mining shall not be subject to this restriction.
I. The site is located in a mountain slope area, national scenic area, or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, and the application involves an area or aggregate area of land (including the surface area of any access roadways that must be built) designated for mining use is two hectares or more, or the application involves an area or aggregate area of land designated for mining use that is in a riverbed extending for 1 kilometer or more along the river.
J. The site is located in a mountain slope area, national scenic area, or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, is also located in a water quality and quantity protection area, and the application involves an area or aggregate area of land (including the surface area of any access roadways that must be built) designated for mining use that is one hectare or more, or the application involves an area or aggregate area of land designated for mining use that is in a riverbed extending for 500 meters or more along the river.
K. The site is located in farmland in a special agricultural district where farmland readjustment has been completed, the agricultural competent authority has agreed to the use change, and the application involes an area or aggregate area of the land (including the surface area of any access roadways that must be built) designated for mining use that is two hectares or more.
L. The area of the land under application for mining use (including the surface area of any access roadways that must be built) is five hectares or more.
M. When sites under application for mining use are located in a mountain slope area, and one of the following conditions is present, the respective areas of the sites or the aggregate approved areas under application shall be calculated on a combined basis, and that area falls within one of the scopes specified in Item (i) or Item (j):
1. The sites under application for mining use or aggregate approved mining sites are located within the same land lot number.
2. The land lot numbers of the approved mining sites or aggregate approved mining sites under application are adjacent to or connected to one another.
3. The horizontal distance between the boundaries of the approved mining sites or aggregate approved mining sites are within a scope of 500 meters.
II. The construction or expansion of mine smelting or sizing and washing plants, and one of the following conditions applies.
A. The site is subject to the provisions of items (a) to (g) of the foregoing subparagraph.
B. The site is located in a mountain slope area, national scenic area, or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than one hectare.
C. The site is located in farmland in a special agricultural district where farmland readjustment has been completed, the agricultural competent authority has agreed to the use change, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than one hectare.
D. The application involves an area or aggregate area of land to be developed that is greater than 5 hectares.
When two or more applications for the development or expansion of mining areas are made at the same time, and any of the conditions described in subparagraph 1, item (l) of the foregoing paragraph are present, and in addition the aggregate surface area of the development application falls within the scope set out in subparagraph 1, items (i) or (j) of the foregoing paragraph, then an environmental impact assessment shall be conducted for each such mining area.
Applications for the development or expansion of mining areas under paragraph 1, subparagraph 1 are subject to a prior overall environmental impact assessment of the Mining District to which the area belongs.
The mining areas subject to combined calculation as specified in Paragraph 1, Subparagraph 1, Item 13 shall include the following situations:
I. Development permission has been received.
II. The application has not yet received permission for development from the industry competent authority.
III. The industry competent authoritys approval has been annulled for less than one year.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 12</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Where one of the following circumstances applies with respect to the development of a reservoir, an environmental impact assessment shall be conducted:
I. When a reservoir is to be built and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The site is located in a national park.
B. The site is located in a wildlife preserve or an important wildlife habitat environment.
C. The site is located in an important national wetland.
D. The site is located in a nature preserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan.
E. The site is located in an aboriginal reserve.
F. The site is located at an elevation of over 1,500 meters.
G. When the project features a retaining dam wall of 15 meters or more in height, or a volume of water stored in excess of 5 million cubic meters; when located in a tap-water quality and volume protection area, these figures are reduced to a retaining dam wall of 7.5 meters or more in height, or a volume of water stored in excess of 2.5 million cubic meters.
H. When the area of the water storage scope in the application is 100 hectares or more.
II. When the expansion of a reservoir or raising of sluice channels falls within the scope of of one of the items (a) to (f) of the foregoing subparagraph, or when the retaining dam is raised by 2 or more meters.
III. When the work involves cross-boundary channeling.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 13</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Where one of the following circumstances applies with respect to water supply, water pumping or water diversion project development, an environmental impact assessment shall be conducted:
I. When a water pumping or water diversion project is to be built and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The volume pumped or diverted surface or underflow water exceeds 2 cubic meters per second. However, this restriction shall not apply when seawater is pumped for use as cooling water or aquaculture water, or water is pumped or diverted for agricultural irrigation use.
B. The volume of pumped groundwater exceeds 0.2 cubic meters per second.
C. The volume of pumped hot springs water (excluding natural outflowing hot springs) exceeds 0.02 cubic meters per second.
D. This restriction shall not apply when groundwater is pumped from a groundwater control area. However, when the volume of pumped groundwater is less than 0.2 cubic meters per second, or the volume of pumped hot springs water (excluding natural outflowing hot springs) is less than 0.02 cubic meters per second, or groundwater is pumped for the purpose of project construction, and the consent of the groundwater control area competent authority has been received, or groundwater is pumped for the purpose of groundwater pollution improvement or remediation, testing water quality, or performing an investigation of hydrological or geological characteristics.
II. Construction or expansion of a seawater desalination plant, and the application involves a daily design water volume of 1,000 tons or more.
III. One of the following circumstances applies to the construction or expansion of a water treatment plant or industrial water supply treatment plant:
A. The site is located in a national park. However, this restriction shall not apply when the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the national park competent authority and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
B. The site is located in a wildlife preserve or an important wildlife habitat environment. However, this restriction shall not apply when the site is located in an important wildlife habitat environment, the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the competent authority for important wildlife habitat environments and the industry competent authority have granted their consent.
C. The site is located in an important national wetland.
D. The site is located in a nature preserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan.
E. The site is located at an elevation of over 1,500 meters.
F. The site is located in a mountain slope area or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, and the application involves an area to be developed greater than one hectare.
G. The site is located in farmland in a special agricultural district where farmland readjustment has been completed, the agricultural competent authority has agreed to the use change, and the application involves an area to be developed greater than one hectare.
H. The application involves design water capacity of 200,000 tons or more.
Where plants falling under items (a) to (e) of the foregoing paragraph are simple water treatment facilities, exemption from an environmental impact assessment may be granted with the approval of the competent authority and the industry competent authority.
Where works falling under item (a) of subparagraph 1 are temporary pumping or channeling projects undertaken for the immediate relief of drought, exemption from an environmental impact assessment may be granted with the approval of the competent authority and the industry competent authority.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 14</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Where one of the following circumstances applies with respect to the development of flood control and drainage systems, an environmental impact assessment shall be conducted:
I. River channel modification project.This does not apply to such modifications as occur naturally.
II. River channel dredging projects that extend for 50 kilometers or more along a river, or dredging projects in a single river and its tributaries of an aggregate length of 50 kilometers or more, or dredging projects in a single river system of an aggregate length of 15 kilometers or more. However, the length of any dredging projects that have already been subjected to environmental impact assessment review or have been completed shall not be included in the aggregate length.
III. Construction or expansion of flood control and drainage systems or irrigation projects including flood control and drainage systems (excluding height increase and strengthening projects), and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The site is located in a national park. However, this restriction shall not apply when the appliedfor expansion length is less than 500 meters, and the national park competent authority and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
B. The site is located in a wildlife preserve or an important wildlife habitat environment. However, this restriction shall not apply when the site is located in an important wildlife habitat environment, the applied-for expansion length is less than 500 meters, and the important wildlife habitat environment competent authority and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
C. The site is located in an important national wetland.However, this restriction shall not apply when the applied-for expansion length is less than 500 meters, and the wetlands competent authority and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
D. The site is located in a nature preserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan. However, this restriction shall not apply when the appliedfor expansion length is less than 500 meters, and the competent authority in charge of the nature reserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
E. A single drainage waterway extends along a river for 10 kilometers or has a total length of 20 kilometers or more. However, the length of completed drainage channels shall not be included in the aggregate total.
F. River embankment projects that extend for 10 kilometers or more along a river, or embankment projects in a single river and its tributaries of an aggregate length of 20 kilometers or more, or embankment projects in a single river system of an aggregate length of 30 kilometers or more. However, the length of a completed river embankment shall not be included in the aggregate total.
IV. A flood detention pond project for flood control and drainage, and the applied-for development is 100 hectares or more. However, this restriction shall not apply when disused salt fields or fish ponds are used for development, or the site is located in a severe ground subsidence area.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 15</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Where one of the following circumstances applies with respect to the development of agricultural, forestry, fishing or grazing lands and the establishment in such areas of recreational farms providing lodging, dining, or hot springs services, or processing plants (not including agricultural product processing rooms used in agricultural industry distribution and processing) for agricultural products, an environmental impact assessment shall be conducted:
I. The site is located in a national park.However, this restriction shall not apply when the area involved is less than 500 square meters or the aggregate area to be developed is less than 2,500 square meters, and the national park competent authority and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
II. The site is located in a wildlife preserve or an important wildlife habitat environment.However, this restriction shall not apply when the site is located in an important wildlife habitat environment, the area involved is less than 500 square meters or the aggregate area to be developed is less than 2,500 square meters, and the competent authority for important wildlife habitat environments and the industry competent authority have granted their consent.
III. The site is located in an important national wetland.
IV. The site is located in a nature preserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan.
V. The site is located at an elevation of over 1,500 meters.
VI. The site is located in a mountain slope area or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, and the application involves an area or aggregate area of land to be developed of ten hectares or more, or involves displacement of earth in excess of 100,000 cubic meters; for a site also located in a water quality and quantity protection area, the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed that is five hectares or more, or involves the displacement of earth in excess of 50,000 cubic meters.
VII. The application involves an area or aggregate area of land to be developed that is greater than 30 hectares.
In the foregoing paragraph, processing plants for agricultural products must apply for factory establishment registration, and shall be handled pursuant to Article 3.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 16</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[With regard to development or use of forest lands or forests as prescribed in the Forestry Act, an environmental impact assessment shall be conducted when any one of the following situations applies to the logging of forest trees:
I. The site is located in a wildlife preserve or an important wildlife habitat environment. However, this restriction shall not apply when the area of clear-cut logging is less than 500 square meters or the aggregate area of clear-cut logging sites cut during the most recent five years in the same protection area or important wildlife habitat environment is less than 2,500 square meters, and the competent authority in charge of the wildlife refuge or important wildlife habitat environment and forestry competent authority have granted their consent.
II. The site is located in an important national wetland. However, this restriction shall not apply when the area of clear-cut logging is less than 500 square meters or the aggregate area of clear-cut logging sites cut during the most recent five years in the same wetlands is less than 2,500 square meters, and the national important wetlands competent authority and forestry competent authority have granted their consent.
III. The site is located in a nature preserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan. However, this restriction shall not apply when the area of clear-cut logging is less than 500 square meters or the aggregate area of clear-cut logging sites cut during the most recent five years in the same nature preserve is less than 2,500 square meters, and the competent authority in charge of the nature reserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan and forestry competent authority have granted their consent.
IV. The site is located at an elevation of over 1,500 meters. However, this restriction shall not apply when the area of clear-cut logging is less than 500 square meters and the forestry competent authority has granted its consent.
V. The site is located in a mountain slope area or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, and the clear-cut logging area is two hectares or more.
VI. Clear-cut logging is to be conducted over an area of 4 hectares or more.
In the foregoing paragraph, after the forestry competent authority grants its consent, exemption from an environmental impact assessment may be obtained in the case of logging conducted in plantation forests on lowland plains, or logging in forests damaged by natural disasters or pests.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 17</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Where one of the following circumstances applies with respect to constructions related to fish farms or fish ponds, an environmental impact assessment shall be conducted:
I. The site is located in a wildlife preserve or an important wildlife habitat environment. However, this restriction shall not apply when the site is located in an important wildlife habitat environment and the application involves an area to be developed that is greater than 500 square meters, and the important wildlife habitat environment competent authority and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
II. The site is located in an important national wetland.
III. The site is located in a nature preserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan.
IV. The site is located in an underground water control area, and the area of land the application addresses is greater than 25 hectares.
V. The area of land to be developed is 50 hectares or more.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 18</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Where one of the following circumstances applies with respect to the establishment of a livestock farming operation on grazing land, an environmental impact assessment shall be conducted:
I. The site is located in a national park.However, this restriction shall not apply when the area involved is less than 500 square meters or the aggregate area to be developed is less than 2,500 square meters, and the national park competent authority and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
II. The site is located in a wildlife preserve or an important wildlife habitat environment.However, this restriction shall not apply when the site is located in an important wildlife habitat environment, the area involved is less than 500 square meters or the aggregate area to be developed is less than 2,500 square meters, and the competent authority for important wildlife habitat environments and the industry competent authority have granted their consent.
III. The site is located in an important national wetland.
IV. The site is located in a nature preserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan.
V. The site is located at an elevation of over 1,500 meters.
VI. The site is located in a mountain slope area or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than one hectare.
VII. The application involves an area or aggregate area of land to be developed that is greater than 5 hectares.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 19</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Agencies, public enterprises and organizations, schools below the senior high school level and juridical associations who derive more than 50 percent of their income from government donations shall draw up an environmental education plan before January 31 each year to promote environmental education. All employees, teachers, and students shall participate in more than four hours of environmental education before December 31 each year. The implementation results of environmental education during the current year are to be reported to the central competent authority via the Internet before January 31 in the following year.
I. A recreational area or zoological garden is to be built or expanded and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The site is located in a wildlife preserve or an important wildlife habitat environment.However, this restriction shall not apply when the site is located in an important wildlife habitat environment, the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the competent authority for important wildlife habitat environments and the industry competent authority have granted their consent.
B. The site is located in an important national wetland.
C. The site is located in a nature preserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan.
D. The site is located at an elevation of over 1,500 meters.
E. The site is located in a mountain slope area or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed that is five hectares or more, or involves the displacement of earth in excess of 50,000 cubic meters; for sites located in a water quality and quantity protection area, the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed that is 2.5 hectares or more, or involves the displacement of earth in excess of 25,000 cubic meters.
F. The site is located in farmland in a special agricultural district where farmland readjustment has been completed, the agricultural competent authority has agreed to the use change, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than five hectares or more, or involves the displacement of earth in excess of 50,000 cubic meters.
G. The application involves an area or aggregate area of land to be developed that is greater than 5 hectares.
II. A recreational facility area is to be built or expanded in a forest recreation area and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The site is located in a wildlife preserve or an important wildlife habitat environment. However, this restriction shall not apply when the site is located in an important wildlife habitat environment, the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the competent authority for important wildlife habitat environments and the industry competent authority have granted their consent.
B. The site is located in an important national wetland.
C. The site is located in a nature preserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan.
D. The site is located at an elevation of over 1,500 meters.
E. The site is located in a mountain slope area or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed that is five hectares or more, or involves the displacement of earth in excess of 50,000 cubic meters; for sites located in a water quality and quantity protection area, the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed that is 2.5 hectares or more, or involves the displacement of earth in excess of 25,000 cubic meters.
F. The site is located in farmland in a special agricultural district where farmland readjustment has been completed, the agricultural competent authority has agreed to the use change, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than five hectares or more, or involves the displacement of earth in excess of 50,000 cubic meters.
III. Recreational facilities are to be built or expanded in a recreational area of a national park and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The site is located in an important national wetland.
B. The site is located in a nature preserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan.
C. The site is located within a tap-water water quality and volume protection area.However, this restriction shall not apply when the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the water quality and quantity protection area competent authority and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
D. The site is located at an elevation of over 1,500 meters.
E. The application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed that is five hectares or more, or involves the displacement of earth in excess of 50,000 cubic meters.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 20</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Where one of the following circumstances applies with respect to the construction or expansion of recreational facilities or sports parks in scenic areas, an environmental impact assessment shall be conducted:
I. The site is located in a wildlife preserve or an important wildlife habitat environment. However, this restriction shall not apply when the site is located in an important wildlife habitat environment, the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the competent authority for important wildlife habitat environments and the industry competent authority have granted their consent.
II. The site is located in an important national wetland.
III. The site is located in a nature preserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan.
IV. The site is located at an elevation of over 1,500 meters.
V. The site is located in a mountain slope area or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed that is five hectares or more, or involves the displacement of earth in excess of 50,000 cubic meters; for sites located in a water quality and quantity protection area, the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed that is 2.5 hectares or more, or involves the displacement of earth in excess of 25,000 cubic meters.
VI. The site is located in farmland in a special agricultural district where farmland readjustment has been completed, the agricultural competent authority has agreed to the use change, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than five hectares or more, or involves the displacement of earth in excess of 50,000 cubic meters.
VII. The application involves an area or aggregate area of land to be developed that is greater than 5 hectares.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 21</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Where one of the following circumstances applies with respect to the construction or expansion of golf course, an environmental impact assessment shall be conducted:
I. The site is located in a national park.
II. The site is located in a wildlife preserve or an important wildlife habitat environment.
III. The site is located in an important national wetland.
IV. The site is located in a nature preserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan.
V. The site is located at an elevation of over 1,500 meters.
VI. The site is located in a mountain slope area or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed that is five hectares or more, or involves displacement of earth in excess of 50,000 cubic meters.
VII. The site is located in farmland in a special agricultural district where farmland readjustment has been completed, the agricultural competent authority has agreed to the use change, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than five hectares or more, or involves the displacement of earth in excess of 50,000 cubic meters.
VIII. The application involves an area or aggregate area of land to be developed that is greater than 5 hectares.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 22</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Where one of the following circumstances applies with respect to the construction or expansion of sports grounds, an environmental impact assessment shall be conducted:
I. The site is located in a wildlife preserve or an important wildlife habitat environment. However, this restriction shall not apply when the site is located in an important wildlife habitat environment, the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the competent authority for important wildlife habitat environments and the industry competent authority have granted their consent.
II. The site is located in an important national wetland.
III. The site is located in a nature preserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan.
IV. The site is located at an elevation of over 1,500 meters.
V. The site is located in a mountain slope area or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, and the application involves an area or aggregate area for indoor ball courts or sports complex to be developed that is one hectare or more, or involves the displacement of earth in excess of 50,000 cubic meters.
VI. The site is located in farmland in a special agricultural district where farmland readjustment has been completed, the agricultural competent authority has agreed to the use change, and the application involves an area or aggregate area for indoor ball courts or sports complex to be developed that is greater than five hectares or more, or involves the displacement of earth in excess of 50,000 cubic meters.
VII. The indoor ball courts or sports complex application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed that is greater than 3 hectares.
VIII. The sports grounds application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed that is 5 hectares or more.
A sports grounds located within a school, and chiefly provided for the use of the schools students and teachers for instructional purposes, is deemed a cultural and educational development.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 23</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Where one of the following circumstances applies with respect to a cultural and educational development, an environmental impact assessment shall be conducted:
I. The development consists of the construction or expansion of any kind of cultural, educational, or training facility or research organization, and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The site is located in a national park. However, this restriction shall not apply when the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed that is less than one hectare, and the national park competent authority and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
B. The site is located in a wildlife preserve or an important wildlife habitat environment. However, this restriction shall not apply when the applied-for area is less than 500 square meters or the aggregate developed area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the competent authority for important wildlife preserve habitat environments and the industry competent authority have granted their consent.
C. The site is located in an important national wetland. However, this restriction shall not apply when the area involved is less than 500 square meters or the aggregate area to be developed is less than 2,500 square meters, and the competent authority for important national wetlands and the industry competent authority have granted their consent.
D. The site is located in a nature preserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan. However, this restriction shall not apply when the appliedfor area is less than 500 square meters or the aggregate developed area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the competent authority in charge of the nature reserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan and the industry competent authority have granted their consent.
E. The site is located at an elevation of over 1,500 meters.
F. The site is located in a mountain slope area or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed that is five hectares or more; for a site also located in a water quality and quantity protection area or reservoir watershed areas, the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed that exceeds one hectare.
G. The site is located in farmland in a special agricultural district where farmland readjustment has been completed, the agricultural competent authority has agreed to the use change, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than five hectares.
H. The application involves an area or aggregate area of land to be developed that is greater than 5 hectares.
II. A livestock area attached to an educational or research institution is to be built or expanded and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The site is located in a national park. However, this restriction shall not apply when the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the national park competent authority and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
B. The site is located in a wildlife preserve or an important wildlife habitat environment. However, this restriction shall not apply when the site is located in an important wildlife habitat environment, the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the competent authority for important wildlife habitat environments and the industry competent authority have granted their consent.
C. The site is located in an important national wetland.
D. The site is located in a nature preserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan.
E. The site is located at an elevation of over 1,500 meters.
F. The site is located in a mountain slope area or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than one hectare.
G. The site is located on urban land, and the application involves an area or aggregate area of land to be developed greater than 5 hectares.
H. The site is located on non-urban land, and the application involves an area or aggregate area of land to be developed greater than 10 hectares.
III. The construction or expansion of a chemical, pharmaceutical, biological, hazardous substance, synchrotron radiation, or high energy laboratory established by a research organization apart from a school or hospital, and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The site is subject to the provisions of items (a) to (f) of the foregoing subparagraph.
B. The site is located in farmland in a special agricultural district where farmland readjustment has been completed, the agricultural competent authority has agreed to the use change, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than one hectare.
C. The site is located on urban land, and the application involves an area or aggregate area of land to be developed greater than 5 hectares.
D. The site is located on non-urban land, and the application involves an area or aggregate area of land to be developed greater than 2 hectares.
IV. The construction or expansion of a religious temple or church complies with the requirements of one of Items (a) through (f) in Subparagraph 2, or the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed that is five hectares or more.
In Subparagraph 3 of the foregoing paragraph, the area or aggregate area to be developed is doubled for an application to establish a research organization in a park which has completed environmental impact assessment review.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 24</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Where one of the following circumstances applies with respect to the construction or expansion of medical facilities, an environmental impact assessment shall be conducted:
I. The site is located in a national park. However, this restriction shall not apply when the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed that is less than one hectare, and the national park competent authority and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
II. The site is located in a wildlife preserve or an important wildlife habitat environment.However, this restriction shall not apply when the site is located in an important wildlife habitat environment, the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the competent authority for important wildlife habitat environments and the industry competent authority have granted their consent.
III. The site is located in an important national wetland.
IV. The site is located in a nature preserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan.
V. The site is located within a water quality and quantity protection area.However, this restriction shall not apply when the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the water quality and quantity protection area competent authority and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
VI. The site is located at an elevation of over 1,500 meters.
VII. The site is located in a mountain slope area or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than one hectare.
VIII. The site is located in farmland in a special agricultural district where farmland readjustment has been completed, the agricultural competent authority has agreed to the use change, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than one hectare.
IX. The application involves an area or aggregate area of land to be developed that is greater than 5 hectares.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 25</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Where one of the following circumstances applies with respect to the development of a new urban district, an environmental impact assessment shall be required:
I. The construction or expansion of a community, and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The site is located in a national park. However, this restriction shall not apply when the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed that is less than one hectare or less than 100 residences or 500 residents, and the national park competent authority and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
B. The site is located in a wildlife preserve or an important wildlife habitat environment.
C. The site is located in an important national wetland.
D. The site is located in a nature preserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan.
E. The site is located within a water quality and quantity protection area. However, this restriction shall not apply when the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed that is less than one hectare or less than 100 residences or 500 residents, and the competent authority for tap water quality and quantity protection areas and the industry competent authority have granted their consent.
F. The site is located at an elevation of over 1,500 meters. However, this restriction shall not apply to indigenous communities when the indigenous competent authority has granted its consent.
G. The site is located in a mountain slope area or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than one hectare.
H. The site is located in farmland in a special agricultural district where farmland readjustment has been completed, the agricultural competent authority has agreed to the use change, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than one hectare.
I. The site is located on non-urban land, and the application involves an area or aggregate area of land to be developed greater than 10 hectares.
II. Construction of a new town.
III. Application to expand a new town, when the aggregate surface area of the various expansion zones exceeds ten percent of the area of the initial new town development.
Where a residential area as defined in subparagraph 1 of the foregoing paragraph above is located in a mountain slope area, and the area of land or aggregate area of land that the application addresses is less than one hectare, but when combined with adjoining land is greater than one hectare, an environmental impact assessment shall be conducted when one of the following conditions applies:
I. When no miscellaneous permit has been obtained: When the lot the application addresses adjoins another lot on mountain slope land upon which a residence is being built but has not yet been completed (application is pending for miscellaneous permits or for a construction permit, or landpreparation work or construction work is under way, or for which a usage permit has not been issued), and where plans for 2 or more projects indicate linking to or the use of the same public facilities, and where the aggregate surface area of these lots is more than 1 hectare, an environmental impact assessment shall be conducted in respect of the new application.
II. When no construction permit has been issued: When a construction permit has been issued within the preceding year for land adjoining the land the new application addresses, and where plans for 2 or more projects indicate linking to or the use of the same public facilities, and where the aggregate surface area of these lots is more than 1 hectare, an environmental impact assessment shall be conducted in respect of the new application.
III. When 2 or more applications made originally by different persons have obtained construction permits, but construction has not yet begun, and the applications are altered to be in the name of one person only, and the surface area to be developed is more than one hectare, an environmental impact assessment shall be conducted.
The public facility systems referred to in the foregoing paragraph are drainage systems, wastewater treatment systems or underground parking lots located within the lot.
When an environmental impact assessment is conducted pursuant to the regulations of Paragraph 1, Subparagraph 1, if the land has been obtained through urban land readjustment or zone expropriation, the environmental impact assessment should be conducted before approval of the detailed urban plan.
When an environmental impact assessment has not been performed by the time of completion of urban land readjustment or zone expropriation, the community construction or expansion shall be handled pursuant to the regulations of Paragraph 1, Subparagraph 1. However, the case shall be exempt from an environmental impact assessment pursuant to this article when land preparation or public facilities have been completed following urban land readjustment or zone expropriation.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 26</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Where one of the following circumstances applies with respect to the construction of a high-rise building, an environmental impact assessment shall be conducted:
I. A high-rise building of 30 storeys or more, or 100 meters or more in height.
II. An office, commercial or general-purpose building of 20 stories or more, or 70 meters or more in height.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 27</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Where one of the following circumstances applies with respect to demolition for reconstruction, renovation of old structures, or maintenance and preservation work, an environmental impact assessment shall be conducted:
I. The site is located in a national park. However, this restriction shall not apply when the surface area under renewal is less than one hectare or there are fewer than 100 residences or there is housing for fewer than 500 persons, and the national park competent authority and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
II. The site is located in a wildlife preserve or an important wildlife habitat environment.
III. The site is located in an important national wetland.
IV. The site is located in a nature preserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan.
V. The site is located within a water quality and quantity protection area.However, this restriction shall not apply when the surface area under renewal is less than one hectare or there are fewer than 100 residences or there is housing for fewer than 500 persons, and the competent authority for water quality and quantity protection areas and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
VI. The site is located at an elevation of over 1,500 meters. However, this restriction shall not apply to indigenous communities when the indigenous competent authority has granted its consent.
VII. The area of land under renewal exceeds 20 hectares.
When an environmental impact assessment is conducted pursuant to the regulations of the foregoing paragraph, if the land has been obtained through urban land readjustment or zone expropriation, the environmental impact assessment should be conducted before approval of the detailed urban plan.
When an environmental impact assessment has not been performed by the time of completion of urban land readjustment or zone expropriation, the residential community construction or expansion shall be handled pursuant to the regulations of Paragraph 1. However, the case shall be exempt from an environmental impact assessment pursuant to this article when land preparation or public facilities have been completed following urban land readjustment or zone expropriation.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 28</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Where one of the following circumstances applies with respect to constructions related to environmental protection, an environmental impact assessment shall be conducted:
I. The construction, expansion or treatment capacity expansion of a nightsoil treatment plant, and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The site is located in a national park. However, this restriction shall not apply when the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the national park competent authority and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
B. The site is located in a wildlife preserve or an important wildlife habitat environment. However, this restriction shall not apply when the site is located in an important wildlife habitat environment, the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the competent authority for important wildlife habitat environments and the industry competent authority have granted their consent.
C. The site is located in an important national wetland.
D. The site is located in a nature preserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan.
E. The site is located at an elevation of over 1,500 meters.
F. The site is located in the water catchment area of a dam or reservoir.However, this restriction shall not apply when the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the reservoir competent authority and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
G. The site is located in a mountain slope area or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than one hectare.
H. The site is located in farmland in a special agricultural district where farmland readjustment has been completed, the agricultural competent authority has agreed to the use change, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than one hectare.
I. The monthly maximum treatment processing capacity of the facility is 2500 tons or more.
II. The construction or expansion of a sewage treatment plant for a sewage system under the conditions set out in items (b) to (d), item (g) or (h) of the foregoing subparagraph, or of a sewage treatment plant with an annual service population of 250,000 persons or more.
III. The construction, expansion or processing capacity expansion of a composting plant, and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The site is subject to the provisions of items (a) to (f) of subparagraph 1.
B. The site is located in a mountain slope area or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed that is two hectares or more; for a site also located in a water quality and quantity protection area, the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed that exceeds one hectare.
C. The site is located in farmland in a special agricultural district where farmland readjustment has been completed, the agricultural competent authority has agreed to the use change, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than two hectares.
D. The application involves an area or aggregate area of land to be developed that is greater than 5 hectares.
E. The site is located in an industrial zone and the maximum monthly waste treatment volume exceeds 2,500 tonnes.
F. The site is located on urban land (not including industrial zones) and the monthly maximum waste treatment volume exceeds 1,200 tonnes.
G. The site is located on non-urban land (not including industrial zones) and the monthly maximum waste treatment volume exceeds 5,000 tonnes.
IV. The waste transshipment facility construction or expansion or expansion of transhipment capacity, and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The site is subject to the provisions of Items (a) through (h) of Subparagraph 1.
B. The monthly maximum waste transshipment capacity is 2500 tons or more.
V. A general waste or general industrial waste landfill or incinerator construction or expansion project, or capacity expansion project. However, this restriction shall not apply when an expansion project is not located in an area specified in Items (a) to (f) of Subparagraph 1, and the expansion area is less than 500 square meters, and the industry competent authority has granted its consent.
VI. A general waste or general industrial waste disposal site not employing incineration, burial, composting, or reuse (also excluding disposal sites using physical methods to process mixed hardware waste) construction or expansion project, or capacity expansion project. However, this restriction shall not apply when an expansion project is not located in an area specified in Items (a) to (f) of Subparagraph 1, and the expansion area is less than 500 square meters, and the industry competent authority has granted its consent.
VII. Construction or expansion of a general waste trash classification facility (excluding facilities located within existing landfills or incinerators), and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The site is subject to the provisions of items (a) to (f) of subparagraph 1.
B. The application involves an area or aggregate area of land to be developed that is greater than 1 hectare.
VIII. A general waste or general industrial waste reuse organization (excluding organic sludge or mixed sludge reuse organizations) construction or expansion project, or reuse capacity expansion project, and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The site is subject to the provisions of items (a) to (h) of going Subparagraph 1 of Paragraph 1.
B. The site is located within a water quality and quantity protection area. However, this restriction shall not apply when the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the water quality and quantity protection area competent authority and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
C. The site is located on urban land, and the application involves an area or aggregate area of land to be developed greater than 5 hectares.
D. The site is located on non-urban land, and the application involves an area or aggregate area of land to be developed greater than 10 hectares.
IX. Apart from reuse, the construction or expansion of facilities for the intermediate treatment or final disposal of hazardous industrial waste by incineration, burial, or other means (excluding mobile facilities for such treatment or disposal, sterilization facilities at hospitals, or facilities using physical methods to process mixed hardware waste), or capacity expansion project. However, this restriction shall not apply when an expansion project is not located in an area specified in Items (a) through (f) of Subparagraph 1, and the expansion area is less than 500 square meters, and the industry competent authority has granted its consent.
X. Construction or expansion of disposal sites or facilities using physical methods to process mixed hardware waste, or capacity expansion projects, subject to one of the provisions among items (a) through (h) in Subparagraph 1.
XI. Organic sludge, mixed sludge, or hazardous industrial waste reuse organization construction or expansion project, or reuse capacity expansion project. However, this restriction shall not apply when the case complies with the following requirements, data concerning total air and water pollution emissions, waste production, and pollution control measures are submitted to the competent authority and industry competent authority, which have granted their consent:
A. Sites not located in areas subject to the provisions of Items (a) through (f) of Subparagraph 1.
B. The site is not located within a water quality and quantity protection area.
C. The site is located in a mountain slope area, national scenic area, or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed less than one hectare.
D. The site is located in farmland in a special agricultural district where farmland readjustment has been completed, the agricultural competent authority has agreed to the use change, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed less than one hectare.
E. The site is located on urban land (excluding industrial zones) and the monthly maximum waste reuse volume is less than 1,250 tonnes.
F. The site is located in an industrial zone or on non-urban land and the monthly maximum waste reuse volume is less than 2,500 tonnes.
XII. Construction or expansion of earth and gravel storage and disposal sites such as waste soil sites and spoil disposal sites, mixed construction resource classification and disposal sites, and furnishing and repair waste classification and disposal sites, or their capacity expansion projects, and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The site is subject to the provisions of Items (a) through (e) of Subparagraph 1.
B. The site is located in a mountain slope area, national scenic area, or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed that is five hectares or more, or involves the piling of earth in excess of 100,000 cubic meters; for sites located in a water quality and quantity protection area, the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed that is 2.5 hectares or more, or involves the piling of earth in excess of 50,000 cubic meters.
C. The site is located in farmland in a special agricultural district where farmland readjustment has been completed, the agricultural competent authority has agreed to the use change, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than five hectares or more, or involves the piling of earth in excess of 100,000 cubic meters.
D. The application involves an area or aggregate area of land to be developed that is greater than 10 hectares.
Where sites falling under subparagraphs 3 to 6 above are established for the purposes of emergency processing activities, exemption from an environmental impact assessment may be granted with the approval of the competent authority and the industry competent authority.
In Paragraph 1, Subparagraph 8 or 11, a reuse organization employing composting shall be handled in accordance with the regulations Paragraph 1, Subparagraph 3.
In Paragraph 1, Subparagraph 6 or 8, when the case does not require application for an establishment, change, or operation permit for a stationary air pollution source, and the user may either obtain a simple discharge permit under the Water Pollution Control Act or the dedicated wastewater sewage system of an industrial area has agreed to connect sewer pipes, the case shall be handled in accordance with the regulations of Paragraph 1, Subparagraph 10. However, when a facility in Subparagraph 8 simultaneously employs composting as a reuse method, the case shall be handled in accordance with the regulations in the foregoing paragraph.
In Paragraph 1, Subparagraph 8 or 11, an experimental project shall be exempt from environmental impact assessment if the competent authority and industry competent authority have reviewed the case and granted their consent.
When the case in Paragraph 1 consists of a replacement or renovation project, the treatment volume and pollution output do not increase, and unit energy consumption is lower, exemption from an environmental impact assessment may be granted with the approval of the industry competent authority.
If, after the development activities in Paragraph 1 cause treatment volume, transshipped volume, storage volume, or reuse volume to increase, the case is subject to regulations requiring an environmental impact assessment, the treatment volume, transshipped volume, storage volume, or reuse volume may not exceed the original permissible levels unless the case passes environmental impact assessment review.
Whether an environmental impact assessment is to be carried out for applicants for a public or private waste disposal or clean-up organization permit shall determine in the following manner:
I. Those required to obtain establishment approval documents before establishing a site or plant, or those required to make changes to establishment approval documents, it will be determined at the time of application for establishment approval documents.
II. Where existing plants or waste disposal facilities apply for disposal or clean-up permits, or are required to conduct trial operations because they have applied to make changes to the content of the original permit or reapply for a permit, it will be determined at the time of application for trial operation.
III. Where the content of the application for a disposal or clean-up permit exceeds the content of the application for establishment approval documents, or where the content of the application for a disposal or clean-up permit exceeds the content of the application for trial operation, or where, after a disposal or clean-up permit has been obtained, an application is filed to make changes to the original permit content, or a permit reapplication is filed, but does not pertain to the required changes to the establishment approval documens or the required trial operations, it will be determined at the time of application for a disposal or clean-up permit.
Paragraph 1 refers to existing facilities once approved by the industry competent authority in accordance with the Waste Disposal Act. With confirmations of the industry competent authority, those possess the same or different kinds of permits applied by the same or different development units based the Waste Disposal Act shall be exempt from environmental impact assessment when complying with regulations in following subparagraphs:
I. The original permit was not cancelled nor abolished, and the application date is within the validity of original permit (3 years).
II. Those ever disposed wastes based on the original permit content.
III. The application content is within field area of original permit.
IV. The application content shall comply with facilities and disposal methods of original permit, and remain within the waste categories and quantities stated in original permit. Original permit refers to the permit of existing facilities for recent disposal. For original permits like the one to reuse industrial wastes, its waste quantity is based on the maximum total reuse quantity of the permit integrated with the reuse quantity of individual or general cases approved by the industry competent authority..
V. Apart from the air pollution control facilities and facilities for collecting and disposing greenhouse gas, the application content shall not involve other constructions.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 29</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Where one of the following circumstances applies with respect to the development of nuclear energy or other energy sources, an environmental impact assessment shall be conducted:
I. The construction, or expansion with additional generating units, of a nuclear power plant.
II. The construction, or expansion with additional generating units of a hydroelectric power plant (not including run-of-river hydroelectric power plant systems), and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The site is located in a national park.
B. The site is located in a wildlife preserve or an important wildlife habitat environment.
C. The site is located in an important national wetland.
D. The site is located in a nature preserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan.
E. The site is located at an elevation of over 1,500 meters.
F. The site is located in the water catchment area of a dam or reservoir.
G. The site is located within a tap-water water quality and volume protection area.
H. Installed or aggregate installed capacity is 200 MW or greater.
III. The construction, or expansion with additional generating units, of a coal-fired power plant. However, this restriction shall not apply when black start units are added, or when the generating units are not located on the main island of Taiwan and not located in the areas specified in items (a) through (e) of the foregoing subparagraph, and gas-fired installed capacity or aggregate gas-fired installed capacity is less than 100 MW, or installed capacity from oil-fired, coal-fired, or other fuel generating units or aggregate installed capacity from oil-fired, coal-fired, or other fuel generating units is less than 500 MW.
IV. The construction or expansion of a power generator for a coal-fired or a gas-fired cogeneration facility, and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The site is located in a national park. However, this restriction shall not apply when the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the national park competent authority and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
B. The site is located in a wildlife preserve or an important wildlife habitat environment. However, this restriction shall not apply when the site is located in an important wildlife habitat environment, the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the competent authority for important wildlife habitat environments and the industry competent authority have granted their consent.
C. The site is located in an important national wetland.
D. The site is located in a nature preserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan.
E. The site is located at an elevation of over 1,500 meters.
F. The site is located on urban land, gas-fired installed capacity or aggregate gas-fired installed capacity is 100 MW or greater, or installed capacity from oil-fired, coal-fired, or other fuel generating units or aggregate installed capacity from oil-fired, coal-fired, or other fuel generating units is 50 MW or greater.
G. The site is located on urban land, gas-fired installed capacity or aggregate gas-fired installed capacity is 200 MW or greater, or installed capacity from oil-fired, coal-fired, or other fuel generating units or aggregate installed capacity from oil-fired, coal-fired, or other fuel generating units is 100 MW or greater.
V. Installation of an offshore wind power generating system.
VI. The installation of wind power generation units and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The site is subject to the provisions of items (a) through (e) of Paragraph 2.
B. The site is located in a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, the application calls for installation of five or more generating units, or the sum of the number of generating units in the same protection area called for by the application and the number of generating units already approved by the industry competent authority is 20 or more.
C. The site is located in a shelter forest area.
D. The straight-line distance between the center of any wind generating unit and the edge of the nearest building (this refers to a third-party building that had received a use license or address number at the time the wind power generation development plan was submitted to the product competent authority for permit application) is less than 250 meters.
VII. Installation of a photovoltaic power generation system in an important national wetland.
VIII. Installation of a tidal, tidal current, ocean current, wave, or thermal differential generating unit. However, this restriction shall not apply when the industry competent authority has approved an experimental project.
IX. Installation of a geothermal generating unit. However, this restriction shall not apply when the industry competent authority has approved an experimental project.
In the foregoing paragraph, Subparagraph 4, items (f) and (g), the installed capacity of a multiple cycle generating unit with no added auxiliary fuel is increased 1.5 times; when an advanced clear fossil energy system has been retrofitted, the installed capacity may be doubled after the industry competent authority has given its approval.
Power generation equipment for self-use using renewable energy in Paragraph 1 is exempt from environmental impact assessment when installed capacity is less than 500 KW.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 30</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Where one of the following circumstances applies with respect to the construction of a storage or treatment facility for radioactive waste, an environmental impact assessment shall be conducted:
I. The construction or expansion of a storage or treatment facility for radioactive waste, and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The site is located in a national park.
B. The site is located in a wildlife preserve or an important wildlife habitat environment.
C. The site is located in an important national wetland.
D. The site is located in a nature preserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan.
E. The site is located at an elevation of over 1,500 meters.
F. The site is located in a mountain slope area, national scenic area, or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than one hectare.
G. The site is located in farmland in a special agricultural district where farmland readjustment has been completed, the agricultural competent authority has agreed to the use change, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than one hectare.
H. The facility provides storage for 1,000 cubic meters or more, or treatment for liquid wastes in excess of 100 kiloliters per day or of 2 thousand kiloliters per month, or treatment by compression equipment in excess of 20 tonnes per day.
II. The construction or expansion of an incinerator for radioactive waste.
III. A facility for the final disposal of radioactive waste.
IV. A facility for the interim storage of spent nuclear fuels.
The regulations of the foregoing paragraphs shall not apply to research radioactive waste disposal or storage facilities or plans that have been approved by the industry competent authority and nuclear competent authority.
If, after the development activities in Paragraph 1 increase the capacity or handling volume of storage facilities, the case is subject to regulations requiring an environmental impact assessment, the capacity or handling volume may not exceed the original permissible levels unless the case passes environmental impact assessment review.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 31</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Where one of the following circumstances applies with respect to other development activity, an environmental impact assessment shall be conducted:
I. A construction or expansion project involving a mixed industrial/commercial district such as a general industry zone, logistics professional zone, industrial/commercial service and exhibition zone, repair service zone, or shopping center zone, or a shopping special use area, or large shopping center, and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The site is located in a national park. However, this restriction shall not apply when the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the national park competent authority and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
B. The site is located in a wildlife preserve or an important wildlife habitat environment. However, this restriction shall not apply when the site is located in an important wildlife habitat environment, the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the competent authority for important wildlife habitat environments and the industry competent authority have granted their consent.
C. The site is located in an important national wetland.
D. The site is located in a nature preserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan.
E. The site is located at an elevation of over 1,500 meters.
F. The site is located in a mountain slope area, national scenic area, or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than one hectare.
G. The site is located in farmland in a special agricultural district where farmland readjustment has been completed, the agricultural competent authority has agreed to the use change, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than one hectare.
H. The site is located on urban land, and the application involves an area or aggregate area of land to be developed greater than 5 hectares.
I. The site is located on non-urban land, and the application involves an area or aggregate area of land to be developed greater than 10 hectares.
II. The construction of exhibition, fair, or trade show venues subject to items (a) through (g) of the foregoing subparagraph, or the construction of buildings with floor space in excess of 30,000 square meters (calculated on the basis of building floor space in the applied-for building license, miscellaneous licenses, and use license).
III. The construction or expansion of a cemetery, and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The site is subject to the provisions of Items (a) through (d) of Subparagraph 1.
B. The site is located in a mountain slope area, national scenic area, or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, is also located in a water quality and quantity protection area, and the applied-for area or aggregate developed area is 2.5 hectares or more.
C. The application involves an area or aggregate area of land to be developed that is greater than 5 hectares.
IV. Construction or expansion of a crematorium, mortuary or facility for the storage of ashes or skeletal remains subject to items (a) through (g) of Subparagraph 1, or the application covers an area or aggregate area that is two hectares or more, or the aggregate developed area is two hectares or more.
V. Construction or expansion of a slaughterhouses subject to Items (a) through (e) of Subparagraph 1, or the applications involves an area or the aggregate area to be developed that exceeds one hectare.
VI. Establishment of an animal shelter subject to Items (a) through (i) of Subparagraph 1.
VII. Construction of an underground pedestrian mall with an applied-for or aggregate development length of one kilometer or more or with applied-for building floor space in excess of 150,000 square meters (calculated on the basis of building floor space in the building license, miscellaneous licenses, and use license application).
VIII. The installation of power transmission lines, where one of the following conditions applies to a 345-kilovolt or 161-kilovolt circuit:
A. The overhead line passes through one of the areas specified in Items (a) through (d) of Subparagraph 1.
B. The overhead line passes through an indigenous reserve.
C. The straight-line distance between the projected edge of the overhead line, its circuits, or its pylons and the edge of a public elementary school or middle school (including designated land) is less than 50 meters.
D. The straight-line distance between the projected edge of the overhead line, its circuits, or its pylons and the edge of a hospital is less than 50 meters.
E. An overhead or underground transmission line with a length of 50 kilometers or more.
IX. Construction or expansion of an ultra high voltage transformer.
X. A port application to establish cement storage silos with a storage capacity in excess of 18,000 cubic meters.
XI. The construction of natural gas pipelines or oil pipelines which extend over a path of 50 kilometers or more.
XII. Construction or expansion of a nursing home, nursing institution, long-term care institution, or welfare institution for the elderly subject to the provisions of Items (a) through (i) of Subparagraph 1.
XIII. The construction or expansion of a military base, coast guard or navy patrol base, missile testing range, firing range or radar station, and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The site is subject to the provisions of Items (a) through (e) of Subparagraph 1.
B. The site is located in a water catchment area of a dam or reservoir. However, this restriction shall not apply when the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the reservoir competent authority and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
C. The site is located in a mountain slope area, national scenic area, or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than ten hectares.
XIV. The construction or expansion of a tourist (recreational) hotel or motel (guest house) and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The site is located in a national park. However, this restriction shall not apply when the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed that is less than one hectare, and the national park competent authority and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
B. The site is located in wildlife refuges or important wildlife habitat environment, or the straight-line distance between the edge of the development site and a protection area or important wildlife habitat environment is less than 500 meters (or less than 200 meters in areas outside the main island of Taiwan). However, this restriction shall not apply when the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the wildlife refuges or important wildlife habitat environment competent authority and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
C. The site is located in an important national wetland, or the straight-line distance between the edge of the development site and a wetland is less than 500 meters (or less than 200 meters in areas outside the main island of Taiwan).
D. The site is located in a nature preserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan.
E. The site is located within a water quality and quantity protection area. However, this restriction shall not apply when the expansion application involves an area of less than 500 square meters or the aggregate expansion area is less than 2,500 square meters, and the water quality and quantity protection area competent authority and industry competent authority have granted their consent.
F. The site is located at an elevation of over 1,500 meters.
G. The site is located in a mountain slope area, national scenic area, or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than one hectare.
H. The site is located in farmland in a special agricultural district where farmland readjustment has been completed, the agricultural competent authority has agreed to the use change, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than one hectare.
I. The site is located on urban land, and the application involves an area or aggregate area of land to be developed greater than 5 hectares.
J. The site is located on non-urban land, and the application involves an area or aggregate area of land to be developed greater than 10 hectares.
K. The site is located in an existing golf course.
XV. The installation of off-loading facilities (or a port) for liquefied natural gas.
XVI. The construction or expansion of a man-made island.
XVII. The decommissioning of nuclear reactor facilities. However, the decommissioning of research reactor facilities shall not be subject to this restriction.
XVIII. The development of a crematorium and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The construction of a crematorium.
B. The expansion of a crematorium and one of the following conditions applies:
1. The site is subject to the provisions of items (a) to (e) of subparagraph 1.
2. The aggregate surface area of separate expansion zones exceeds one hectare.
3. A new crematorium.However, this provision shall not apply where a crematorium is constructed as a replacement on the original site and having the original size.
XIX. Construction or expansion of a cable car. However, this restriction shall not apply when the cable car is located within the scope of a zoo or other existing recreation area (excluding forest recreation areas and national parks), and the industry competent authority has granted its consent.
XX. Construction or expansion of a correctional agency, rehabilitative measure institutions, or other detention institutions with the goal of imprisonment and reform, and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The site is subject to the provisions of Items (a) through (e) of Subparagraph 1.
B. The site is located in a mountain slope area, national scenic area or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed that is five hectares or more; for a site also located in a water quality and quantity protection area or reservoir watershed areas, the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed that exceeds one hectare.
C. The site is located in farmland in a special agricultural district where farmland readjustment has been completed, the agricultural competent authority has agreed to the use change, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than five hectares.
D. The application involves an area or aggregate area of land to be developed that is greater than 5 hectares.
XXI. Use or development of deep seawater, and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The site is subject to the provisions of Items (a) through (g) of Subparagraph 1.
B. The maximum daily amount of pumped water exceeds 5,000 tons.
C. The application involves an area or aggregate area of land to be developed that is greater than 10 hectares.
XXII. Construction or expansion of a weather radar station, subject to the provisions of Items (a) through (g) of Subparagraph 1.
XXIII. Establishment of a petroleum or petroleum product storage tank as prescribed by the Petroleum Administration Act; an environmental impact assessment shall be conducted when any one of the following situations applies:
A. The site is located in a national park subarea outside of general control areas, or located in a national park general control area, and the total storage capacity of the storage tanks or aggregate storage capacity is more than 300 kiloliters.
B. The site is located in a wildlife preserve or an important wildlife habitat environment.
C. The site is located in an important national wetland.
D. The site is located in a nature preserve approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan.
E. The site is located in the water catchment area of a dam or reservoir.
F. The site is located in a water quality and quantity protection area, and the total storage capacity of the storage tanks or aggregate storage capacity is more than 300 kiloliters.
G. The site is located in a port zone, and the total storage capacity of the storage tanks or aggregate storage capacity is more than 300 kiloliters.
H. The site is located at an elevation of over 1,500 meters.
I. The site is located in a mountain slope area, national scenic area, or a general protected area approved and announced under a Taiwan coastal area natural environment protection plan, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than one hectare.
J. The site is located in farmland in a special agricultural district where farmland readjustment has been completed, the agricultural competent authority has agreed to the use change, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed greater than one hectare.
K. The site is located on urban land, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed that is five hectares or more, or the total storage capacity of the storage tanks or aggregate storage capacity is more than 15,000 kiloliters.
L. The site is located on urban land, and the application involves an area or aggregate area to be developed that is ten hectares or more, or the total storage capacity of the storage tanks or aggregate storage capacity is more than 30,000 kiloliters.
XXIV. Land rezoned for factory use is used for non-factory development purposes, and one of the following conditions applies:
A. The industry type complies with the regulations of Attached Table 3.
B. The industry type complies with the regulations of Attached Table 4, and the area of the rezoned land is one hectare or more.
XXV. Reclaimed land created from marine areas by construction of dikes and drainage. However, this restriction shall not apply when the land is within the scope of an existing port.
XXVI. Stationary facilities established in marine areas for the observation of meteorological conditions above land and sea or earthquakes, with site development less than 10 meters in depth. Moreover, the footprint of any facility must not exceed a total of 500 square meters within a two kilometer radius of the facility's center.
In Subparagraph 24 of the foregoing paragraph, factory refers to a plant that is already developed and in use; if the industry type changed after January 16, 1997, the industry type should be determined on a relatively strict basis.
Where facilities falling under Subparagraph 26 of Paragraph 1 are experimental projects or temporary facilities with a usage period of less than five years, exemption from an environmental impact assessement may be granted with the approval of the industry competent authority.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 32</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Except where the regulations of Articles 3 through 31 and Article 5, Paragraph 1, Subparagraph 11 of this Act apply, when any one of the following situations applies, an environmental impact assessment shall be conducted when the competent authority believes that there is concern of adverse impact on the environment from development activities:
I. After the competent authority determined pursuant to Article 14 of this Act following review that a site should not be developed, the development unit drafted an alternative plan for the same development activity in the original location.
II. After the competent authoritys environmental impact assessment review committee case task force reached a conclusion that a site should not be developed, the development unit re-planned the same development activity in the original location after withdrawing its original environmental impact statement or assessment document.
When a development activity has any of the situations of the subparagraphs of the foregoing paragraph, the development unit must submit an environmental impact statement to the original industry competent authority, and the original industry competent authority shall forward the statement to the original review competent authority for review. After the environmental impact statement or assessment document has passed review by the competent authority, the developer may not apply to change the environmental impact statement or assessment document or the content of the review conclusions as prescribed in Article 40, Paragraph 1, until after completed the development activity.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 33</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Where, in respect of any development activity outlined in Articles 3 through 31 above, a central government competent authority deems it necessary, the said authority may require that an environmental impact assessment be conducted, and shall set out separately and publicly the items and scope of such an assessment.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 34</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Any development activity undertaken within a development activity (or project) for which the environmental impact assessment review (approval) has been completed shall be exempt from environmental impact assessment when complying with the regulations in the following subparagraphs:
I. The industry type is consistent with the original approval.
II. The management agency (organization) in charge of the development activity (project) has confirmed that the originally-approved total pollution has not been exceeded. However, when the discharge of any one pollutant accounts for more than 20% of the total approved volume of that pollutant, or the annual discharge of any one pollutant type among the items of particulate pollutants, nitrogen oxides, sulfur oxides, or volatile organic compounds exceeds 100 tons, the competent authority and industry competent authority must grant their consent.
In the foregoing paragraph, the management agency (organization) in charge of the development activity (project) must implement total pollution controls, and must report total pollution emission quotas to the local competent authority on an annual basis.
With regard to the development activity in Paragraph 1, if the original environmental impact assessment review (approval) does not determine the industry type or total pollution amount, the development unit may apply for a change as prescribed in Article 16 of this Act. After the industry type and total pollution amount have been included, and review (approval) completed, the various development activities in the project shall be subject to the regulations in Paragraph 1.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 35</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[When one of the following conditions applies, a development activity shall be exempt from environmental impact assessment; the case should be reported to the industry competent authority and competent authority for subsequent reference before the project gets underway:
I. Traffic emergency repairs after having been confirmed by the industry competent authority as dredging during post-disaster restoration and reconstruction or as post-disaster restoration and reconstruction projects. However, those reconstruction projects undertaken as part of post-disaster restoration and reconstruction development activities as specified in Articles 5-7 should comply with the principle of rejoining an existing road, railway, or mass transit system damaged by a natural disaster.
II. A professional engineering association believes that there is concern that an accident may occur if improvements are not taken immediately, and the management (organization) has completed sealing to prohibit use.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 36</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[In case of reapplying permit for the same development activity once approved by the industry competent authority due to the change of developer or other factors, the application of the permit shall be handled in accordance with this regulation. But the case conforms to below regulations as the industry competent authority confirms, the case shall be exempt from environmental impact assessment:
I. The original permit was not cancelled nor abolished, and the application date is within the validity of original permit (3 years).
II. Original development activities are completed and have been operated.
III. The content of reapplied permit is within the scope of original permit content. In case of having a multi-level permit or the original permit content was once modified, the last permit content shall be taken into account.
IV. Apart from the air pollution control facilities and facilities for collecting and disposing greenhouse gas, the application content shall not involve other constructions.
V. In case of having plant development activities, the industry type, production facilities and manufacturing processes of the application shall be the same as the original plant. If preceding development activity is held by waste disposal facilities, it shall be handled based on regulations stated in Paragraph 9 of Article 28.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 37</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[When the site of a development activity is also located within any type of development zone as defined in these Standards and meets any one of the following conditions, an environmental impact assessment shall be conducted on the basis of the overall plans for the applied-for development:
I. In any type of zone, an environmental impact assessment shall be conducted regardless of the scale.
II. In any type of zone, the scale of development complies with regulations for that zone requiring an environmental impact assessment.
III. When the scale in relatively strict zones is combined sequentially with the scale in a relatively lax zone, this complies with regulations for the relatively lax zone requiring an environmental impact assessment. However, the scale of development in overlapping zones may not be added more than once.
IV. When the scale of an development activity is not specified in terms of area or length, the scale must comply with regulations requiring an environmental impact assessment in the strictest zone.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 38</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Except where other regulations in these Standards apply, the definitions of development activities and development zone scopes announced in Articles 3 through 31 and Article 5, Paragraph 1, Subparagraph 11 of this Act shall be interpreted on the basis of the relevant regulations of each competent authority.
As used in these Standards, "important national wetland" refers to the scope of important national wetlands selected and delineated by the wetlands competent authority.
The water catchment area of a dam or reservoir refers to the ones announced by the Ministry of Economic Affairs. The water catchment area of a first-class dam or reservoir refers to water areas for the dam or reservoir stated in Attached Table 4-1; the water catchment area of a second-class dam or reservoir refer to those, which are not the water catchment areas for the first-class dam or reservoir; the weir catchment areas refer to water catchment areas of the dam or reservoir stated in Attached Table 4-2.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 39</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[In Articles 3 through 31, the aggregate development scale requiring that an environmental impact assessment be conducted shall be calculated using the following methods:
I. When, after March 2, 2010, an application is made to the industry competent authority for a construction permit for a development activity, the aggregate development scale shall be the sum of the scale of the applied-for construction work and successively expansions.
II. When, before March 2, 2010, a construction permit is received from the industry competent authority or an application is made to the industry competent authority for a construction permit, the aggregate development scale shall be the sum of the scale of successive expansions, where the aggregate development scale accumulation starting date and standards requiring an environmental impact assessment shall be as shown in Attached Table 5.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 40</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[After the environmental impact assessment review has been completed for a development activity, when any one of the following situations applies during subsequent implementation of the activity or after its completion, causing the original development activity to no longer comply with regulations requiring an environmental impact assessment, the development unit may apply for a change of the environmental impact statement or assessment document, or content of the review conclusions, as prescribed in Article 16 of this Act:
I. The scale of the development activity has been reduced.
II. The determination of environmental sensitivity zone has been changed.
III. Regulations requiring an environmental impact assessment have been revised.
IV. Other relevant laws and regulations have been revised.
When a development activity has any one of the situations in the various subparagraphs of the foregoing paragraph prior to completion of the environmental impact assessment review, causing the original development activity to no longer comply with regulations requiring an environmental impact assessment, the competent authority shall return the environmental impact statement or assessment document to the industry competent authority.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 41</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Apart from Articles 3 through 31, which shall take effect three months after the date of promulgation, these Standards shall take effect on the date of promulgation.
These Standards were revised shall take effect on the date of promulgation.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
