<法規>
<法規性質>法律</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Fundamental Communications Act</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>通訊傳播基本法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=P0010005</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20161109</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated on January 7, 2004
2.Amended on Novenber 9, 2016]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This Act is enacted to accommodate the convergence of technologies, encourage the sound development of communications, safeguard citizens' rights, protect consumers' interests, improve cultural diversity, and close the gap between urban and rural areas.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The terms used herein are defined as follows:
1."Communications" refers to the transmission of sounds, pictures, text or data via wire, radio, satellite or other electronic transmission facilities.
2."Communications enterprise” refers to an enterprise engaging in communications business.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[In order to effectively carry out the regulatory affairs concerning communications, the Government shall establish the National Communications Commission to independently exercise its duties and powers in accordance with the laws.
The planning of national communications resources and the provision of guidance and incentives for industrial development shall be performed, in accordance with the laws, by subordinate agencies under the Executive Yuan.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Government shall establish the communications supervisory and administration fund to meet the various expenditures that are necessary to carry out regulatory affairs concerning communications.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Communications shall safeguard human dignity, respect minorities' rights and interests, and promote the balanced development of cultural diversity.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Government shall encourage innovation in communications technologies and services and shall not impose any restriction on innovation without proper cause. 
The interpretation and application of the relevant statutes concerning communications shall not be prejudicial to the provision of innovative technologies and services.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Government shall avoid any discriminatory administration of different transmission technologies, provided that this requirement shall not apply to the allocation of scarce resources.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The prescription of technical specifications relating to communications and related inspection work shall be undertaken in such a way as to promote interoperability.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Communications enterprises shall publicly disclose necessary information with respect to consumption and shall provide fair and reasonable services to protect the rights and interests of consumers.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 10</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The allocation and administration of scarce communications resources shall conform to the principles of fairness, efficiency, convenience, harmony and the neutrality of technology.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 11</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Government shall take necessary measures to promote interconnection between and among communications network infrastructure.
Network interconnection set forth in the preceding paragraph shall conform to the principles of transparency, reasonableness and non-discrimination.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 12</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Government shall take necessary measures to promote the right of access to communications and the provision of universal services in line with the planning of the National Communications Commission.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 13</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The National Communications Commission shall submit a performance report and recommendations for improvements annually concerning the sound development of communications, the safeguarding of citizens' rights, the protection of consumers' interests, the improvement of cultural diversity, the protection of minority' rights and interests, and the provision of universal services.
In the event that the recommendation for improvements would involve the amendment of existing laws, the National Communications Commission shall prescribe the direction for such amendment and the reasons relating thereto.
The performance report and recommendation set forth in the preceding paragraphs shall be announced in an appropriate manner and shall be submitted to the Legislative Yuan for reference.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 14</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Upon occurrence of a natural disaster or emergency, or in the likelihood that such an event could occur, the Government may require a communications enterprise to take necessary counter measures in the consideration of public interests.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 15</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[In order to upgrade the development of communications, the Government shall proactively promote and participate in international cooperation and may, where necessary, authorize private institutions to carry out the relevant matters in accordance with the laws.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 16</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Government shall amend the relevant statutes concerning communications in accordance with the principles set forth in this Act within two (2) years after the establishment of the National Communications Commission.
Prior to implementation of the amendments of the laws set forth in the preceding paragraph, the National Communications Commission may interpret and apply the laws which are in conflict or in concurrence with the provisions set forth in this Act based upon the principles set forth herein.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 17</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This Act shall come into force on the date of promulgation.]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
