<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Regulations for the Administration of Responsible Persons of Satellite Broadcasting Businesses</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>衛星廣播電視事業負責人監督管理辦法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawContent.aspx?PCODE=P0050056</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20161121</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.5 Articles promulgated in full by on Novermber 21 of 2016 according to Letter Tong-Chuan-Nei-Rong No.10548033810 by National Communications Commission]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulations are hereby enacted pursuant to Paragraph 3, Article 10 of the Satellite Broadcasting Act (hereinafter referred to as the Act).
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Responsible persons of satellite broadcasting businesses refers to directors, supervisors, general managers, chief executive officers, or persons with similar duties.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Those in any one of the following circumstances shall not be deemed as a responsible person; those already in the aforementioned role but falling under one of the following circumstances shall be removed from the position:
1. Those in any one of the situations in Subparagraph 2, Paragraph 1, Article 10 of the Satellite Broadcasting Act;
2. Those who were once deemed as a responsible person, where the execution of his/her duties caused the business license to be revoked;
3. Those who have been sentenced to imprisonment for embezzlement, the custodial sentence of which has not concluded or five years have not lapsed since the date of conclusion of the custodial sentence, the expiration of probation period, or the pardon of such punishment;
4. Those without domestic residence; or
5. Those with other serious problems that are deemed as unsuitable for being a responsible person.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The general manager, chief executive officer, or a person with similar duties of satellite broadcasting businesses shall meet at least one of the following qualifications:
1. Those graduated from a vocational college, college, university, or higher, recognized by the Ministry of Education, or who have equivalent education; or
2. Those with other evidence, sufficient to prove having professional knowledge or operational management capabilities or who have an adequate amount of experience.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulations shall take effect from the date of promulgation.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
