<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Standards for the Regulation Fee of Applications for the Operation of a Digital Broadcasting Business</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>申請經營數位廣播業務規費收費標準</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawContent.aspx?PCODE=P0050022</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20040505</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Article 1-5 promulgated by GIO, Executive Yuan, Hsin Guan Er Zi No 0930622369 on May 5th, 2004; implemented on the day of its promulgation.]]></沿革內容>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These standards are promulgated in accordance with Article 50-1 of the Radio and Television Act.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The regulation fee of these standards refers to the approval fee and license fee for application for the operation of a digital broadcasting business and shall be calculated in New Taiwan Dollars.
The above mentioned approval fee and the license fee are as follows:
I. Approval fee
(I) New application: Whole network: NTD500,000 per application; district network: NTD300,000 per application.
(II) Application for license renewal upon expiry: Whole network: NTD500,000 per application; district network: NTD300,000 per application.
(III) License renewal due to license damage or content changes: NTD3,000 per application.
(IV) License replacement due to a lost license: NTD3,000 per application.
II. License fee
(I) Issue: Whole network: NTD1,000,000 per application; district network: NTD300,000 per application.
(II) License renewal upon expiry: Whole network: NTD1,000,000 per application; district network: NTD300,000 per application
(III) License renewal due to license damage or content change or replacement due to a lost license: exempt from license fee.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[According to the notice from the competent authority, there shall be no additional charges for applications submitted within the deadline.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Once paid, the approval fees, including those that have been mistakenly paid or over paid, shall not be refunded.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These standards shall become effective on the day of their promulgation.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
