<法規>
<法規性質>法律</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>The Organization Act of the Civil Service Development Institute, Directorate-General of Personnel Administration, Executive Yuan</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>行政院人事行政總處公務人力發展中心組織法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawContent.aspx?PCODE=S0000024</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20171227</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件 />
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated on November 14, 2011 and enforced on February 2,2012 
2.Abolished on December 27, 2017]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[To administer the training and development of civil servants in the Executive Yuan’s subordinate agencies, the Directorate- General of Personnel Administration, Executive Yuan shall establish the Civil Service Development Institute (hereinafter referred to as the Institute) under its purview.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Institute shall be charged with:
1.In-service training and education of mid- and high-level civil servants at the Executive Yuan’s subordinate agencies;
2.Holding workshops on key Executive Yuan policies and regulations, and developmental training for civil servants;
3.Research and execution of training and development programs for civil servants and personnel officers at the Executive Yuan’s subordinate agencies;
4.Implementation of virtual learning and lifelong learning for civil servants at the Executive Yuan’s subordinate agencies;
5.Research and promotion of training techniques, materials, and methods for civil servants at the Executive Yuan’s subordinate agencies;
6.Cooperation between and integration of training programs involving domestic and foreign training and academic institutes;
7.Training guidance and consultation for civil servants at the Executive Yuan’s subordinate agencies;
8.Execution of training programs commissioned by other agencies; and
9.Other affairs pertaining to the training of civil servants at the Executive Yuan’s subordinate agencies.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Institute shall have one director-general ranked Senior 13th grade and one deputy director-general ranked Senior 12th grade.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The official ranks, grades, and headcounts of personnel at the Institute shall be regulated by a separate Personnel Establishment Table.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This Act shall come into force on the date prescribed by the Executive Yuan.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
