<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Fee-charging Standards on the Access to Government information by the DGBAS, Executive Yuan and/or its Subordinate Agencies</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>行政院主計總處提供政府資訊收費標準</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawAll.aspx?pcode=T0010009</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20060629</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Attachment：The Duplicating or Copying the Government Information Fee Standard Table.PDF]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000004382</下載網址>
  </檔案>
  <檔案>
    <檔案名稱><![CDATA[Attachment：The Duplicating or Copying the Government Information Fee Standard Table.DOC]]></檔案名稱>
    <下載網址>https://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawGetFile.ashx?FileId=0000000224</下載網址>
  </檔案>
</附件>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Full text promulgated on June 29,2006 by the DGBAS, Executive Yuan Order Chu Ping Tsu No.0950003947A.]]></沿革內容>
<前言><![CDATA[]]></前言>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This Standard is enacted according to paragraph 2 of Article 22 of the Freedom of Government Information Law (hereinafter referred to as the “Law”).
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The fee-charging for requesting the Directorate General of Budget, Accounting and Statistics of Executive Yuan (hereinafter referred to as the DGBAS) and/or its subordinate agencies to provide government information,shall be governed by this Standard, unless otherwise prescribed by law and regulation.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The fee for browsing, transcribing, or photographing government information is NT$20 for every two hours. Time spent less than two hours is counted as two hours.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The fee for duplicating or copying government information shall be charged in accordance with the Duplicating or Copying the Government Information Fee Standard Table as set forth in the attachment.
The items undefined in the above Fee Standard Table shall be charged in accordance with the actual costs of duplication or copying.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[If the applicant requests that the duplicated or copied government information be sent by mail, the applicant shall be charged for the actual mailing expenses.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The applicant that requests the government information for academic research or public interest use shall file the request with the relevant documentary proof attached. After the request is approved, the fee shall be halved except for the actual mailing expenses.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The requested government information that falls within the scope of business or educational promotions as defined in paragraph 1, Article 12 of the Charges and Fees Law may be provided free of charge.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The collection of fees as listed in this Standard shall comply with the budgetary procedures.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This Standard shall be effective immediately upon date of promulgation.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
