<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Regulations Governing the Detention of the Aliens</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>外國人收容管理規則</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawContent.aspx?PCODE=D0080130</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20120727</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1. Enacted and promulgated by Order (89) Tai-Nei-Yi-Tzu No.8981106 of the Ministry of the Interior on Feb.1, 2000
2. The amended Act with all 15 articles was promulgated by the Ministry of the interior Order Tai-Nei-Yi-Tzu No.0971027572 on August 1,2008;the date of its effect was to be set by the Ministry of the interior. 
   The amended Act was set to go into effect since August 1,2008 by the Ministry of the interior Order Tai-Nei-Yi-Tzu No.0971035715 on August 1,2008.
3. The amended Articles 4 was promulgated by the Ministry of the interior Order Tai-Nei-Yi-Tzu No.1000934066 on November 30,2011; and went into effect on the date of promulgation.
4. The amended Articles 3 was promulgated by the Ministry of the interior Order Tai-Nei-Yi-Tzu No.1010956104 on july 27,2012;the date of its effect was to be set by the Ministry of the interior.
   The amended Article 3 was set to go into effect since July 30,2012 by the Ministry of the interior Order Tai-Nei-Yi-Tzu No.1010956111 on August 22,2012.]]></沿革內容>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Regulation is enacted pursuant to Article 39 of the Immigration Act (hereinafter referred to as "the Act").
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Alien detention shall be implemented in alien detention centers, temporary　detention centers set up by the National Immigration Agency of the Ministry of the Interior (hereinafter referred to as the "National Immigration Agency"), or other proper locations designated by the National Immigration Agency under necessary circumstances (hereinafter referred to as "the detention center").
Male detainees shall be separated from female detainees in detention centers.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Upon detaining an alien, the National Immigration Agency shall establish a “Bill of Mandatory Detention” containing the following details:
1.Detainee’s name, sex, date of birth, nationality, type of identification and identification number and place of residence in the country. In the event that the name of the detainee is unclear and if necessary otherwise, detainee’s appearance characteristics must also be described.
2.The facts.
3.Reasons for such detention.
4.Place for such detention
5.Duration of the detention
6.Procedure for the appeal of the detention, duration, relevant authorities and other related rules.
Unless it is impossible to do so, the Bill issued in accordance with preceding paragraphs shall be delivered to the detainee and notification of such shall be made to his/her spouse, or the lineal relative as appointed by the detainee, legal representative and sibling.
Should the National Immigration Agency terminate the detention in accordance with Article 4 of this Act, it shall establish a “Bill of Terminating Mandatory Detention” containing the following details:
1.Detainee’s name, sex, date of birth, nationality, type of identification and identification number and place of residence in the country. In the event that the name of the detainee is unclear and if necessary otherwise, detainee’s appearance characteristics must also be described.
2.The facts.
3.Reasons for such detention.
4.Restriction on place of residence or any other conditions and the consequence of breaching such conditions.
5.Procedure for the appeal of the detention, duration, relevant authorities and other related rules.
There should be restrictions on the place of residence or any other conditions upon Termination of Mandatory Detention.
Should the detainee is in breach of the above mentioned restriction or conditions, the Termination of Mandatory Detention shall be null and void.
Restriction on place of residence in above-mentioned sub-paragraph 4 shall be considered in the following order:
1.Detainee.
2.Detainee’s relative who has household registration in Taiwan.
3.Responsible person for Charity Organizations of NGOs.
4.Detainee’s nationality’s embassy in Taiwan or its authorized person.
5.Former employer of detainee or responsible person for the employment agency.
6.Person consented by the National Immigration Agency.
Conditions in above-mentioned sub-paragraph 4 shall be considered in the following order:
1.Must be present as ordered at the prescribed public area as deemed fit upon the inspections by the National Immigration Agency officials in accordance with the law, the intervals of such appearance must not be less than seven days and not more than fifteen days as deemed fit.
2.Report to National Immigration Agency as ordered, the intervals of which must not be less than seven days and not more than fifteen days as deemed fit.
3.Provide contact details which detainee can be contacted at any time and must respond to the National Immigration Agency immediately when contacted.
4.Any other conditions as deemed fit by the National Immigration Agency.
National Immigration Agency must obtain the consent of the owner of the residence upon restricting the place of residence in accordance with sub- paragraph two to six of Article 6 of the Act; same is applicable to imposing conditions which affects persons other than the detainee in accordance with the above-mentioned sub- paragraph three and four.
Person named in the above paragraphs may apply to the National Immigration Agency for the amendment to the restricted place of residence and contents of the conditions imposed.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[For an alien, who may be subject to temporary detention pursuant to Paragraph 1 of Article 38 of the Act, the detention may be suspended temporarily if he/she:
1.Is mentally impaired or physically sick, and the detention will affect the treatment or is likely to endanger his/her life.
2.Has been pregnant for five (5) months or longer, or has given birth or had a miscarriage for less than two (2) months.
3.Has contracted infectious diseases prescribed in Article 3 of the Communicable Disease Control Act and possibly causes infection cluster.
4.Could not take care of his/her daily life due to senility or physical or mental handicap.
A detainee, who is under the situation prescribed in one of the subparagraphs of the preceding paragraph, may prepare a declaration together with his/her relative having a household registration in Taiwan area, a charity organization, or persons consented by the National Immigration Agency, to temporarily suspend his/her detention.
When the cause for suspension in temporarily detention prescribed in the preceding　paragraph lapses, the alien may be put in temporary custody again unless the procedure for exiting the country has been completed.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Upon entering a detention center, each detainee shall have a checkup and have his/her fingerprint and photograph taken. If the detainee is a woman, her checkup shall be conducted by female examiners.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Except daily necessities, articles carried by a detainee shall be examined and put in the custody of a detention center. A receipt shall be produced upon receiving such articles. The articles shall be returned when the detainee leaves the detention center. Where the articles are not suitable for custody, the detainee shall be ordered to properly dispose such articles. The former requirements shall also apply to articles mailed to the detainees.
To ensure the safety and management of the detention center, the center may inspect the detainee, articles he/she carried with, or the detention area.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Upon entering a detention center, detainees shall be informed of the matters to comply with, specified as follows:
1.No suicide, self-mutilation, or behavior injuring others life or body allowed.
2.No clamor, quarrel, fight, attack to management, or escape from the facility allowed.
3.No drinking or gambling allowed.
4.Shall not hide prohibited items, contraband, or other dangerous goods.
5.Shall not defy the management order or act against the order of the detention.
6.Shall not smear, pollute, destruct, or damage the public facility.
7.Other compliance rules specified by the detention center.
The compliance rules referred to in the previous paragraph shall be posted or hung at a clear spot in the detention center in both Chinese and English.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Where a detainee violates the rules as referred to in Paragraph 1 of the previous Article, the detention center shall first stop such behaviors and may take the following measures:
1.Precept.
2.Labor service.
3.Phone call restrictions.
4.Visitation restrictions.
5.Solitary confinement.
Where measures specified in Subparagraphs 2 to 5 are taken, the detention center shall issue a warning. The measures taken shall comply with the principle of proportionality.
After measures stated in Paragraph 1 are taken, the National Immigration Agency may conduct necessary exanimation.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[If a female detainee requests to carry her child under three (3) years old, the request may be approved.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 10</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[In case a detainee contracts a disease, a doctor shall be employed, or the detainee shall be sent to hospital for treatment. If the detainee contracts infectious disease prescribed in Article 3 of the Communicable Disease Control Act, a local health authority shall be notified to discuss whether to put such detainee in quarantine or have him/her treated.
If the detainee prescribed in the previous paragraph needs to be hospitalized for treatment, personnel shall be sent by the detention center to the hospital to keep guard.
The medical expense incurred in the Paragraph 1 shall be paid by the detainee. If the detainee could not pay the expense, it shall be paid by the National Immigration Agency.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 11</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Detention centers shall hold various activities. Unless kept under solitary confinement, detainees shall have time to do outdoor activities in appropriate places; provided that such activities may be cancelled in case of bad weather, safety concern, or insufficient space in the detention center.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 12</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The detainees may have visitations with relatives.
The relatives referred to in the previous paragraph shall take the identification, contact information, and other necessary information to the detention center to apply for visitation. Once approved, the relatives shall comply with the following rules:
1.Visitation shall be conducted at the time and place designated by the detention center.
2.No prohibited items, contraband, or dangerous goods allowed.
3.Properties to be given to a detainee shall be transferred after the inspection, registration, and approval.
4.Orders from the staff or management of the detention center shall be obeyed.
5.The visitation is restricted to thirty (30) minutes; provided that the official in charge of the detention center may approve an extension under special circumstance.
6.No acts against the order of the visitation allowed.
7.Other compliance rules stipulated by the detention center.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 13</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The detention center may refuse visitations or cancel approved visitations with the following circumstances:
1.The detainee has two (2) visitations on a same day.
2.The detainee has been restricted from visitation or put under solitary confinement.
3.The relatives of the detainee who applied for visitation violate the subparagraphs of the previous article, and refuse to obey the staff or management of the detention center.
4.The relatives of the detainee who applied for visitation seem to be drunk, infected with serious contagious disease, or mentally abnormal.
5.Due to the managerial need, the detention center deems visitations inappropriate.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 14</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[If a detainee is about to die of illness or deceased, his/her relatives, related persons, the foreign missions of his/her country in the Republic of China, or authorized institutions shall be notified, unless such notification is impossible.
After the detainee deceased, the National Immigration Agency shall notify his/her relatives, related persons, the foreign missions of his/her country in the Republic of China, or authorized institutions to deal with the funeral affairs, pick-up the remaining items of the deceased, and pay for expenses resulting from funeral affairs; provided that the National Immigration Agency may directly handle the funeral affairs under the following circumstances:
1.The person being notified does not take relevant measures within one (1) month after the service of written notification.
2.Is unable to notify or unable to service the written notification, and the detainee has deceased for more than one (1) month.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 15</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The effective date of the Regulation shall be determined by the Ministry of  the Interior
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
