<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Organization Regulations of the Navy Command Headquarters of the Ministry of National Defense</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>國防部海軍司令部組織規程</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawContent.aspx?PCODE=F0000042</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20121230</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.The whole 17 articles enacted and promulgated by Ministry of National Defense with Gang─sher order 1151 on April 13, 1981
2.Article 3,8,12,13,14 and 15 amended and promulgated by Ministry of National Defense with Dwao─Gue order 0033 on Jan 11, 1995.
3.The whole 11 articles amended and promulgated by Ministry of National Defense with Dwao─Gue order 890017681 on Dec 30, 2000.
4.Article 3,4,7 and 11 amended and promulgated by Ministry of National Defense with Zhi─Kai order 0930000517 on May 18, 2004.
5.The whole 7 articles amended and promulgated by Ministry of National Defense with Zhi─Chuang order 0950000136 on Feb 15, 2006. The regulations will be put into practice from the promulgation date.
6.Amended and promulgated by the Ministry of National Defense o Dec.30,2012,on the orders of Girzhi-Lossix 1010001127.The Regulations,totally 8 articles,shall be put into force from the date of Jan,1,2013.]]></沿革內容>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Navy Command Headquarters (hereinafter “ the HQs” ) is a branch of the Ministry of National Defense , that responds in naval affairs.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The HQs is in charge of following affairs:
(1) Planning, supervising, and implementing of political warfare.
(2) Planning, supervising, and implementing of inspection, medical and legal affairs.
(3) Planning, supervising, and implementing of military personnel management, military personnel service, general administration,military history affairs, and education.
(4) Planning, supervising, and implementing of collection and distribution of military intelligence.
(5) Planning, supervising, and implementing of operation readiness, training, development and application of standards, and assistance in calamity prevention and cure.
(6) Planning, supervising, and implementing of reserve and mobilization affairs.
(7) Coordinating, controlling, and supervising of the Logistics affairs ; planning, supervising, and implementing of military material management and professional services ’ logistics preparation.
(8) Planning and supervising of armed forces buildup and weapon systems policies.
(9) Planning, supervising, and implementing of electronic information, communications, and comptroller affairs.
(10) Planning, supervising, and implementing of other affairs not mentioned above.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The HQs may establish divisions or offices to handle affairs stated above, and distribute into sections or centers to perform affairs as needed.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The HQs may establish several commanding, training, professional, execution, support, and research organizations and forces. There are tables of organization to formulate all the positions.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[In the HQs, there are a chief with the rank of admiral ; two vice chiefs and a chief of staff with the rank of vice admiral.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The organization of the HQs also formulates all the positions and prescribed numbers of personnel mentioned in the table of organization.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The HQs, when deeming it necessary, may employ civilian staff.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The regulations will be put into practice from January 1st, 2013.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
