<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Regulations Governing the Entrustment to the Bank of Taiwan of Matters Associated with the Issuance of the New Taiwan Dollar by the Central Bank of China</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>中央銀行委託臺灣銀行經理新臺幣發行附隨業務辦法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawContent.aspx?PCODE=G0440002</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20000415</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1. Promulgated on April 15, 2000]]></沿革內容>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Regulations are prescribed pursuant to Article 3 of the Regulations Governing the Issuance of the New Taiwan Dollar by
the Central Bank of China.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Central Bank of China (hereinafter referred as “the Bank”) shall entrust the Bank of Taiwan to manage business
operations associated with the issuance of the New Taiwan Dollar in accordance with the Regulations.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The term "business operations associated with the issuance of the New Taiwan Dollar" as stated in the Regulations refers to the 
receipt, payment, delivery, regulation of supply and demand of notes and coins, and arrangements for returned notes that are 
incidental to the issuance of the New Taiwan Dollar.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Bank of Taiwan may establish currency distribution centers on various locations in order to manage business operations 
associated with the issuance of the New Taiwan Dollar.
The establishment and dissolution of currency distribution centers shall be subject to the Bank's approval.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Bank of Taiwan shall follow the instruction and supervision of the Bank in managing business operations associated with 
the issuance of the New Taiwan Dollar.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Bank shall assume responsibility for all expenses incurred by the Bank of Taiwan in managing business operations 
associated with the issuance of the New Taiwan Dollar.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Regulations shall become effective on July 1, 2000.


〔Remarks: These Regulations are made in Chinese which shall prevail in case of any discrepancy between the English 
translation and the Chinese original〕
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
