<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Organizational Rule for the Institute of Forensic Medicine, Ministry of Justice</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>法務部法醫研究所處務規程</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawContent.aspx?PCODE=I0010089</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20111005</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Issued on Oct. 05, 2011]]></沿革內容>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This Organizational Rule is established by the Institute of Forensic Medicine, Ministry of Justice (hereinafter referred to as “the Institute”) in order to specify the job function of each internal unit.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The General Director manages all affairs of the Institute, as well as conducting and supervising all personnel; the Deputy Director assists the General Director in the handling of all the affairs of the Institute.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The Institute is composed of the below mentioned divisions (office):
1. Forensic Pathology Division
2. Forensic Toxicology Division
3. Forensic Genetics and Evidence Tracing Division
4. Secretarial Office
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Responsibilities of the Forensic Pathology Division:
1. To examine, identify and investigate the cadaver.
2. To examine, identify and investigate the pathology.
3. To examine, identify and investigate the cause of death.
4. To explain and investigate the dubious and difficult cases of forensic pathology.
5. To formulate the standard operational procedure of the forensic pathology laboratory.
6. To instruct and supervise the forensic medicine affairs at each District Prosecutors Office.
7. To cultivate, educate and train forensic medical experts.
8. Other affairs relating to the investigation and development of forensic pathology.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Responsibilities of the Forensic Toxicology Division:
1. To examine, identify and investigate toxicological chemistry.
2. To examine, identify and investigate biological chemistry.
3. To examine, identify and investigate pharmaceutical chemistry.
4. To explain and investigate the dubious and difficult cases of forensic toxicology.
5. To formulate the standard operational procedure of the forensic toxicology laboratory.
6. Other affairs relating to the investigation and development of forensic toxicology.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Responsibilities of the Forensic Genetics and Evidence Tracing Division:
1. To examine, identify and investigate serum and other serum-related criminal evidence.
2. To establish the database for regional population frequency of various types of deoxyribonucleic acid (DNA), as well as to analyze and investigate the relevant data.
3. To identify and contrast the type of deoxyribonucleic acid (DNA) for unidentified cadavers.
4. To explain and investigate the dubious and difficult cases of forensic biology, such as serum evidence, etc.
5. To formulate a standard operational procedure of the deoxyribonucleic acid (DNA) laboratory.
6. Other affairs relating to the investigation and development of forensic biology, such as serum evidence, etc.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Responsibilities of the Secretarial Office:
1. To draw up and appraise the implementation plan and working report of the Institute.
2. The custody of official seals, as well as the management of documents and archives.
3. To manage the cashier, finance, repair, maintenance, procurement, and other administrative affairs.
4. To communicate with Congress, to arrange public relationship affairs with the media, and to release the dispatch.
5. To arrange affairs relating to conferences and meetings, as well as  preparing relevant reports and minutes.
6. To supervise all public assets and property.
7. To manage the maintenance worker (including technical workers and drivers).
8. To archive rules and regulations, and to enlighten the forensic medicine education.
9. The repair and maintenance of electronic instruments, the management and maintenance of information-related affairs.
10. Affairs that are not under the authority or responsibility of other divisions.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The personnel superintendent of the Institute is in charge of personnel related affairs in accordance with relevant regulations.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The accountant of the Institute is in charge of affairs related to budgeting, accounting, and statistics in accordance with relevant regulations.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 10</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The operation and authorization of the Institute are based on hierarchical system, and details specified on relevant table.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 11</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These organizational Rules were enforced on Jan. 01, 2012.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
