<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Regulations Governing Traceability of Foods and Relevant Products</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>食品及其相關產品追溯追蹤系統管理辦法</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawContent.aspx?PCODE=L0040111</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20131119</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.MOHW Food No. 1021351000 promulgated, November 19, 2013.]]></沿革內容>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This regulation is prescribed in accordance with the provisions of Paragraph 2 of Article 9 of the Act Governing Food Sanitation (hereinafter referred to as “this Act”).
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[“Foods and relevant products” referred to in this regulation shall mean foods, special dietary foods, food additives, food utensils, food containers or packaging, and food cleansers prescribed under Subparagraphs 1 to 6, Paragraphs 1, Article 3 of this Act.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[“Traceability” referred to in this regulation shall mean food businesses established the information and management to trace the source and track the flow of foods and relevant products at all stage of supply chain.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Food businesses that engage in the manufacture, processing, preparation of the foods and relevant products shall establish traceability system include at least the following items:
1. Product Information:
(1) product name;
(2) main and minor raw materials;
(3) food additives;
(4) packaging containers;
(5) storage conditions;
(6) manufacturer;
(7) responsible domestic manufacturer;
(8) net weight, volume, quantity or measurement;
(9) expiry date or manufacture date.
2. Identification: including any unique mark, lot number, text or picture that is identifiable on raw materials, semi-finished products or finished products.
3. Supplier Information:
(1) supplier (enterprise or company name, address, contact person and telephone number etc.);
(2) product name;
(3) net weight, volume, quantity or measurement;
(4) lot number;
(5) expiry date or manufacture date;
(6) receiving date;
(7) the products shall be labelled the country of origin of raw materials designated by the central competent authority in a public announcement; the country of origin of raw materials must be included.
4. Product flow Information:
(1) distributor and recipient (enterprise or company name, address, contact person, telephone number etc.);
(2) product name;
(3) net weight, volume, quantity or measurement;
(4) lot number;
(5) expiry date or manufacture date;
(6) delivery date.
5. Other information of internal traceability related to the products.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Food businesses that engage in the import of the foods and relevant products shall establish traceability system include at least the following items:
1. Product Information:
(1) chinese and English (foreign) product name;
(2) main and minor raw materials;
(3) food additives;
(4) packaging containers;
(5) storage conditions;
(6) applicant of inspection;
(7) net weight, volume, quantity or measurement;
(8) expiry date or manufacture date;
(9) notice number of foods and relevant products import admitted.
2. Identification: including any unique mark, lot number, text or picture that is identifiable on raw materials, semi-finished products or finished products.
3. Supplier Information:
(1) exporter and manufacturer (slaughterer) (name/code of enterprise or company, address, contact person, telephone number etc.);
(2) product name;
(3) net weight, volume, quantity or measurement;
(4) lot number;
(5) expiry date or manufacture date;
(6) receiving date;
(7) the products shall be labelled the country of origin of raw materials designated by the central competent authority in a public announcement; the country of origin of raw materials must be included.
4. Product Flow Information:
(1) distributor and recipient (enterprise or company name, address, contact person, telephone number etc.);
(2) product name;
(3) net weight, volume, quantity or measurement;
(4) lot number;
(5) expiry date or manufacture date;
(6) delivery date.
5. Other information of internal traceability related to the products.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Food businesses that engage in the sale and export of the foods and relevant products shall establish traceability system include at least the following items:
1. Supplier Information:
(1) supplier (enterprise or company name, address, contact person and telephone number);
(2) product name;
(3) net weight, volume, quantity or measurement;
(4) lot number;
(5) expiry date or manufacture date;
(6) receiving date;
(7) the products shall be labelled the country of origin of raw materials designated by the central competent authority in a public announcement; the country of origin of raw materials must be included.
2. Product Flow Information:
(1) distributor and recipient (enterprise or company name, address, contact person, telephone number etc.);
(2) product name;
(3) net weight, volume, quantity or measurement;
(4) lot number;
(5) expiry date or manufacture date;
(6) delivery date.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Food businesses that engage in the packaging of the foods and relevant products shall comply with the provisions of Article 4. If the original packaging has not been changed after combining the various raw materials, the provisions of the previous articles shall be complied with.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Food businesses shall record detailed information of management items referred to Articles 4 to 6.
Food businesses shall maintain records such as complete proof and shall also keep documents regarding food traceability in written or electronic form for six months after expiry date.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The municipal or county/city competent authority may enter the place of food businesses to perform on-site examination and ensure that food businesses are in compliance with the provisions of food traceability relevant documents, and businesses shall not evade, impede or refuse.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 10</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[This regulation shall be implemented as of its being promulgated.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
