<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Labor Insurance Permanent Disability Benefits Criteria</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>勞工保險失能給付標準</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawContent.aspx?PCODE=N0050023</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20130522</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件>
  <下載網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/Law/law_getfile.ashx?FileId=0000002034</下載網址>
</附件>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1. All nine articles enacted and promulgated per Council for Labor of Labor Affairs Order No. 0970140672 on Dec. 25, 2008 to take effect on Jan. 1, 2009
2. Amendment to Article 9 and the table attached to Article 3 promulgated per Council of Labor Affairs Order No. 0990140449 on Oct. 8, 2010 taking effect on the day of announcement
3. Amendment to the table attached to Article 3 promulgated per Council of Labor Affairs Order No. 1000140356 on Oct. 17, 2011
4. Amendment to Articles 4 and 9 and addition of Article 4-1 promulgated per Council of Labor Affairs Order No. 1020140355 on May 22, 2013 to take effect on Aug. 13, 2013]]></沿革內容>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These standards are established in accordance with the regulation of Paragraph 1 of Article 54-1 of the Labor Insurance Act (hereafter this Act).
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Types of disability:
1. Mental
2. Neurological
3. Eye
4. Ear
5. Nose
6. Mouth
7. Internal Organ
8. Torso
9. Head, face, neck
10. Skin
11. Upper limb
12. Lower limb
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The condition and level of seriousness, evaluation standards, and level of medical institution eligible for issuance of diagnoses are as shown in the table attached.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[As set forth in the Act, workers meeting one of the following conditions shall be regarded incapable of work for the rest of their lives:
1. Having a disability defined in the attached table as “loss of work capacity for the rest of their lives;”
2. The insured applying for disability pensions having been individually evaluated in accordance with Paragraph 2 of Article 54-1 of the Act by specialists as losing over 70% of their work capacity and unable to return to the job market.
The individual work capacity evaluation by specialists prescribed in Subparagraph 2 of the preceding paragraph shall be conducted with the percentage of impairment of the entire body, earning capacity in the future, occupation, and age of the insured taken into consideration.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4-1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The insurer may delegate National Health Insurance contracted hospitals with physicians who have completed corresponding training to conduct the individual work capacity evaluation by specialists prescribed in the preceding article.
Hospitals delegated to perform work capacity evaluation shall assign physicians to conduct the evaluation by applying the methods, instruments, and calculation approaches stipulated by the central competent authority. If necessary, the said evaluation may be conducted by a team composed of specialists, physical therapists, occupational therapists, clinical psychologists, and speech therapists.
The physicians assigned by delegated hospitals as described in the preceding paragraph shall have completed individual work capacity evaluation training courses specified by the central competent authority and conducted by the insurer or a medical organization delegated by the insurer.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Disabilities are divided into 15 levels. The corresponding benefits are calculated on a daily basis according to the average daily pay insured:
1. 1,200 days for Level 1
2. 1,000 days for Level 2
3. 840 days for Level 3
4. 740 days for Level 4
5. 640 days for Level 5
6. 540 days for Level 6
7. 440 days for Level 7
8. 360 days for Level 8
9. 280 days for Level 9
10. 220 days for Level 10
11. 160 days for Level 11
12. 100 days for Level 12
13. 60 days for Level 13
14. 40 days for Level 14
15. 30 days for Level 15
The average insured daily pay is calculated by dividing the average insured monthly pay with 30 days according to the regulation of Item 2 of Paragraph 3 of Article 19 of this Act. 
The disability levels and payment standards prescribed in the two preceding paragraphs shall no apply when workers request for disability pensions.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[When the disability condition of an insured person meets the description of the corresponding item in the attached table, besides applying for the disability pension in accordance with the regulation of Paragraph 2 of Article 53 of the Act, the disability benefits shall be remitted in a lump sum according to the level of disability. 
The disability level described in the preceding paragraph shall be evaluated according to the following regulations:
1. Benefits for disability that meets the description of any one item listed in the attached table shall be remitted according to the regulation of the said item.
2. Benefits for disability that meets the description of two or more than two items listed in the attached table, in addition to the regulation of Item 3 to Item 6, shall be remitted according to the highest disability level of the said items. 
3. Benefits for disability that meets the description of two or more than two items between Level 14 and Level 1 prescribed in the attached table shall be one level above the highest level of disability among the said items. Where the highest level being Level 1, the disability benefits shall be remitted accordingly.   
4. Benefits for disability that meets the description of two or more than two items between Level 8 and Level 1 listed in the attached table shall be two levels above the highest level among the said items. Where the highest level being Level 2 or above, benefits for Level 1 disability shall be remitted.
5. Benefits for disability that meets the description of two or more than two items between Level 5 and Level 1 listed in the attached table shall be three levels above the highest level among the said items. Where the highest level being Level 3 or above, benefits for Level 1 disability shall be remitted.
6. Disability that fails to meet any of the items listed in the attached table shall be evaluated to determine the level by comparing with the disability conditions prescribed in the attached table.
7. In the event that the number of days calculated for disability benefits according to the regulation of Item 3 to Item 6 exceeds the total of days of disability benefits for the individual items, the said total of days of disability benefits shall be remitted.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[According to Paragraph 2 of Article 63-1, where the survivors of the insured opt to receive a lump sum of disability benefits, the payment standards prescribed in the two preceding articles shall apply, with already paid pension amount deducted.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The disability statement prescribed in Item 2 of Paragraph 1 of Article 68 of the Enforcement Rules for the Labor Insurance Act shall be issued by a hospital or clinic designated by the Bureau of National Health Insurance (hereafter BNHI). Due to the need of technology and equipment required for confirmation of disability items, the BNHI-designated hospital issuing the disability statement shall be of the level of local community teaching hospital or higher, rated by the Department of Health of the Executive Yuan as of the level of excellence or better according to the new hospital accreditation system, or a hospital certified as a qualified medical institution according to the new hospital accreditation system and the new teaching hospital accreditation system. Where the disability of an insured person takes place in offshore islands such as Penghu County, Kinmen County, Lianjiang County, or in a place outside the coverage of this Act, the diagnosis from the hospital or clinic where the insured seeks medication may be accepted.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Criteria shall take effect on Jan. 1, 2009
This amendment to the Criteria shall take effect on the day of promulgation.
The amendment made to the Criteria on May 22, 2013 shall take effect on Aug. 13, 2013.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
