<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Civil Aircraft Noise Control Standards</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>民用航空器噪音管制標準</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawContent.aspx?PCODE=O0030004</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20090716</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件>
  <下載網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/Law/law_getfile.ashx?FileId=0000001715</下載網址>
  <下載網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/Law/law_getfile.ashx?FileId=0000001716</下載網址>
  <下載網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/Law/law_getfile.ashx?FileId=0000001717</下載網址>
  <下載網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/Law/law_getfile.ashx?FileId=0000001718</下載網址>
  <下載網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/Law/law_getfile.ashx?FileId=0000001719</下載網址>
</附件>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Full text in 8 articles jointly promulgated in Environmental Protection Administration Order (77) Huan-Shu-Kung-Tzu No.08563 and Ministry of Transportation and Communications Order Chiao-Hang (77) No. 09477 on May 4, 1988.
2.Revisions to Articles 1 and 8 promulgated in Environmental Protection Administration Order (89) Huan-Shu-Kung-Tzu No. 0056631 on October 11, 2000.
3.Revisions to full text in 9 articles jointly promulgated in Environmental Protection Administration Order Huan-Shu-Kung-Tzu No. 0930083349 and Ministry of Transportation and Communications Order Chiao-Hang-Fa-Tzu No. 093B000080 on November 24, 2004.
4.Revision jointly promulgated in Environmental Protection Administration Order Huan-Shu-Kung-Tzu No. 0980061237D and Ministry of Transportation and Communications Order Chiao-Hang-Tzu No 0980085036 on July 16, 2009.]]></沿革內容>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These standards are determined pursuant to Article 11, Paragraph 1 of the Noise Control Act
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Testing of civil aircraft noise levels shall be performed in accordance with effective perceived noise (EPN), A-weighting maximum noise level, or sound exposure level (SEL) regulations in ISO-3891. The units employed are EPN dB, LAmax dB, and SEL dB, respectively.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Noise control standards for subsonic jet aircraft for which a prototype airworthiness certificate application was made by October 5, 1977 are shown in the following table:
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Noise control standards for subsonic jet aircraft for which a prototype airworthiness certificate application was made by October 5, 1977 and where the aircraft design was modified after November 26, 1981 are shown in the following table:
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Noise control standards for subsonic jet aircraft for which a prototype airworthiness certificate application was made after October 6, 1977 are shown in the following table:
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Noise control standards for propeller aircraft are shown in the following tables in accordance with their maximum take-off weight and date of application for a prototype airworthiness certificate. 
I. Noise control standards for propeller aircraft with a maximum take-off weight greater than 5,700 kg for which a prototype airworthiness certificate application was made by December 31, 1984 are shown in the following table:

II. Noise control standards for propeller aircraft with a maximum take-off weight in excess of 5,700 kg for which a prototype airworthiness certificate application was made after January 1, 1985 but before November 16, 1988 are shown in the following table:

III. Noise control standards for propeller aircraft with a maximum take-off weight of less than 8,618 kg for which a prototype airworthiness certificate application was made by November 16, 1988 are shown in the following table:

IV. Noise control standards for propeller aircraft with a maximum take-off weight greater than 8,618 kg for which a prototype airworthiness certificate application was made after November 17, 1988 are shown in the following table:

V. Noise control standards for propeller aircraft with a maximum take-off weight of less than 8,618

Either standards may be applied when the situation simultaneously conforms to the conditions in Subparagraph 1 and Subparagraph 3 of the foregoing paragraph. The same when the situation simultaneously conforms to the conditions in Subparagraph 2 and Subparagraph 3 of the foregoing paragraph.
The noise control standards in Paragraph 1 are not applicable to stunt, special event, agricultural, and fire fighting propeller aircraft.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Noise control standards for helicopter aircraft are shown in the following table in accordance with their maximum take-off weight and date of model airworthiness certificate application:
I. Noise control standards for helicopter aircraft with a maximum take-off weight that is less than or equal to 788 kg and for which a prototype airworthiness certificate application was made after December 31, 1984 or for which an aircraft design modification airworthiness certificate application was made after November 17, 1988 are shown in the following table:

II. Noise control standards for helicopter aircraft with a maximum take-off weight that is less than or equal to 788 kg and for which a prototype airworthiness certificate application or design modification airworthiness certificate application was made after March 21, 2002 are shown in the following table:

III. Noise control standards for helicopter aircraft with a maximum take-off weight that is less than or equal to 3,175 kg and for which a prototype airworthiness certificate application or design modification airworthiness certificate application was made after November 11, 1993 are shown in the following table:

IV. Noise control standards for helicopter aircraft with a maximum take-off weight that is less than or equal to 3,175 kg and for which a prototype airworthiness certificate application or design modification airworthiness certificate application was made after March 21, 2002 are shown in the following table:

The noise control standards in the foregoing paragraph are not applicable to stunt, special event, agricultural, and fire fighting helicopters.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Volume testing procedures and method for measuring civil aircraft noise shall be carried out in accordance with Conventions on International Civil Aviation Annex 6.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Standards shall take effect on the date of promulgation.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
