<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Water Pollution Control Act Enforcement Rules</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>水污染防治法施行細則</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawContent.aspx?PCODE=O0040002</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>20060414</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1.Promulgated on May 29, 1975 
2.Amended on May 18, 1984
3.Amended on December 7, 1992 
4.Amended on May 25, 1994
5.Amended on April 23, 1997
6.Amended on August 12, 1998
7.Amended on September 22, 1999
8.Amended on August 8, 2001
9.Amended on July 30, 2003 
10.Revised Article 9-1, Article 12, and Article 15 promulgated and enacted into law by Environmental Protection Administration Order Huan-Shu-Shui-Tzu No. 0950028185C on April 14, 2006.]]></沿革內容>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Rules are determined pursuant to Article 74 of the Water Pollution Control Act (herein referred to as "this Act")
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The "working environment" referred to in Article 2, Subparagraph 8 of this Act means the scope of enterprise use.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The matters designated in this Act as the responsibility of the central competent authority are as follows. 
ⅠDetermination, supervision and implementation of national water pollution control policies, programs and plans
ⅡDetermination, approval, interpretation and implementation of national water pollution control laws regulations
ⅢCollection and management of water pollution control fees
ⅣNational water pollution control research and development
ⅤTraining and management of national water pollution control personnel
ⅥSupervision of water pollution control work in special municipalities, counties and cities
ⅦNational water pollution control monitoring and testing
ⅧNational water pollution control survey work and compilation of statistics
ⅨNational water pollution control public awareness work
ⅩInternational cooperation and technology exchange related to water pollution control
XICoordination or implementation of national and inter-special municipality, county or city water pollutio control work
XⅡOther national water pollution control matters
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The matters designated in this Act as the responsibility of special municipality, county and city com authorities are as follows.
ⅠPlanning and implementation of special municipality, county and city water pollution control plans
ⅡDetermination, approval, interpretation and implementation of special municipality, county and city pollution control laws and regulations
ⅢPlanning, management and implementation for the use of water pollution control fees
ⅣSpecial municipality, county and city water pollution control research and development
ⅤTraining and management of special municipality, county and city water pollution control personnel
ⅥSpecial municipality, county and city water pollution control monitoring and testing
ⅦSpecial municipality, county and city water pollution control survey work and compilation of statistics
ⅧSpecial municipality, county and city water pollution control public awareness work
ⅨOther special municipality, county and city water pollution control matters
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[As referred to in Article 5 of this Act, "the carrying capacity of a water body may not be exceeded when a water body is utilized to receive or conv effluent" means that any changes in the water quality of a water body that are caused by the total quantity of discharges from all pollution sources that use said water body to receive or convey effluent may not exceed the water classifications and water quality standards determined pursuant to Article 6 of this Act.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA["Building sewage treatment facilities" referred to in Article 7, Article 8, Article 25 and Article 26 of this Act means facilities for treating human excrement and other domestic sewage produced by human activities within a building.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The "water quality monitoring stations" designated in Article 10, Paragraph 1 of this Act shall be installed and perform monitoring pursuant to the following regulations.
ⅠThe central competent authority shall install monitoring stations depending on the water quality circumstances in surface water bodies and groundwater bodies involving two or more special municipalities, counties o cities.
ⅡSpecial municipality, county and city competent authorities shall install monitoring stations depending on water quality circumstances in surface water bodies and groundwater bodies within their jurisdictions.
The sampling frequency of water quality monitoring stations in the foregoing paragraph shall, in principle once per quarter and these stations shall monitor the following items.
ⅠWater temperature
ⅡHydrogen ion concentration index
ⅢDissolved oxygen
ⅣHeavy metals
ⅤOther items designated by the central competent authority based on water body characteristics
Competent authorities at all levels shall issue official announcements for monitoring results and statistical data on a quarterly basis and special municipality, county and city competent authorities shall report data to th competent authority to be filed for future reference.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 8</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The following items shall be checked when an engineer performs signature work pursuant to Article Paragraph 4 of this Act.
ⅠThe reliability and reasonableness of wastewater and sewage water quality and water volume surveyin estimates
ⅡWhether the wastewater and sewage treatment design requires a small-scale experiment and whether i achieved necessary reliable design parameters
ⅢWhether the functions and calculations of the design of wastewater, sewage or sludge treatment system discharge point facilities comply with the regulations of this Act
ⅣThe specifications of wastewater, sewage or sludge treatment facilities shall be checked when the construction of these facilities is completed to determine whether they are consistent the original design diagrams. Whet any inconsistencies have been noted and explained in the plan modification statement shall also be checked.
ⅤWhen functionality testing is being performed following the completion of the trial operation of waste sewage or sludge treatment facilities, the engineer shall conduct an on-site check to determine wheth enterprise's wastewater, sewage and sludge output volume; operating system; operational status of wastewater, sewage and sludge treatment; sampling locations; sample quantity; and sampling frequency comply regulations and whether relevant records are reliable.
ⅥWhether reporting documents are consistent with on-site checks
ⅦWhether the enterprise's standard operating procedures and emergency response measures with regard sampling and testing of wastewater, sewage and sludge, and the operation, maintenance and service o treatment facilities, are sufficient to ensure compliance with regulations
ⅧOther items the competent authority has designated as requiring checks
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[In order to verify the functioning of an enterprise's wastewater, sewage and sludge treatment facilitie competent authorities at all levels shall, when performing inspection work pursuant to Article 26, Para Subparagraph 1 of this Act, notify the enterprise 14 days prior to the inspection to, on the day of inspection increase its production to conditions of reported or already actually achieved routine maximum water pollutio output volumes and to operate its wastewater, sewage and sludge treatment facilities in order to facilitate inspection.
Enterprises that are unable to coordinate with the inspection conditions in the foregoing paragraph for so reason shall submit to the competent authority an explanation of the specific reason, the date on which it ca achieve the inspection conditions designated in the foregoing paragraph, and relevant verification documents th days prior to the original inspection date. Another inspection date shall be set after the competent auth authorization.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 9-1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[When a competent authority at any level performs verification work pursuant to Article 26, Paragraph 1 of this Act, it may commission relevant agencies (organizations) or corporations, juristic persons or groups to perform work within special zones.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 10</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[When a competent authority at any level dispatches personnel bearing identification documents to ente premises of a military authority in order to perform verification work pursuant to Article 26, Paragraph 2 of thi Act, the personnel shall visit relevant premises or facilities together with local military police or milita environmental protection personnel.
The inspected military authority shall provide necessary assistance when undergoing inspection or appraisal in the foregoing paragraph.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 11</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Those applying for a permit to inject treated sewage into a groundwater body pursuant to Article 32, Paragraph 1 of this Act shall submit the following documents.
ⅠApplication form
ⅡSewage treatment measures
ⅢEnvironmental risk assessment report
ⅣExplanation of groundwater body injection method, frequency, times, injection rate and total volume
ⅤStructural design diagrams and explanation of the functions of facilities used for injection into groundwa bodies
ⅥWater quality and volume monitoring plan for injected water during the period of injection into a ground body
ⅦSurvey and analytical data concerning the underground water-bearing strata that will receive injections. content of this data shall include the following items.
  1.Existing conditions and structure of geological strata at injection location
  2.Groundwater hydrology and water quality data
  3.Status of groundwater use within a radius of 1,000 meters from the injection location or within a designated by the competent authority
  4.Analysis of the impact of injected water on the quality of groundwater
ⅧEmergency response plan
ⅨOther documents designated by the competent authority
Those that have jointly installed wastewater treatment facilities and that apply for a permit to make injecti into a groundwater body shall submit the documents in the foregoing paragraph and jointly submit an application.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 12</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Competent authorities at all levels that require written notification of improvements or corrections w designated time period pursuant to this Act shall produce separate disciplinary citations.
The written notification mentioned in the foregoing paragraph shall record the items stipulated in Art Paragraph 1, of the Administrative Procedure Act, and explicitly state the following items.
ⅠReason for disciplinary action
ⅡItems requiring improvements or corrections
ⅢDeadline for improvements or corrections
ⅣVerification documents required to be submitted upon completion of improvements or corrections
ⅤRegulations for consecutive daily fines or consecutive fines per occurrence following failure to improvements or corrections by the deadline
ⅥOther items designated by the competent authority
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 13</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The competent authority shall perform the work resumption checking and evaluation work in Article 63 of this Act in accordance with the following methods.
ⅠTesting of an enterprise's water pollution control measures or sludge treatment facilities based on the ac routine maximum wastewater and sewage output volume reported by the enterprise when resuming operations
ⅡTesting of the functioning of water pollution control measures or sludge treatment facilities based on the actual routine maximum wastewater and sewage output volume of the enterprise
ⅢAssess the enterprise's regularly reported water quality and water volume data, the water quality and wa volume data resulting from tests performed by the competent authority, and the daily average limits, w average limits and monthly average limits for water quality and water volumes, and compare this data with the current functioning of the enterprise's facilities.
ⅣOther methods recognized by the competent authority
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 14</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA["Within a one-year period" referred to in Article 73, Paragraph 4 of this Act means the 365 days prior to the date of violation.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 15</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[(Deleted)
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 16</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These Rules shall take effect on the date of promulgation.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
