<法規>
<法規性質>命令</法規性質>
<英文法規名稱>Standards for advertising production and broadcast of satellite radio and television</英文法規名稱>
<中文法規名稱>衛星廣播電視廣告製播標準</中文法規名稱>
<法規網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/LawClass/LawContent.aspx?PCODE=P0050024</法規網址>
<最新英文異動日期>19990730</最新英文異動日期>
<廢止註記>
</廢止註記>
<附件>
  <下載網址>http://law.moj.gov.tw/Eng/Law/law_getfile.ashx?FileId=0000001466</下載網址>
</附件>
<沿革內容><![CDATA[1. On July 30, 1999, the Order of Government Information Office (88) Jian Guang No. 12122 published the full text of seven articles. These standards shall come into effect as of the date of promulgation.]]></沿革內容>
<法規內容>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 1</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These standards are promulgated according to the Paragraph 2 of Article 20 of the Satellite Broadcasting Act (hereinafter referred to as the Act)
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 2</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The satellite radio and television advertisements in these standards shall refer to the images, sounds and contents transmitted by the system operators to promote commodities, concepts, services, or images. 
The provisions of the preceding paragraph shall apply to the product or service advertisements that are produced by foreign satellite broadcasting or television enterprises for domestic broadcasting.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 3</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The contents of the advertisements shall not
1. Violate compulsory or prohibitive regulations under the law;
2. Impair the physical or mental health of children or juveniles; or
3. Disrupt public order or adversely affect good social customs.
The demonstration of the foregoing section is set as an Attached Table.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 4</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The satellite radio and television enterprises shall transmit certain advertisements in the time slots and with the encoding method designated by the central regulatory agency.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 5</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[The transmission of advertising should be distinguishable by subtitles, picture cards, narration, music or other appropriate means from the transmission of programs.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 6</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[Stipulations for production and transmission of satellite radio and television advertisement shall be promulgated by the central regulatory agency.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
  <條文>
    <條號>Article 7</條號>
    <條文內容><![CDATA[These standards shall come into effect as of the date of promulgation.
]]></條文內容>
  </條文>
</法規內容>
</法規>
